[
    {
        "front": "現像",
        "pronunciation": "げんぞう",
        "back": "developing (film)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原則",
        "pronunciation": "げんそく",
        "back": "principle, general rule",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見地",
        "pronunciation": "けんち",
        "back": "point of view",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "現地",
        "pronunciation": "げんち",
        "back": "actual place, local",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "限定",
        "pronunciation": "げんてい",
        "back": "limit, restriction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原点",
        "pronunciation": "げんてん",
        "back": "origin (coordinates, starting point)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原典",
        "pronunciation": "げんてん",
        "back": "original, source",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原爆",
        "pronunciation": "げんばく",
        "back": "atomic bomb",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原文",
        "pronunciation": "げんぶん",
        "back": "the text, original",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "厳密",
        "pronunciation": "げんみつ",
        "back": "strict, close",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "賢明",
        "pronunciation": "けんめい",
        "back": "wisdom, intelligence, prudence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "倹約",
        "pronunciation": "けんやく",
        "back": "thrift, economy, frugality",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原油",
        "pronunciation": "げんゆ",
        "back": "crude oil",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "兼用",
        "pronunciation": "けんよう",
        "back": "multi-use, combined use",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "権力",
        "pronunciation": "けんりょく",
        "back": "(political) power, authority, influence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "言論",
        "pronunciation": "げんろん",
        "back": "discussion, speech",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "故～",
        "pronunciation": "こ～",
        "back": "deceased, late",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "語彙",
        "pronunciation": "ごい",
        "back": "vocabulary, glossary",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "恋する",
        "pronunciation": "こいする",
        "back": "to fall in love with, to love",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "甲",
        "pronunciation": "こう",
        "back": "1st in rank; shell",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～光",
        "pronunciation": "～こう",
        "back": "light",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "好意",
        "pronunciation": "こうい",
        "back": "good will, favor, courtesy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "行為",
        "pronunciation": "こうい",
        "back": "act, deed, conduct",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "合意",
        "pronunciation": "ごうい",
        "back": "agreement, consent, mutual understanding",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "工学",
        "pronunciation": "こうがく",
        "back": "engineering",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "抗議",
        "pronunciation": "こうぎ",
        "back": "protest, objection",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "合議",
        "pronunciation": "ごうぎ",
        "back": "consultation, conference",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "皇居",
        "pronunciation": "こうきょ",
        "back": "Imperial Palace",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "好況",
        "pronunciation": "こうきょう",
        "back": "prosperous conditions, healthy economy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉱業",
        "pronunciation": "こうぎょう",
        "back": "mining industry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "興業",
        "pronunciation": "こうぎょう",
        "back": "starting a business; industry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "高原",
        "pronunciation": "こうげん",
        "back": "tableland, plateau",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "交互",
        "pronunciation": "こうご",
        "back": "mutual, reciprocal, alternate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "煌々と",
        "pronunciation": "こうこうと",
        "back": "brightly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "考古学",
        "pronunciation": "こうこがく",
        "back": "archeology",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "工作",
        "pronunciation": "こうさく",
        "back": "handicraft, maneuvering",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "耕作",
        "pronunciation": "こうさく",
        "back": "cultivation, farming",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉱山",
        "pronunciation": "こうざん",
        "back": "mine",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "講習",
        "pronunciation": "こうしゅう",
        "back": "short course, training",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "口述",
        "pronunciation": "こうじゅつ",
        "back": "verbal statement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "控除",
        "pronunciation": "こうじょ",
        "back": "subsidy, deduction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "交渉",
        "pronunciation": "こうしょう",
        "back": "negotiation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "高尚",
        "pronunciation": "こうしょう",
        "back": "high, noble, refined",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "向上",
        "pronunciation": "こうじょう",
        "back": "rise, improvement, progress",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "行進",
        "pronunciation": "こうしん",
        "back": "march, parade",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "香辛料",
        "pronunciation": "こうしんりょう",
        "back": "spices",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "降水",
        "pronunciation": "こうすい",
        "back": "rainfall, precipitation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "洪水",
        "pronunciation": "こうずい",
        "back": "flood",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "合成",
        "pronunciation": "ごうせい",
        "back": "synthetic, mixed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "公然",
        "pronunciation": "こうぜん",
        "back": "openly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "抗争",
        "pronunciation": "こうそう",
        "back": "dispute, resistance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "構想",
        "pronunciation": "こうそう",
        "back": "plan, plot, idea, conception",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "後退",
        "pronunciation": "こうたい",
        "back": "retreat, backspace",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "光沢",
        "pronunciation": "こうたく",
        "back": "luster, glossy finish (of photographs)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "公団",
        "pronunciation": "こうだん",
        "back": "public corporation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "好調",
        "pronunciation": "こうちょう",
        "back": "satisfactory, in good shape",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "口頭",
        "pronunciation": "こうとう",
        "back": "oral",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "講読",
        "pronunciation": "こうどく",
        "back": "reading",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "購読",
        "pronunciation": "こうどく",
        "back": "subscription",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "購入",
        "pronunciation": "こうにゅう",
        "back": "purchase, buy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "公認",
        "pronunciation": "こうにん",
        "back": "official recognition, authorization",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "光熱費",
        "pronunciation": "こうねつひ",
        "back": "cost of fuel and light",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "購買",
        "pronunciation": "こうばい",
        "back": "purchase, buy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "好評",
        "pronunciation": "こうひょう",
        "back": "popularity, favorable reputation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "交付",
        "pronunciation": "こうふ",
        "back": "delivering, furnishing (with copies)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "公募",
        "pronunciation": "こうぼ",
        "back": "public appeal, public contribution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "巧妙",
        "pronunciation": "こうみょう",
        "back": "ingenious, skillful, clever",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "公用",
        "pronunciation": "こうよう",
        "back": "government business, public use, public expense",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "小売",
        "pronunciation": "こうり",
        "back": "retail",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "効率",
        "pronunciation": "こうりつ",
        "back": "efficiency",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "公立",
        "pronunciation": "こうりつ",
        "back": "public institution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "護衛",
        "pronunciation": "ごえい",
        "back": "guard, convoy, escort",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "コーナー",
        "pronunciation": "コーナー",
        "back": "corner",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "小柄",
        "pronunciation": "こがら",
        "back": "small, diminutive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "小切手",
        "pronunciation": "こぎって",
        "back": "cheque, check",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "国産",
        "pronunciation": "こくさん",
        "back": "domestic products",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "国定",
        "pronunciation": "こくてい",
        "back": "state-sponsored, national",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "告白",
        "pronunciation": "こくはく",
        "back": "confession, acknowledgment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "国防",
        "pronunciation": "こくぼう",
        "back": "national defense",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "国有",
        "pronunciation": "こくゆう",
        "back": "national ownership",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "極楽",
        "pronunciation": "ごくらく",
        "back": "paradise",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "国連",
        "pronunciation": "こくれん",
        "back": "U.N., United Nations",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "焦げ茶",
        "pronunciation": "こげちゃ",
        "back": "dark brown",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "語源",
        "pronunciation": "ごげん",
        "back": "word root, word derivation, etymology",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "心地",
        "pronunciation": "ここち",
        "back": "feeling, sensation, mood",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "心得",
        "pronunciation": "こころえ",
        "back": "knowledge, information",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "心掛け",
        "pronunciation": "こころがけ",
        "back": "readiness, intention, aim",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "心掛ける",
        "pronunciation": "こころがける",
        "back": "to bear in mind, to aim to do",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "志",
        "pronunciation": "こころざし",
        "back": "will, intention, motive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "志す",
        "pronunciation": "こころざす",
        "back": "to plan, to intend, to aspire to",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "心強い",
        "pronunciation": "こころづよい",
        "back": "heartening, reassuring",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "心細い",
        "pronunciation": "こころぼそい",
        "back": "helpless, hopeless, discouraging",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "試み",
        "pronunciation": "こころみ",
        "back": "trial, experiment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "試みる",
        "pronunciation": "こころみる",
        "back": "to try, to test",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "快い",
        "pronunciation": "こころよい",
        "back": "pleasant, agreeable",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "誤差",
        "pronunciation": "ごさ",
        "back": "error",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ございます (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "ございます (かん)",
        "back": "to be (polite, to exist)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "孤児",
        "pronunciation": "こじ",
        "back": "orphan",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "こじれる",
        "pronunciation": "こじれる",
        "back": "to get complicated, to grow worse",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "こす (みずを～)",
        "pronunciation": "こす (みずを～)",
        "back": "to strain, to filter",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "梢",
        "pronunciation": "こずえ",
        "back": "treetop",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "個性",
        "pronunciation": "こせい",
        "back": "individuality, personality, idiosyncrasy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "戸籍",
        "pronunciation": "こせき",
        "back": "census, family register",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "古代",
        "pronunciation": "こだい",
        "back": "ancient times",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "こたつ",
        "pronunciation": "こたつ",
        "back": "table with heater, (originally) charcoal brazier in a floor well",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "こだわる",
        "pronunciation": "こだわる",
        "back": "to fuss over, to be particular about",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "誇張",
        "pronunciation": "こちょう",
        "back": "exaggeration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "こつ (をつかむ)",
        "pronunciation": "こつ (をつかむ)",
        "back": "secret, trick, hang",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "滑稽",
        "pronunciation": "こっけい",
        "back": "funny, humorous, comical",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "国交",
        "pronunciation": "こっこう",
        "back": "diplomatic relations",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "骨董品",
        "pronunciation": "こっとうひん",
        "back": "curio",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "固定",
        "pronunciation": "こてい",
        "back": "fixation, fixing (e.g., salary, capital)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "事柄",
        "pronunciation": "ことがら",
        "back": "matter, thing, affair, circumstance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "孤独",
        "pronunciation": "こどく",
        "back": "isolation, loneliness, solitude",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ことごとく",
        "pronunciation": "ことごとく",
        "back": "altogether, entirely",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "言付け",
        "pronunciation": "ことづけ",
        "back": "to leave a message",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "殊に",
        "pronunciation": "ことに",
        "back": "especially, above all",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "粉々",
        "pronunciation": "こなごな",
        "back": "in very small pieces",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "好ましい",
        "pronunciation": "このましい",
        "back": "nice, likable, desirable",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "碁盤",
        "pronunciation": "ごばん",
        "back": "Go board",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "個別",
        "pronunciation": "こべつ",
        "back": "particular case",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ごまかす",
        "pronunciation": "ごまかす",
        "back": "to deceive, to falsify, to misrepresent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "細やか",
        "pronunciation": "こまやか",
        "back": "meager, modest",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "コマーシャル",
        "pronunciation": "コマーシャル",
        "back": "a commercial",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "込める",
        "pronunciation": "こめる",
        "back": "to include, to put into",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "コメント",
        "pronunciation": "コメント",
        "back": "comment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "籠もる",
        "pronunciation": "こもる",
        "back": "to seclude oneself, to be confined in",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "固有",
        "pronunciation": "こゆう",
        "back": "characteristic, tradition, peculiar",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "暦",
        "pronunciation": "こよみ",
        "back": "calendar, almanac",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "凝らす",
        "pronunciation": "こらす",
        "back": "to concentrate, to devote, to peer into",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ごらんなさい (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "ごらんなさい (かん)",
        "back": "look, (please) try to do",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "孤立",
        "pronunciation": "こりつ",
        "back": "isolation, helplessness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "懲りる",
        "pronunciation": "こりる",
        "back": "to learn by experience, to be disgusted with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "凝る",
        "pronunciation": "こる",
        "back": "to stiffen, to harden",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "根気",
        "pronunciation": "こんき",
        "back": "patience; perseverance, energy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "根拠",
        "pronunciation": "こんきょ",
        "back": "basis, foundation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "混血",
        "pronunciation": "こんけつ",
        "back": "mixed race, mixed parentage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "コンタクト (レンズ)",
        "pronunciation": "コンタクト (レンズ)",
        "back": "contact; contact lens",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "昆虫",
        "pronunciation": "こんちゅう",
        "back": "insect, bug",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "根底",
        "pronunciation": "こんてい",
        "back": "root, basis, foundation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "混同",
        "pronunciation": "こんどう",
        "back": "confusion, mixing, merger",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "コントラスト",
        "pronunciation": "コントラスト",
        "back": "contrast",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "コントロール",
        "pronunciation": "コントロール",
        "back": "control",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "コンパス",
        "pronunciation": "コンパス",
        "back": "compass",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "根本",
        "pronunciation": "こんぽん",
        "back": "foundation, root, base",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "財",
        "pronunciation": "ざい",
        "back": "fortune, riches",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "再会",
        "pronunciation": "さいかい",
        "back": "meeting again, reunion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "災害",
        "pronunciation": "さいがい",
        "back": "calamity, disaster, misfortune",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "細菌",
        "pronunciation": "さいきん",
        "back": "bacillus, bacterium, germ",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "細工",
        "pronunciation": "さいく",
        "back": "work, craftsmanship, trick",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "採掘",
        "pronunciation": "さいくつ",
        "back": "mining",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "サイクル",
        "pronunciation": "サイクル",
        "back": "cycle",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "採決",
        "pronunciation": "さいけつ",
        "back": "vote, roll call",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "再建",
        "pronunciation": "さいけん",
        "back": "(temple or shrine) rebuilding",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "再現",
        "pronunciation": "さいげん",
        "back": "reproduction, return, revival",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "財源",
        "pronunciation": "ざいげん",
        "back": "source of funds, resources, finances",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "在庫",
        "pronunciation": "ざいこ",
        "back": "stockpile, stock",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "採算",
        "pronunciation": "さいさん",
        "back": "profit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "サイズ",
        "pronunciation": "サイズ",
        "back": "size",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "再生",
        "pronunciation": "さいせい",
        "back": "playback, regeneration, resuscitation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "財政",
        "pronunciation": "ざいせい",
        "back": "economy, financial affairs",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "最善",
        "pronunciation": "さいぜん",
        "back": "the very best",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "採択",
        "pronunciation": "さいたく",
        "back": "adoption, selection, choice",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "栽培",
        "pronunciation": "さいばい",
        "back": "cultivation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "再発",
        "pronunciation": "さいはつ",
        "back": "return, relapse, reoccurrence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "細胞",
        "pronunciation": "さいぼう",
        "back": "cell",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "採用",
        "pronunciation": "さいよう",
        "back": "use, adopt",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "遮る",
        "pronunciation": "さえぎる",
        "back": "to interrupt, to intercept, to obstruct",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "さえずる",
        "pronunciation": "さえずる",
        "back": "to sing, to chirp, to twitter",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "冴える",
        "pronunciation": "さえる",
        "back": "to be clear, to be bright, to be skillful",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "竿",
        "pronunciation": "さお",
        "back": "rod, pole (e.g., for drying laundry)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "栄える",
        "pronunciation": "さかえる",
        "back": "to flourish, to prosper, to thrive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "差額",
        "pronunciation": "さがく",
        "back": "balance, difference, margin",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "杯",
        "pronunciation": "さかずき",
        "back": "wine cup",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "逆立ち",
        "pronunciation": "さかだち",
        "back": "handstand, headstand",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "さきに (いぜん)",
        "pronunciation": "さきに (いぜん)",
        "back": "before, earlier than, previously",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "詐欺",
        "pronunciation": "さぎ",
        "back": "fraud, swindle",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "削減",
        "pronunciation": "さくげん",
        "back": "cut, reduction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "錯誤",
        "pronunciation": "さくご",
        "back": "mistake",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "作戦",
        "pronunciation": "さくせん",
        "back": "military operations, tactics, strategy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "叫び",
        "pronunciation": "さけび",
        "back": "shout, scream, outcry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "捧げる",
        "pronunciation": "ささげる",
        "back": "to lift up, to give, to offer",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "差し掛かる",
        "pronunciation": "さしかかる",
        "back": "to come near to, to approach",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "指図",
        "pronunciation": "さしず",
        "back": "instruction, mandate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "差し出す",
        "pronunciation": "さしだす",
        "back": "to present, to submit, to hold out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "差し支える",
        "pronunciation": "さしつかえる",
        "back": "to interfere, to hinder",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "授ける",
        "pronunciation": "さずける",
        "back": "to grant, to award, to teach",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "摩する",
        "pronunciation": "さする",
        "back": "to rub, to stroke",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "さぞ (さぞや。さぞかし)",
        "pronunciation": "さぞ (さぞや。さぞかし)",
        "back": "I am sure, certainly, no doubt",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "定まる",
        "pronunciation": "さだまる",
        "back": "to become settled, to be fixed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "定める",
        "pronunciation": "さだめる",
        "back": "to decide, to determine",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "座談会",
        "pronunciation": "ざだんかい",
        "back": "symposium, round-table discussion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雑",
        "pronunciation": "ざつ",
        "back": "rough, crude",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雑貨",
        "pronunciation": "ざっか",
        "back": "miscellaneous goods, general goods",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "殺人",
        "pronunciation": "さつじん",
        "back": "murder",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "察する",
        "pronunciation": "さっする",
        "back": "to guess, to sense, to judge",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雑談",
        "pronunciation": "ざつだん",
        "back": "chatting, idle talk",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "さっと",
        "pronunciation": "さっと",
        "back": "suddenly, smoothly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "さっぱりする",
        "pronunciation": "さっぱりする",
        "back": "to refresh",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "悟る",
        "pronunciation": "さとる",
        "back": "to attain enlightenment, to understand",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "最中",
        "pronunciation": "さなか",
        "back": "in the middle of, midst",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "座標",
        "pronunciation": "ざひょう",
        "back": "coordinates",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "さほど",
        "pronunciation": "さほど",
        "back": "not so, not that much",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "サボる",
        "pronunciation": "サボる",
        "back": "to cut (skip) classes; to loaf on the job; to idle away one's time",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "様",
        "pronunciation": "さま",
        "back": "state; way (a person does something); Mr. or Mrs.",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "寒気",
        "pronunciation": "さむけ",
        "back": "chill, shiver, cold",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "侍",
        "pronunciation": "さむらい",
        "back": "samurai",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "さも",
        "pronunciation": "さも",
        "back": "with gusto, with satisfaction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "作用",
        "pronunciation": "さよう",
        "back": "operation, effect, function",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "さらう (こどもを～)",
        "pronunciation": "さらう (こどもを～)",
        "back": "to kidnap",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "障る",
        "pronunciation": "さわる",
        "back": "to hinder, to interfere with, to affect",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "酸",
        "pronunciation": "さん",
        "back": "acid",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "山岳",
        "pronunciation": "さんがく",
        "back": "mountains",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "参議院",
        "pronunciation": "さんぎいん",
        "back": "House of Councilors",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "産休",
        "pronunciation": "さんきゅう",
        "back": "maternity leave",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "サンキュー",
        "pronunciation": "サンキュー",
        "back": "thank you",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "残金",
        "pronunciation": "ざんきん",
        "back": "remaining money",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "産後",
        "pronunciation": "さんご",
        "back": "postpartum, after childbirth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "残酷",
        "pronunciation": "ざんこく",
        "back": "cruelty, harshness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "産出",
        "pronunciation": "さんしゅつ",
        "back": "yield, produce",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "参照",
        "pronunciation": "さんしょう",
        "back": "reference, consultation, consultation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "参上",
        "pronunciation": "さんじょう",
        "back": "calling on, visiting",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "残高",
        "pronunciation": "ざんだか",
        "back": "(bank) balance, remainder",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "サンタクロース",
        "pronunciation": "サンタクロース",
        "back": "Santa Claus",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "桟橋",
        "pronunciation": "さんばし",
        "back": "wharf, jetty, pier",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "賛美",
        "pronunciation": "さんび",
        "back": "praise, adoration, glorification",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "山腹",
        "pronunciation": "さんぷく",
        "back": "hillside, mountainside",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "産婦人科",
        "pronunciation": "さんふじんか",
        "back": "maternity and gynecology department",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "産物",
        "pronunciation": "さんぶつ",
        "back": "product, result, fruit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "山脈",
        "pronunciation": "さんみゃく",
        "back": "mountain range",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕上がり",
        "pronunciation": "しあがり",
        "back": "finish, end, completion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕上",
        "pronunciation": "しあげ",
        "back": "end, finishing touches",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕上げる",
        "pronunciation": "しあげる",
        "back": "to finish up, to complete",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "飼育",
        "pronunciation": "しいく",
        "back": "breeding, raising, rearing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "強いて",
        "pronunciation": "しいて",
        "back": "to dare, to insist",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "シート",
        "pronunciation": "シート",
        "back": "seat; sheet",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジーパン",
        "pronunciation": "ジーパン",
        "back": "jeans",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕入れる",
        "pronunciation": "しいれる",
        "back": "to lay in stock, to replenish stock, to procure",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "強いる",
        "pronunciation": "しいる",
        "back": "to force, to compel, to coerce",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "潮",
        "pronunciation": "しお",
        "back": "tide",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "歯科",
        "pronunciation": "しか",
        "back": "dentistry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "自我",
        "pronunciation": "じが",
        "back": "self, ego",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "自覚",
        "pronunciation": "じかく",
        "back": "self-conscious",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕掛",
        "pronunciation": "しかけ",
        "back": "device, trick, mechanism",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕掛ける",
        "pronunciation": "しかける",
        "back": "to lay, to set, to wage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "しかしながら",
        "pronunciation": "しかしながら",
        "back": "however, nevertheless",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "色彩",
        "pronunciation": "しきさい",
        "back": "color",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "式場",
        "pronunciation": "しきじょう",
        "back": "ceremonial hall, place of ceremony (e.g., marriage)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "しきたり",
        "pronunciation": "しきたり",
        "back": "custom, conventional practice, tradition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "事業",
        "pronunciation": "じぎょう",
        "back": "project, enterprise, business",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "軽蔑",
        "pronunciation": "けいべつ",
        "back": "scorn, disdain",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "経歴",
        "pronunciation": "けいれき",
        "back": "personal history, career",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "経路",
        "pronunciation": "けいろ",
        "back": "course, route, channel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "けがらわしい",
        "pronunciation": "けがらわしい",
        "back": "filthy, unfair",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "劇団",
        "pronunciation": "げきだん",
        "back": "troupe, theatrical company",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "激励",
        "pronunciation": "げきれい",
        "back": "encouragement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ゲスト",
        "pronunciation": "ゲスト",
        "back": "guest",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "獣",
        "pronunciation": "けだもの",
        "back": "beast, brute",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "決",
        "pronunciation": "けつ",
        "back": "decision, vote",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "決意",
        "pronunciation": "けつい",
        "back": "decision, determination",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "結核",
        "pronunciation": "けっかく",
        "back": "tuberculosis",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "決議",
        "pronunciation": "けつぎ",
        "back": "resolution, vote, decision",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "結合",
        "pronunciation": "けつごう",
        "back": "combination, union",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "決算",
        "pronunciation": "けっさん",
        "back": "balance sheet, settlement of accounts",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "月謝",
        "pronunciation": "げっしゃ",
        "back": "monthly tuition fee",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "決勝",
        "pronunciation": "けっしょう",
        "back": "finals (in sports)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "結晶",
        "pronunciation": "けっしょう",
        "back": "crystal, crystallization",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "結成",
        "pronunciation": "けっせい",
        "back": "formation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "結束",
        "pronunciation": "けっそく",
        "back": "union, unity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "げっそり",
        "pronunciation": "げっそり",
        "back": "being disheartened, losing weight",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "決断",
        "pronunciation": "けつだん",
        "back": "decision, determination",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "月賦",
        "pronunciation": "げっぷ",
        "back": "monthly installment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "欠乏",
        "pronunciation": "けつぼう",
        "back": "shortage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "蹴飛ばす",
        "pronunciation": "けとばす",
        "back": "to kick away, to kick (someone)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "けなす",
        "pronunciation": "けなす",
        "back": "to speak ill of",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "煙たい",
        "pronunciation": "けむたい",
        "back": "smoky, feeling awkward",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "煙る",
        "pronunciation": "けむる",
        "back": "to smoke (e.g., fire)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "獣",
        "pronunciation": "けもの",
        "back": "beast, brute",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "家来",
        "pronunciation": "けらい",
        "back": "retainer, retinue, servant",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "下痢",
        "pronunciation": "げり",
        "back": "diarrhea",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "権威",
        "pronunciation": "けんい",
        "back": "authority, power, influence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "兼業",
        "pronunciation": "けんぎょう",
        "back": "holding two jobs at the same time",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原形",
        "pronunciation": "げんけい",
        "back": "original form, base form",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原型",
        "pronunciation": "げんけい",
        "back": "prototype, model, archetypal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "権限",
        "pronunciation": "けんげん",
        "back": "power, authority, jurisdiction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "現行",
        "pronunciation": "げんこう",
        "back": "present, current, in operation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "健在",
        "pronunciation": "けんざい",
        "back": "in good health, well",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原作",
        "pronunciation": "げんさく",
        "back": "original work",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "検事",
        "pronunciation": "けんじ",
        "back": "public prosecutor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原子",
        "pronunciation": "げんし",
        "back": "atom",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "元首",
        "pronunciation": "げんしゅ",
        "back": "ruler, sovereign",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原書",
        "pronunciation": "げんしょ",
        "back": "original document",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "懸賞",
        "pronunciation": "けんしょう",
        "back": "offering prizes, winning, reward",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "健全",
        "pronunciation": "けんぜん",
        "back": "health, soundness, wholesome",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "元素",
        "pronunciation": "げんそ",
        "back": "element",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "同調",
        "pronunciation": "どうちょう",
        "back": "sympathy, agree with, alignment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "到底",
        "pronunciation": "とうてい",
        "back": "(cannot) possibly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "動的",
        "pronunciation": "どうてき",
        "back": "dynamic, kinetic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "尊い",
        "pronunciation": "とうとい",
        "back": "precious, valuable, noble",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "貴い",
        "pronunciation": "とうとい",
        "back": "precious, valuable, noble",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "同等",
        "pronunciation": "どうとう",
        "back": "equality, equal, same rank",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "堂々",
        "pronunciation": "どうどう",
        "back": "magnificent, grand, impressive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "尊ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "とうとぶ",
        "back": "to value, to prize, to esteem",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "どうにか",
        "pronunciation": "どうにか",
        "back": "in some way or other, one way or another",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "投入",
        "pronunciation": "とうにゅう",
        "back": "throw, investment, making (an electrical circuit)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "導入",
        "pronunciation": "どうにゅう",
        "back": "introduction, bringing in, leading in",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "当人",
        "pronunciation": "とうにん",
        "back": "the one concerned, the said person",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "同封",
        "pronunciation": "どうふう",
        "back": "enclosure (e.g., in a letter)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "逃亡",
        "pronunciation": "とうぼう",
        "back": "escape",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "冬眠",
        "pronunciation": "とうみん",
        "back": "hibernation, winter sleep",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "同盟",
        "pronunciation": "どうめい",
        "back": "alliance, union, league",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "どうやら",
        "pronunciation": "どうやら",
        "back": "it seems like, somehow or other",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "動力",
        "pronunciation": "どうりょく",
        "back": "power, motive power, dynamic force",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "登録",
        "pronunciation": "とうろく",
        "back": "registration, register, record",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "討論",
        "pronunciation": "とうろん",
        "back": "discussion; debate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "遠ざかる",
        "pronunciation": "とおざかる",
        "back": "to go far off",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "遠回り",
        "pronunciation": "とおまわり",
        "back": "detour, roundabout way",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "トーン",
        "pronunciation": "トーン",
        "back": "tone",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "とかく",
        "pronunciation": "とかく",
        "back": "anyhow, anyway, in any case",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "とがめる",
        "pronunciation": "とがめる",
        "back": "to blame, to rebuke",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "時折",
        "pronunciation": "ときおり",
        "back": "sometimes",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "とぎれる",
        "pronunciation": "とぎれる",
        "back": "to pause, to be interrupted",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "研ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "とぐ",
        "back": "to sharpen, to grind, to polish",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "特技",
        "pronunciation": "とくぎ",
        "back": "special talent; skill",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "独裁",
        "pronunciation": "どくさい",
        "back": "dictatorship, despotism",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "特産",
        "pronunciation": "とくさん",
        "back": "specialty, special product",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "独自",
        "pronunciation": "どくじ",
        "back": "original, peculiar, characteristic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "特集",
        "pronunciation": "とくしゅう",
        "back": "feature (e.g., newspaper, special edition, report)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "独占",
        "pronunciation": "どくせん",
        "back": "monopoly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "独創",
        "pronunciation": "どくそう",
        "back": "originality",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "得点",
        "pronunciation": "とくてん",
        "back": "score, points made",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "特派",
        "pronunciation": "とくは",
        "back": "send specially, special envoy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "特有",
        "pronunciation": "とくゆう",
        "back": "characteristic (of, peculiar (to))",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "とげ (をさす)",
        "pronunciation": "とげ (をさす)",
        "back": "thorn",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "遂げる",
        "pronunciation": "とげる",
        "back": "to accomplish, to achieve, to carry out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～どころか",
        "pronunciation": "～どころか",
        "back": "rather, far from",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "年頃",
        "pronunciation": "としごろ",
        "back": "age, marriageable age, adolescence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "戸締り",
        "pronunciation": "とじまり",
        "back": "closing up, locking the doors",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "途上",
        "pronunciation": "とじょう",
        "back": "en/in route, half way",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "土台",
        "pronunciation": "どだい",
        "back": "foundation, base, basis",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "途絶える",
        "pronunciation": "とだえる",
        "back": "to stop, to cease, to come to an end",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "特許",
        "pronunciation": "とっきょ",
        "back": "special permission, patent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "特権",
        "pronunciation": "とっけん",
        "back": "privilege, special right",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "とっさに",
        "pronunciation": "とっさに",
        "back": "at once",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "突如",
        "pronunciation": "とつじょ",
        "back": "suddenly, all of a sudden",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "とって",
        "pronunciation": "とって",
        "back": "handle, grip, knob",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "突破",
        "pronunciation": "とっぱ",
        "back": "breaking through, breakthrough, penetration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "土手",
        "pronunciation": "どて",
        "back": "embankment, bank",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "届",
        "pronunciation": "とどけ",
        "back": "report, notification, registration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "滞る",
        "pronunciation": "とどこおる",
        "back": "to stagnate, to be delayed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "整える",
        "pronunciation": "ととのえる",
        "back": "to put in order, to arrange, to adjust; to get ready, to prepare; to raise money",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "止める",
        "pronunciation": "とどめる",
        "back": "to end, to stop, to cease, to resign",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "唱える",
        "pronunciation": "となえる",
        "back": "to recite, to chant, to call upon",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "殿様",
        "pronunciation": "とのさま",
        "back": "feudal lord",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "土俵",
        "pronunciation": "どひょう",
        "back": "arena",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "扉",
        "pronunciation": "とびら",
        "back": "door, opening",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "溝",
        "pronunciation": "どぶ",
        "back": "ditch, drain, gap",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "徒歩",
        "pronunciation": "とほ",
        "back": "walking, going on foot",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "土木",
        "pronunciation": "どぼく",
        "back": "public works",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "とぼける",
        "pronunciation": "とぼける",
        "back": "to play dumb, to feign ignorance, to play innocent, to have a blank facial expression; to play the fool; to be in one's dotage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "乏しい",
        "pronunciation": "とぼしい",
        "back": "meager, scarce, hard up, poor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "富",
        "pronunciation": "とみ",
        "back": "wealth, fortune",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "富む",
        "pronunciation": "とむ",
        "back": "to be rich, to become rich",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "共稼ぎ",
        "pronunciation": "ともかせぎ",
        "back": "working together, (husband and wife) earning a living together",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "伴う",
        "pronunciation": "ともなう",
        "back": "to accompany, to bring with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "共働き",
        "pronunciation": "ともばたらき",
        "back": "dual income (husband and wife both working)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ドライ",
        "pronunciation": "ドライ",
        "back": "dry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ドライクリーニング",
        "pronunciation": "ドライクリーニング",
        "back": "dry cleaning",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ドライバー",
        "pronunciation": "ドライバー",
        "back": "driver, screwdriver",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ドライブイン",
        "pronunciation": "ドライブイン",
        "back": "drive in",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "トラブル",
        "pronunciation": "トラブル",
        "back": "trouble (sometimes used as a verb)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "トランジスター",
        "pronunciation": "トランジスター",
        "back": "transistor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "とりあえず",
        "pronunciation": "とりあえず",
        "back": "at once, first of all, for the time being",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取扱",
        "pronunciation": "とりあつかい",
        "back": "treatment, handling, management",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り扱う",
        "pronunciation": "とりあつかう",
        "back": "to treat, to handle, to deal in",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "鳥居",
        "pronunciation": "とりい",
        "back": "Shinto shrine archway",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り替え",
        "pronunciation": "とりかえ",
        "back": "swap, exchange",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り組む",
        "pronunciation": "とりくむ",
        "back": "to tackle, to engage in a bout, to come to grips with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取締り",
        "pronunciation": "とりしまり",
        "back": "control, crackdown, supervision",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り締まる",
        "pronunciation": "とりしまる",
        "back": "to crack down, to control, to supervise",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り調べる",
        "pronunciation": "とりしらべる",
        "back": "to investigate, to examine",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り立てる",
        "pronunciation": "とりたてる",
        "back": "to collect, to extort",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り次ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "とりつぐ",
        "back": "to act as an agent for, to announce (someone), to convey (a message)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り付ける",
        "pronunciation": "とりつける",
        "back": "to furnish, to install; to get someone's agreement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り除く",
        "pronunciation": "とりのぞく",
        "back": "to remove, to take away, to set apart",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取引",
        "pronunciation": "とりひき",
        "back": "transactions, dealings, business",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り巻く",
        "pronunciation": "とりまく",
        "back": "to surround, to circle, to enclose",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り混ぜる",
        "pronunciation": "とりまぜる",
        "back": "to mix, to put together",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り戻す",
        "pronunciation": "とりもどす",
        "back": "to take back, to regain",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り寄せる",
        "pronunciation": "とりよせる",
        "back": "to order, to send away for",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ドリル",
        "pronunciation": "ドリル",
        "back": "drill",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "副",
        "pronunciation": "とりわけ",
        "back": "especially, above all",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "とろける",
        "pronunciation": "とろける",
        "back": "melt; to be enchanted with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "鈍感",
        "pronunciation": "どんかん",
        "back": "thickheadedness, stolidity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "とんだ",
        "pronunciation": "とんだ",
        "back": "terrible, awful, serious, absolutely not",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "度忘れ",
        "pronunciation": "どわすれ",
        "back": "lapse of memory, forget for a moment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "問屋",
        "pronunciation": "とんや",
        "back": "wholesale store",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "内閣",
        "pronunciation": "ないかく",
        "back": "cabinet, (government)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "乃至",
        "pronunciation": "ないし",
        "back": "from...to, between...and, or",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "内緒",
        "pronunciation": "ないしょ",
        "back": "secrecy, privacy, secret",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "内心",
        "pronunciation": "ないしん",
        "back": "innermost thoughts, real intention, inmost heart",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "内蔵",
        "pronunciation": "ないぞう",
        "back": "internal organ; built-in",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ナイター",
        "pronunciation": "ナイター",
        "back": "game under lights (e.g., baseball), night game",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "内部",
        "pronunciation": "ないぶ",
        "back": "interior, inside, internal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "内乱",
        "pronunciation": "ないらん",
        "back": "civil war, domestic conflict",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "内陸",
        "pronunciation": "ないりく",
        "back": "inland",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "苗",
        "pronunciation": "なえ",
        "back": "rice seedling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "なおさら",
        "pronunciation": "なおさら",
        "back": "all the more, still less",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "流し",
        "pronunciation": "ながし",
        "back": "sink",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "長々",
        "pronunciation": "ながなが",
        "back": "long, drawn-out, very long",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "中程",
        "pronunciation": "なかほど",
        "back": "middle, midway",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "渚",
        "pronunciation": "なぎさ",
        "back": "water's edge, beach, shore",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "嘆く",
        "pronunciation": "なげく",
        "back": "to sigh, to lament, to grieve",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "投げ出す",
        "pronunciation": "なげだす",
        "back": "to abandon, to throw out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仲人",
        "pronunciation": "なこうど",
        "back": "go-between, matchmaker",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "和やか",
        "pronunciation": "なごやか",
        "back": "mild, calm, harmonious",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "名残",
        "pronunciation": "なごり",
        "back": "remains, traces, memory",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "情け",
        "pronunciation": "なさけ",
        "back": "sympathy, compassion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "情無い",
        "pronunciation": "なさけない",
        "back": "miserable, pitiable, shameful",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "情深い",
        "pronunciation": "なさけぶかい",
        "back": "tender-hearted, compassionate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "詰る",
        "pronunciation": "なじる",
        "back": "to rebuke, to scold, to tell off",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "名高い",
        "pronunciation": "なだかい",
        "back": "famous, celebrated, well-known",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雪崩",
        "pronunciation": "なだれ",
        "back": "avalanche",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "懐く",
        "pronunciation": "なつく",
        "back": "to become emotionally attached",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "名付ける",
        "pronunciation": "なづける",
        "back": "to name",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "何気ない",
        "pronunciation": "なにげない",
        "back": "casual, unconcerned",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "なにとぞ",
        "pronunciation": "なにとぞ",
        "back": "please, kindly, by all means",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "なにより",
        "pronunciation": "なにより",
        "back": "most, best",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ナプキン",
        "pronunciation": "ナプキン",
        "back": "napkin",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "名札",
        "pronunciation": "なふだ",
        "back": "name plate, name tag",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "生臭い",
        "pronunciation": "なまぐさい",
        "back": "smelling of fish or blood, fish or meat",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "生温い",
        "pronunciation": "なまぬるい",
        "back": "lukewarm, halfhearted",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "生身",
        "pronunciation": "なまみ",
        "back": "living flesh, flesh and blood, the quick",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉛",
        "pronunciation": "なまり",
        "back": "lead (the metal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "滑らか",
        "pronunciation": "なめらか",
        "back": "smoothness, glassiness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "嘗める",
        "pronunciation": "なめる",
        "back": "to lick; to experience; to make fun of",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "悩ましい",
        "pronunciation": "なやましい",
        "back": "seductive, melancholy, languid",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "悩ます",
        "pronunciation": "なやます",
        "back": "to bother, to harass, to molest",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "悩み",
        "pronunciation": "なやみ",
        "back": "trouble(s), worry, distress",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "並びに",
        "pronunciation": "ならびに",
        "back": "and",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "成り立つ",
        "pronunciation": "なりたつ",
        "back": "to consist of; to be practical (logical, feasible, viable), to be concluded, to hold true",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "なるたけ",
        "pronunciation": "なるたけ",
        "back": "as much as possible, if possible",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "慣れ",
        "pronunciation": "なれ",
        "back": "practice, experience",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "馴々しい",
        "pronunciation": "なれなれしい",
        "back": "familiar, make free with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～なんか",
        "pronunciation": "～なんか",
        "back": "in the least ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ナンセンス",
        "pronunciation": "ナンセンス",
        "back": "nonsense",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "何だか",
        "pronunciation": "なんだか",
        "back": "a little, somewhat, somehow",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "なんだかんだ",
        "pronunciation": "なんだかんだ",
        "back": "something or other",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "なんなり",
        "pronunciation": "なんなり",
        "back": "anything, whatever",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "荷",
        "pronunciation": "に",
        "back": "load, baggage, cargo",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "似通う",
        "pronunciation": "にかよう",
        "back": "to resemble closely",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "にきび",
        "pronunciation": "にきび",
        "back": "pimple, acne",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "賑わう",
        "pronunciation": "にぎわう",
        "back": "to prosper, to flourish, to be crowded with people",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "憎しみ",
        "pronunciation": "にくしみ",
        "back": "hatred",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "肉親",
        "pronunciation": "にくしん",
        "back": "blood relationship, blood relative",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "肉体",
        "pronunciation": "にくたい",
        "back": "the body, the flesh",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "逃げ出す",
        "pronunciation": "にげだす",
        "back": "to run away, to escape from",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "西日",
        "pronunciation": "にしび",
        "back": "westering sun",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "滲む",
        "pronunciation": "にじむ",
        "back": "to run, to blur, to spread",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "にせ物",
        "pronunciation": "にせもの",
        "back": "imitation, counterfeit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "日夜",
        "pronunciation": "にちや",
        "back": "day and night, always",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "荷造り",
        "pronunciation": "にづくり",
        "back": "packing, baling, crating",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "担う",
        "pronunciation": "になう",
        "back": "to carry on shoulder, to bear (burden), to shoulder (gun)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "鈍る",
        "pronunciation": "にぶる",
        "back": "to become less capable, to grow dull, to become blunt, to weaken",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "にも関わらず",
        "pronunciation": "にもかかわらず",
        "back": "in spite of, nevertheless",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ニュアンス",
        "pronunciation": "ニュアンス",
        "back": "nuance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ニュー",
        "pronunciation": "ニュー",
        "back": "new",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "入手",
        "pronunciation": "にゅうしゅ",
        "back": "obtaining, coming to hand",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "入賞",
        "pronunciation": "にゅうしょう",
        "back": "winning a prize or place (in a contest",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "入浴",
        "pronunciation": "にゅうよく",
        "back": "bathe, bathing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "尿",
        "pronunciation": "にょう",
        "back": "urine",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "認識",
        "pronunciation": "にんしき",
        "back": "recognition, cognizance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "妊娠",
        "pronunciation": "にんしん",
        "back": "conception, pregnancy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "任務",
        "pronunciation": "にんむ",
        "back": "duty, mission, task",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "任命",
        "pronunciation": "にんめい",
        "back": "appointment, nomination, ordination",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "抜かす",
        "pronunciation": "ぬかす",
        "back": "to omit, to leave out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "抜け出す",
        "pronunciation": "ぬけだす",
        "back": "to slip out, to sneak away, to excel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主",
        "pronunciation": "ぬし",
        "back": "owner, master, god",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "沼",
        "pronunciation": "ぬま",
        "back": "swamp, bog, pond",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "音色",
        "pronunciation": "ねいろ",
        "back": "tone color, timbre",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "値打ち",
        "pronunciation": "ねうち",
        "back": "value, worth, price",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ネガ",
        "pronunciation": "ネガ",
        "back": "(photographic) negative",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "寝かせる",
        "pronunciation": "ねかせる",
        "back": "to put to bed, to lay down, to ferment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ねじまわし",
        "pronunciation": "ねじまわし",
        "back": "screwdriver",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "捩れる",
        "pronunciation": "ねじれる",
        "back": "twist, strain",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "妬む",
        "pronunciation": "ねたむ",
        "back": "to be jealous, to be envious",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ねだる",
        "pronunciation": "ねだる",
        "back": "to nag, to demand",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "熱意",
        "pronunciation": "ねつい",
        "back": "zeal, enthusiasm",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "熱湯",
        "pronunciation": "ねっとう",
        "back": "boiling water",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "熱量",
        "pronunciation": "ねつりょう",
        "back": "calorific value",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "粘り",
        "pronunciation": "ねばり",
        "back": "stickiness, viscosity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "粘る",
        "pronunciation": "ねばる",
        "back": "to be sticky, to be adhesive, to persist, to stick to",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "値引き",
        "pronunciation": "ねびき",
        "back": "price reduction, discount",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "根回し",
        "pronunciation": "ねまわし",
        "back": "making necessary arrangements",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "眠たい",
        "pronunciation": "ねむたい",
        "back": "sleepy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "練る",
        "pronunciation": "ねる",
        "back": "to knead, to work over, to polish up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "念",
        "pronunciation": "ねん",
        "back": "sense, feeling, desire",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "年賀",
        "pronunciation": "ねんが",
        "back": "New Year's greetings, New Year's card",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "念願",
        "pronunciation": "ねんがん",
        "back": "one's heart's desire, earnest petition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "年号",
        "pronunciation": "ねんごう",
        "back": "name of an era, year number",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "燃焼",
        "pronunciation": "ねんしょう",
        "back": "burning, combustion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "年長",
        "pronunciation": "ねんちょう",
        "back": "seniority",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "燃料",
        "pronunciation": "ねんりょう",
        "back": "fuel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "年輪",
        "pronunciation": "ねんりん",
        "back": "annual tree ring",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ノイローゼ",
        "pronunciation": "ノイローゼ",
        "back": "neurosis (GER: Neurose)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "農耕",
        "pronunciation": "のうこう",
        "back": "farming, agriculture",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "農場",
        "pronunciation": "のうじょう",
        "back": "farm",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "農地",
        "pronunciation": "のうち",
        "back": "agricultural land",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "納入",
        "pronunciation": "のうにゅう",
        "back": "payment, supply",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "逃す",
        "pronunciation": "のがす",
        "back": "to let loose, to set free, to let escape",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "逃れる",
        "pronunciation": "のがれる",
        "back": "to escape",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "軒並",
        "pronunciation": "のきなみ",
        "back": "row of houses; uniformly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "望ましい",
        "pronunciation": "のぞましい",
        "back": "desirable, hoped for",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "乗っ取る",
        "pronunciation": "のっとる",
        "back": "to capture, to occupy, to take over",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "のどか",
        "pronunciation": "のどか",
        "back": "tranquil, calm, quiet",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "罵る",
        "pronunciation": "ののしる",
        "back": "to speak ill of, to abuse",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "延べ",
        "pronunciation": "のべ",
        "back": "futures, credit (buying), stretching, total",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "飲み込む",
        "pronunciation": "のみこむ",
        "back": "to gulp down, to swallow deeply, to understand",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "乗り込む",
        "pronunciation": "のりこむ",
        "back": "to board, to get into (a car); to march into, to enter",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "刃",
        "pronunciation": "は",
        "back": "blade, sword",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～派",
        "pronunciation": "～は",
        "back": "group, party, section (mil)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "バー",
        "pronunciation": "バー",
        "back": "bar",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "把握",
        "pronunciation": "はあく",
        "back": "grasp, catch, understanding",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "パート",
        "pronunciation": "パート",
        "back": "part-time job",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "廃棄",
        "pronunciation": "はいき",
        "back": "disposal, abandon, discarding",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "配給",
        "pronunciation": "はいきゅう",
        "back": "distribution (e.g., films, rice",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ばい菌",
        "pronunciation": "ばいきん",
        "back": "bacteria, germ(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "配偶者",
        "pronunciation": "はいぐうしゃ",
        "back": "spouse",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "拝啓",
        "pronunciation": "はいけい",
        "back": "-- a formal greeting used at the beginning of a letter --",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "背景",
        "pronunciation": "はいけい",
        "back": "background, scenery, setting",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "背後",
        "pronunciation": "はいご",
        "back": "back, rear",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "廃止",
        "pronunciation": "はいし",
        "back": "abolition, repeal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "拝借",
        "pronunciation": "はいしゃく",
        "back": "(humble) (polite) borrowing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "排除",
        "pronunciation": "はいじょ",
        "back": "exclusion, removal, rejection",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "賠償",
        "pronunciation": "ばいしょう",
        "back": "reparations, indemnity, compensation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "排水",
        "pronunciation": "はいすい",
        "back": "drainage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "敗戦",
        "pronunciation": "はいせん",
        "back": "defeat, losing a war",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "配置",
        "pronunciation": "はいち",
        "back": "arrangement (of resources), disposition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "配布",
        "pronunciation": "はいふ",
        "back": "distribution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "配分",
        "pronunciation": "はいぶん",
        "back": "distribution, allotment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "敗北",
        "pronunciation": "はいぼく",
        "back": "defeat (as a verb it means 'to be defeated')",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "倍率",
        "pronunciation": "ばいりつ",
        "back": "diameter, magnification",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "配慮",
        "pronunciation": "はいりょ",
        "back": "consideration, concern, forethought",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "配列",
        "pronunciation": "はいれつ",
        "back": "arrangement, array (programming)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "破壊",
        "pronunciation": "はかい",
        "back": "destruction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "いたわる",
        "pronunciation": "いたわる",
        "back": "to sympathize with, to console, to care for",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一概に",
        "pronunciation": "いちがいに",
        "back": "unconditionally, necessarily",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "著しい",
        "pronunciation": "いちじるしい",
        "back": "remarkable, considerable",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一同",
        "pronunciation": "いちどう",
        "back": "all present, all concerned, all of us",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一部分",
        "pronunciation": "いちぶぶん",
        "back": "a part, a portion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一別",
        "pronunciation": "いちべつ",
        "back": "parting",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一面",
        "pronunciation": "いちめん",
        "back": "one side, the other hand",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一目",
        "pronunciation": "いちもく",
        "back": "a glance, a look, a glimpse",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一様",
        "pronunciation": "いちよう",
        "back": "uniform, similar, equal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一律",
        "pronunciation": "いちりつ",
        "back": "even, uniform, equal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一連",
        "pronunciation": "いちれん",
        "back": "a series, a chain, a ream (of paper)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一括",
        "pronunciation": "いっかつ",
        "back": "all together, batch",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一気",
        "pronunciation": "いっき",
        "back": "at one push, in one gulp",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一挙に",
        "pronunciation": "いっきょに",
        "back": "at a stroke, with a single swoop",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一見",
        "pronunciation": "いっけん",
        "back": "a look, a glimpse, glance; first meeting",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一切",
        "pronunciation": "いっさい",
        "back": "without exception, the whole",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一心",
        "pronunciation": "いっしん",
        "back": "one mind, with rapt attention",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "いっそ",
        "pronunciation": "いっそ",
        "back": "rather, sooner, might as well",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一変",
        "pronunciation": "いっぺん",
        "back": "complete change",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "意図",
        "pronunciation": "いと",
        "back": "intention, aim, design",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "営む",
        "pronunciation": "いとなむ",
        "back": "to carry on (e.g., in ceremony), to run a business",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "挑む",
        "pronunciation": "いどむ",
        "back": "to challenge",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "稲光",
        "pronunciation": "いなびかり",
        "back": "(flash of) lightning",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "祈り",
        "pronunciation": "いのり",
        "back": "prayer, supplication",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "いびき",
        "pronunciation": "いびき",
        "back": "snoring",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "今更",
        "pronunciation": "いまさら",
        "back": "now, again",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "未だ",
        "pronunciation": "いまだ",
        "back": "yet, still",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "移民",
        "pronunciation": "いみん",
        "back": "emigrant, immigrant",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "嫌々",
        "pronunciation": "いやいや",
        "back": "reluctantly, by no means, unwillingly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "卑しい",
        "pronunciation": "いやしい",
        "back": "greedy, vulgar, shabby",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "いやに",
        "pronunciation": "いやに",
        "back": "awfully, terribly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "いやらしい",
        "pronunciation": "いやらしい",
        "back": "unpleasant, disgusting, indecent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "意欲",
        "pronunciation": "いよく",
        "back": "will, desire, ambition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "威力",
        "pronunciation": "いりょく",
        "back": "power, might, authority",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "衣類",
        "pronunciation": "いるい",
        "back": "clothes, clothing, garments",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "異論",
        "pronunciation": "いろん",
        "back": "different opinion, objection",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "印鑑",
        "pronunciation": "いんかん",
        "back": "stamp, seal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "陰気",
        "pronunciation": "いんき",
        "back": "gloom, melancholy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "隠居",
        "pronunciation": "いんきょ",
        "back": "retirement; retired person",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "インターチェンジ",
        "pronunciation": "インターチェンジ",
        "back": "interchange",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "インターナショナル",
        "pronunciation": "インターナショナル",
        "back": "international",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "インターフォン",
        "pronunciation": "インターフォン",
        "back": "entry phone, intercom",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "インテリ",
        "pronunciation": "インテリ",
        "back": "(abbr.) egghead, intelligentsia",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "インフォメーション",
        "pronunciation": "インフォメーション",
        "back": "information",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "インフレ",
        "pronunciation": "インフレ",
        "back": "(abbr.) inflation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "受かる",
        "pronunciation": "うかる",
        "back": "to pass (examination)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "受け入れ",
        "pronunciation": "うけいれ",
        "back": "receiving, acceptance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "受け入れる",
        "pronunciation": "うけいれる",
        "back": "to accept, to receive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "受け継ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "うけつぐ",
        "back": "to inherit, to succeed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "受け付ける",
        "pronunciation": "うけつける",
        "back": "to be accepted, to receive (an application)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "受け止める",
        "pronunciation": "うけとめる",
        "back": "to catch, to react to, to take",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "受身",
        "pronunciation": "うけみ",
        "back": "passive, passive voice",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "受持ち",
        "pronunciation": "うけもち",
        "back": "charge (of something), matter in one's charge",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "動き",
        "pronunciation": "うごき",
        "back": "movement, activity, trend",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "埋める",
        "pronunciation": "うずめる",
        "back": "to bury, to fill",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "嘘つき",
        "pronunciation": "うそつき",
        "back": "liar",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "うたた寝",
        "pronunciation": "うたたね",
        "back": "dozing, napping",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "打ち明ける",
        "pronunciation": "うちあける",
        "back": "to confess, to be open",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "打ち切る",
        "pronunciation": "うちきる",
        "back": "to stop, to abort, to discontinue, to close",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "打ち消し",
        "pronunciation": "うちけし",
        "back": "(gram) negation, denial, negative",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "打ち込む",
        "pronunciation": "うちこむ",
        "back": "to devote oneself to, to shoot into",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "団扇",
        "pronunciation": "うちわ",
        "back": "fan",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "内訳",
        "pronunciation": "うちわけ",
        "back": "the items, breakdown, classification",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "写し",
        "pronunciation": "うつし",
        "back": "copy, duplicate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "訴え",
        "pronunciation": "うったえ",
        "back": "lawsuit, complaint",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "うっとうしい",
        "pronunciation": "うっとうしい",
        "back": "weary, annoying",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "うつむく",
        "pronunciation": "うつむく",
        "back": "to look downward, to stoop",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "空ろ",
        "pronunciation": "うつろ",
        "back": "blank, hollow, empty",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "器",
        "pronunciation": "うつわ",
        "back": "bowl, vessel, container",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "腕前",
        "pronunciation": "うでまえ",
        "back": "ability, skill, facility",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雨天",
        "pronunciation": "うてん",
        "back": "rainy weather",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "促す",
        "pronunciation": "うながす",
        "back": "to urge, to suggest, to demand",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "うぬぼれ",
        "pronunciation": "うぬぼれ",
        "back": "pretension, conceit, hubris",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "生まれつき",
        "pronunciation": "うまれつき",
        "back": "by nature, by birth, native",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "埋め込む",
        "pronunciation": "うめこむ",
        "back": "to embed, implant",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "梅干し",
        "pronunciation": "うめぼし",
        "back": "dried plum",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "裏返し",
        "pronunciation": "うらがえし",
        "back": "inside out, reverse",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "売り出し",
        "pronunciation": "うりだし",
        "back": "(bargain) sale",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "売り出す",
        "pronunciation": "うりだす",
        "back": "to put on sale, to market",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "潤う",
        "pronunciation": "うるおう",
        "back": "to be moist; to profit by",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "浮気",
        "pronunciation": "うわき",
        "back": "affair, to cheat",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "上回る",
        "pronunciation": "うわまわる",
        "back": "to exceed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "植わる",
        "pronunciation": "うわる",
        "back": "to be planted",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "運営",
        "pronunciation": "うんえい",
        "back": "management, administration, operation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "うんざり",
        "pronunciation": "うんざり",
        "back": "tedious, boring, being fed up with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "運送",
        "pronunciation": "うんそう",
        "back": "shipping, freight",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "運賃",
        "pronunciation": "うんちん",
        "back": "freight rates, shipping expenses, (passenger) fare",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "云々",
        "pronunciation": "うんぬん",
        "back": "and so on, and so forth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "運搬",
        "pronunciation": "うんぱん",
        "back": "transport, carriage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "運命",
        "pronunciation": "うんめい",
        "back": "fate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "運輸",
        "pronunciation": "うんゆ",
        "back": "transportation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "運用",
        "pronunciation": "うんよう",
        "back": "making use of, application, practical use",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "エアメール",
        "pronunciation": "エアメール",
        "back": "air mail",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～営",
        "pronunciation": "～えい",
        "back": "~ run",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "英字",
        "pronunciation": "えいじ",
        "back": "English letter (character)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "映写",
        "pronunciation": "えいしゃ",
        "back": "projection",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "映像",
        "pronunciation": "えいぞう",
        "back": "reflection, image",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "英雄",
        "pronunciation": "えいゆう",
        "back": "hero, great man",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "液",
        "pronunciation": "えき",
        "back": "liquid, fluid",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "閲覧",
        "pronunciation": "えつらん",
        "back": "inspection, reference, browse",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "獲物",
        "pronunciation": "えもの",
        "back": "game, spoils, trophy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "襟",
        "pronunciation": "えり",
        "back": "neck, collar",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "エレガント",
        "pronunciation": "エレガント",
        "back": "elegant",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "円滑",
        "pronunciation": "えんかつ",
        "back": "harmony, smoothness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "縁側",
        "pronunciation": "えんがわ",
        "back": "veranda, porch, balcony, open corridor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "沿岸",
        "pronunciation": "えんがん",
        "back": "coast, shore",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "婉曲",
        "pronunciation": "えんきょく",
        "back": "euphemistic, indirect, insinuating",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "演出",
        "pronunciation": "えんしゅつ",
        "back": "production (erg. play, direction)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "エンジニア",
        "pronunciation": "エンジニア",
        "back": "engineer",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "演じる",
        "pronunciation": "えんじる",
        "back": "to perform, to play (a part), to act",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "演ずる",
        "pronunciation": "えんずる",
        "back": "to perform, to play (a part), to act",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "沿線",
        "pronunciation": "えんせん",
        "back": "along railway line",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "縁談",
        "pronunciation": "えんだん",
        "back": "marriage proposal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "遠方",
        "pronunciation": "えんぽう",
        "back": "long way, distant place",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "円満",
        "pronunciation": "えんまん",
        "back": "harmony, peace, smoothness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "追い込む",
        "pronunciation": "おいこむ",
        "back": "to herd, to corner, to drive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "追い出す",
        "pronunciation": "おいだす",
        "back": "to expel, to drive out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "於いて",
        "pronunciation": "おいて",
        "back": "at, in, on",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "老いる",
        "pronunciation": "おいる",
        "back": "to age, to grow old",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "応急",
        "pronunciation": "おうきゅう",
        "back": "emergency",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "黄金",
        "pronunciation": "おうごん",
        "back": "gold",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "往診",
        "pronunciation": "おうしん",
        "back": "doctor's visit, house call",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "応募",
        "pronunciation": "おうぼ",
        "back": "subscription, application",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おおい (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "おおい (かん)",
        "back": "hey",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大方",
        "pronunciation": "おおかた",
        "back": "almost all, majority",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大柄",
        "pronunciation": "おおがら",
        "back": "large build, large pattern",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おおげさ",
        "pronunciation": "おおげさ",
        "back": "grandiose, exaggerated",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大筋",
        "pronunciation": "おおすじ",
        "back": "outline, summary",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大空",
        "pronunciation": "おおぞら",
        "back": "heaven, the sky",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "オートマチック",
        "pronunciation": "オートマチック",
        "back": "automatic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大幅",
        "pronunciation": "おおはば",
        "back": "full width, large scale, drastic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おおまかな",
        "pronunciation": "おおまかな",
        "back": "rough, approximate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大水",
        "pronunciation": "おおみず",
        "back": "flood",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "公",
        "pronunciation": "おおやけ",
        "back": "public",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "犯す",
        "pronunciation": "おかす",
        "back": "to perpetrate, to violate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "侵す",
        "pronunciation": "おかす",
        "back": "to invade, to raid, to trespass",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "臆病",
        "pronunciation": "おくびょう",
        "back": "cowardice, timidity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "遅らす",
        "pronunciation": "おくらす",
        "back": "to retard, to delay",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "厳か",
        "pronunciation": "おごそか",
        "back": "majestic, dignified",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "行い",
        "pronunciation": "おこない",
        "back": "conduct, behavior, action",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おごる (ゆうしょくを～)",
        "pronunciation": "おごる (ゆうしょくを～)",
        "back": "to give (someone) a treat",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "収まる",
        "pronunciation": "おさまる",
        "back": "to settle into; to be obtained",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "納まる",
        "pronunciation": "おさまる",
        "back": "to settle into; to be obtained",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "治まる",
        "pronunciation": "おさまる",
        "back": "to be at peace, to calm down",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "お産",
        "pronunciation": "おさん",
        "back": "(giving) birth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "押し切る",
        "pronunciation": "おしきる",
        "back": "to have one's own way",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "押し込む",
        "pronunciation": "おしこむ",
        "back": "to push into, to crowd into",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "惜しむ",
        "pronunciation": "おしむ",
        "back": "to be frugal, to value, to regret",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "押し寄せる",
        "pronunciation": "おしよせる",
        "back": "to push aside, to advance on",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雄",
        "pronunciation": "おす",
        "back": "male (animal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "御世辞",
        "pronunciation": "おせじ",
        "back": "flattery, compliment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "襲う",
        "pronunciation": "おそう",
        "back": "to attack",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "遅くとも",
        "pronunciation": "おそくとも",
        "back": "at the latest",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "恐れ",
        "pronunciation": "おそれ",
        "back": "fear, horror",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "恐れ入る",
        "pronunciation": "おそれいる",
        "back": "to be filled with awe, to feel small",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おだてる",
        "pronunciation": "おだてる",
        "back": "to flatter",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "落ち込む",
        "pronunciation": "おちこむ",
        "back": "to get depressed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "落ち着き",
        "pronunciation": "おちつき",
        "back": "calm, composure",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "落葉",
        "pronunciation": "おちば",
        "back": "fallen leaves",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "乙",
        "pronunciation": "おつ",
        "back": "2nd in rank",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "お使い",
        "pronunciation": "おつかい",
        "back": "errand",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おっかない",
        "pronunciation": "おっかない",
        "back": "frightening, scary",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "お手上げ",
        "pronunciation": "おてあげ",
        "back": "given in, given up hope",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おどおど",
        "pronunciation": "おどおど",
        "back": "coweringly, hesitantly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "脅す",
        "pronunciation": "おどす",
        "back": "to threaten, to menace",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "訪れる",
        "pronunciation": "おとずれる",
        "back": "to visit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "お供",
        "pronunciation": "おとも",
        "back": "attendant, companion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "衰える",
        "pronunciation": "おとろえる",
        "back": "to become weak, to decline",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "同い年",
        "pronunciation": "おないどし",
        "back": "of the same age",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "自ずから",
        "pronunciation": "おのずから",
        "back": "naturally, as a matter of course",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "怯える",
        "pronunciation": "おびえる",
        "back": "to become frightened",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おびただしい",
        "pronunciation": "おびただしい",
        "back": "abundantly, innumerably",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "脅かす",
        "pronunciation": "おびやかす",
        "back": "to threaten, to coerce",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "帯びる",
        "pronunciation": "おびる",
        "back": "to bear, to carry, to be entrusted",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "お袋",
        "pronunciation": "おふくろ",
        "back": "mother",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "覚え",
        "pronunciation": "おぼえ",
        "back": "memory, sense, experience",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おまけ",
        "pronunciation": "おまけ",
        "back": "a discount; something additional",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "お宮",
        "pronunciation": "おみや",
        "back": "Shinto shrine",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おむつ",
        "pronunciation": "おむつ",
        "back": "diaper, nappy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "思い付き",
        "pronunciation": "おもいつき",
        "back": "plan, idea, suggestion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "趣",
        "pronunciation": "おもむき",
        "back": "flavor, appearance, quaint",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "赴く",
        "pronunciation": "おもむく",
        "back": "to go, to proceed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "重んじる",
        "pronunciation": "おもんじる",
        "back": "to respect, to honor, to esteem, to prize",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "重んずる",
        "pronunciation": "おもんずる",
        "back": "to honor, to respect, to value",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "親父",
        "pronunciation": "おやじ",
        "back": "one's father, old man, one's boss",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "及び",
        "pronunciation": "および",
        "back": "and, as well as",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "及ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "およぶ",
        "back": "to reach, to extend",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "折",
        "pronunciation": "おり",
        "back": "chance, occasion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "檻",
        "pronunciation": "おり",
        "back": "cage, pen, jail cell",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "オリエンテーション",
        "pronunciation": "オリエンテーション",
        "back": "orientation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "折り返す",
        "pronunciation": "おりかえす",
        "back": "to turn up, to fold back",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "織物",
        "pronunciation": "おりもの",
        "back": "textile, fabric",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "俺",
        "pronunciation": "おれ",
        "back": "I (ego) (boastful first-person pronoun)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "愚か",
        "pronunciation": "おろか",
        "back": "foolish, stupid",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おろそか",
        "pronunciation": "おろそか",
        "back": "neglect, negligence, carelessness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "おんぶ",
        "pronunciation": "おんぶ",
        "back": "carrying on one's back (erg. Baby)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "オンライン",
        "pronunciation": "オンライン",
        "back": "on-line",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "温和",
        "pronunciation": "おんわ",
        "back": "gentle, mild, moderate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "我",
        "pronunciation": "が～",
        "back": "ego",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "カーペット",
        "pronunciation": "カーペット",
        "back": "carpet",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～界",
        "pronunciation": "～かい",
        "back": "world, circle, kingdom",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～街",
        "pronunciation": "～がい",
        "back": "town",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "改悪",
        "pronunciation": "かいあく",
        "back": "deterioration, changing for the worse",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "海運",
        "pronunciation": "かいうん",
        "back": "marine transportation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "外貨",
        "pronunciation": "がいか",
        "back": "foreign money",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "改革",
        "pronunciation": "かいかく",
        "back": "reform, reformation, innovation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "貝殻",
        "pronunciation": "かいがら",
        "back": "shell",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "外観",
        "pronunciation": "がいかん",
        "back": "appearance, exterior, facade",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "階級",
        "pronunciation": "かいきゅう",
        "back": "class, rank, grade",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "海峡",
        "pronunciation": "かいきょう",
        "back": "channel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "会見",
        "pronunciation": "かいけん",
        "back": "interview, conference",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "介護",
        "pronunciation": "かいご",
        "back": "nursing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "開催",
        "pronunciation": "かいさい",
        "back": "holding a meeting, open an exhibition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "回収",
        "pronunciation": "かいしゅう",
        "back": "collection, recovery",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "改修",
        "pronunciation": "かいしゅう",
        "back": "repair, improvement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "怪獣",
        "pronunciation": "かいじゅう",
        "back": "monster",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "解除",
        "pronunciation": "かいじょ",
        "back": "cancellation, release, cancel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "外相",
        "pronunciation": "がいしょう",
        "back": "Foreign Minister",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "害する",
        "pronunciation": "がいする",
        "back": "to harm, to offend",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "概説",
        "pronunciation": "がいせつ",
        "back": "general statement, outline",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "回送",
        "pronunciation": "かいそう",
        "back": "forwarding",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "階層",
        "pronunciation": "かいそう",
        "back": "class, level, stratum, hierarchy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "開拓",
        "pronunciation": "かいたく",
        "back": "cultivation, pioneer",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "会談",
        "pronunciation": "かいだん",
        "back": "conversation, interview",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "改定",
        "pronunciation": "かいてい",
        "back": "reform",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "改訂",
        "pronunciation": "かいてい",
        "back": "revision",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ガイド",
        "pronunciation": "ガイド",
        "back": "guide",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "街道",
        "pronunciation": "かいどう",
        "back": "highway",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "該当",
        "pronunciation": "がいとう",
        "back": "corresponding, answering to, coming under",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "街頭",
        "pronunciation": "がいとう",
        "back": "in the street",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ガイドブック",
        "pronunciation": "ガイドブック",
        "back": "guidebook",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "介入",
        "pronunciation": "かいにゅう",
        "back": "intervention",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "概念",
        "pronunciation": "がいねん",
        "back": "general idea, concept, notion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "開発",
        "pronunciation": "かいはつ",
        "back": "development, exploitation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "海抜",
        "pronunciation": "かいばつ",
        "back": "height above sea level",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "介抱",
        "pronunciation": "かいほう",
        "back": "nursing, looking after",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "解剖",
        "pronunciation": "かいぼう",
        "back": "dissection, autopsy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "外来",
        "pronunciation": "がいらい",
        "back": "(abbr.) imported, outpatient clinic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "回覧",
        "pronunciation": "かいらん",
        "back": "circulation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "概略",
        "pronunciation": "がいりゃく",
        "back": "outline, summary, gist",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "海流",
        "pronunciation": "かいりゅう",
        "back": "ocean current",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "改良",
        "pronunciation": "かいりょう",
        "back": "improvement, reform",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "回路",
        "pronunciation": "かいろ",
        "back": "circuit (electric)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "海路",
        "pronunciation": "かいろ",
        "back": "sea route",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "省みる",
        "pronunciation": "かえりみる",
        "back": "to reflect",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "顧みる",
        "pronunciation": "かえりみる",
        "back": "to look back, to turn around, to review",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "顔付き",
        "pronunciation": "かおつき",
        "back": "facial expression",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "課外",
        "pronunciation": "かがい",
        "back": "extracurricular",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "掲げる",
        "pronunciation": "かかげる",
        "back": "to hoist, to fly (a sail), to float (a flag)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "かかと",
        "pronunciation": "かかと",
        "back": "shoe heel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "書き取る",
        "pronunciation": "かきとる",
        "back": "to write down, to take dictation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "掻き回す",
        "pronunciation": "かきまわす",
        "back": "to stir up, to churn, to disturb",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "かく (はじを)",
        "pronunciation": "かく (はじを)",
        "back": "to humiliate oneself",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～画",
        "pronunciation": "～かく",
        "back": "~ strokes",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "学芸",
        "pronunciation": "がくげい",
        "back": "arts and sciences, liberal arts",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "格差",
        "pronunciation": "かくさ",
        "back": "difference, disparity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "拡散",
        "pronunciation": "かくさん",
        "back": "scattering, diffusion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "学士",
        "pronunciation": "がくし",
        "back": "university graduate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "各種",
        "pronunciation": "かくしゅ",
        "back": "every kind, all sorts",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "隔週",
        "pronunciation": "かくしゅう",
        "back": "every other week",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "確信",
        "pronunciation": "かくしん",
        "back": "conviction, confidence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "革新",
        "pronunciation": "かくしん",
        "back": "reform, innovation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "学説",
        "pronunciation": "がくせつ",
        "back": "theory",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "確定",
        "pronunciation": "かくてい",
        "back": "fixed, decision",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "カクテル",
        "pronunciation": "カクテル",
        "back": "cocktail",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "獲得",
        "pronunciation": "かくとく",
        "back": "acquisition, possession",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "楽譜",
        "pronunciation": "がくふ",
        "back": "score (music, sheet music)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "確保",
        "pronunciation": "かくほ",
        "back": "guarantee, insure, secure",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "革命",
        "pronunciation": "かくめい",
        "back": "revolution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "確立",
        "pronunciation": "かくりつ",
        "back": "establishment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "賭",
        "pronunciation": "かけ",
        "back": "betting, gambling, a gamble",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "掛～",
        "pronunciation": "かけ～",
        "back": "credit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～掛け",
        "pronunciation": "～かけ",
        "back": "rack, hanger",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "崖",
        "pronunciation": "がけ",
        "back": "cliff",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "駆け足",
        "pronunciation": "かけあし",
        "back": "running fast, double time",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "家計",
        "pronunciation": "かけい",
        "back": "household economy, family finances",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "駆けっこ",
        "pronunciation": "かけっこ",
        "back": "(foot) race",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "加工",
        "pronunciation": "かこう",
        "back": "manufacturing, processing, treatment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "化合",
        "pronunciation": "かごう",
        "back": "chemical combination",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "かさばる",
        "pronunciation": "かさばる",
        "back": "to be bulky",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "かさむ",
        "pronunciation": "かさむ",
        "back": "to pile up, to increase",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "箇条書",
        "pronunciation": "かじょうがき",
        "back": "itemized form, itemization",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "頭",
        "pronunciation": "かしら",
        "back": "head, chief",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "微か",
        "pronunciation": "かすか",
        "back": "faint, dim, weak",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "霞む",
        "pronunciation": "かすむ",
        "back": "to grow hazy, to be misty",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "擦る",
        "pronunciation": "かする",
        "back": "to rub, to chafe",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "火星",
        "pronunciation": "かせい",
        "back": "Mars",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "化石",
        "pronunciation": "かせき",
        "back": "fossil, petrifaction, fossilization",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "河川",
        "pronunciation": "かせん",
        "back": "rivers",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "化繊",
        "pronunciation": "かせん",
        "back": "synthetic fibers",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "過疎",
        "pronunciation": "かそ",
        "back": "depopulation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "片～",
        "pronunciation": "かた～",
        "back": "single ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "片言",
        "pronunciation": "かたこと",
        "back": "broken (in reference to speaking style, e.g., Japanese)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "傾ける",
        "pronunciation": "かたむける",
        "back": "to incline, to tilt, to bend",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "固める",
        "pronunciation": "かためる",
        "back": "to harden, to freeze, to fortify",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "傍ら",
        "pronunciation": "かたわら",
        "back": "beside(s, while, nearby",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "花壇",
        "pronunciation": "かだん",
        "back": "flower bed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "家畜",
        "pronunciation": "かちく",
        "back": "domestic animals, livestock, cattle",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "且つ",
        "pronunciation": "かつ",
        "back": "yet, and",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "がっくり",
        "pronunciation": "がっくり",
        "back": "heartbroken",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "合唱",
        "pronunciation": "がっしょう",
        "back": "chorus, singing in a chorus",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "がっしり",
        "pronunciation": "がっしり",
        "back": "firmly, solidly, tough",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "合致",
        "pronunciation": "がっち",
        "back": "agreement, concurrence, conforming to",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "がっちり",
        "pronunciation": "がっちり",
        "back": "solidly built, tightly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "かつて",
        "pronunciation": "かつて",
        "back": "once, before, formerly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勝手",
        "pronunciation": "かって",
        "back": "kitchen; one's way, selfishness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "カット",
        "pronunciation": "カット",
        "back": "cut, cutting",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "活発",
        "pronunciation": "かっぱつ",
        "back": "vigor, active",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "合併",
        "pronunciation": "がっぺい",
        "back": "combination, amalgamation, merger",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "カテゴリー",
        "pronunciation": "カテゴリー",
        "back": "category",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "叶う",
        "pronunciation": "かなう",
        "back": "to come true",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "叶える",
        "pronunciation": "かなえる",
        "back": "to grant (request, wish)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "金槌",
        "pronunciation": "かなづち",
        "back": "(iron) hammer",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "かなわない",
        "pronunciation": "かなわない",
        "back": "be beyond one's power, be unable",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "加入",
        "pronunciation": "かにゅう",
        "back": "becoming a member, admission",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "予て",
        "pronunciation": "かねて",
        "back": "previously, already, lately",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "庇う",
        "pronunciation": "かばう",
        "back": "to protect someone, to&nbsp;&nbsp;cover up for someone",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "株式",
        "pronunciation": "かぶしき",
        "back": "stock",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "かぶれる",
        "pronunciation": "かぶれる",
        "back": "to react to; to be influenced by",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "花粉",
        "pronunciation": "かふん",
        "back": "pollen",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "貨幣",
        "pronunciation": "かへい",
        "back": "money, currency, coinage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "構える",
        "pronunciation": "かまえる",
        "back": "to set up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "過密",
        "pronunciation": "かみつ",
        "back": "crowded",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "噛み切る",
        "pronunciation": "かみきる",
        "back": "to bite off, to gnaw through",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "カムバック",
        "pronunciation": "カムバック",
        "back": "comeback",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "カメラマン",
        "pronunciation": "カメラマン",
        "back": "cameraman",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "粥",
        "pronunciation": "かゆ",
        "back": "rice porridge",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "体付き",
        "pronunciation": "からだつき",
        "back": "body build, figure",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "絡む",
        "pronunciation": "からむ",
        "back": "to entangle, to entwine",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "かりに",
        "pronunciation": "かりに",
        "back": "temporarily; if, for argument's sake",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "カルテ",
        "pronunciation": "カルテ",
        "back": "clinical records (GER: Karte)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ガレージ",
        "pronunciation": "ガレージ",
        "back": "garage (at house)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "過労",
        "pronunciation": "かろう",
        "back": "overwork, strain",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "かろうじて",
        "pronunciation": "かろうじて",
        "back": "barely, narrowly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "交す",
        "pronunciation": "かわす",
        "back": "to exchange",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "代る代る",
        "pronunciation": "かわるがわる",
        "back": "alternately",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "簡易",
        "pronunciation": "かんい",
        "back": "simplicity, easiness, quasi-",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "灌漑",
        "pronunciation": "かんがい",
        "back": "irrigation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "眼科",
        "pronunciation": "がんか",
        "back": "ophthalmology",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "眼球",
        "pronunciation": "がんきゅう",
        "back": "eyeball",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "玩具",
        "pronunciation": "がんぐ",
        "back": "toy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "簡潔",
        "pronunciation": "かんけつ",
        "back": "brevity, concise, simple",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "還元",
        "pronunciation": "かんげん",
        "back": "resolution, reduction, return",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "看護",
        "pronunciation": "かんご",
        "back": "nursing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "漢語",
        "pronunciation": "かんご",
        "back": "Chinese word, Sino-Japanese word",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "頑固",
        "pronunciation": "がんこ",
        "back": "stubbornness, obstinacy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勧告",
        "pronunciation": "かんこく",
        "back": "advice, counsel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "換算",
        "pronunciation": "かんさん",
        "back": "conversion, change, exchange",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "監視",
        "pronunciation": "かんし",
        "back": "observation, guarding, surveillance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "慣習",
        "pronunciation": "かんしゅう",
        "back": "usual (historical) custom",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "観衆",
        "pronunciation": "かんしゅう",
        "back": "spectators, audience",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "願書",
        "pronunciation": "がんしょ",
        "back": "application form",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "干渉",
        "pronunciation": "かんしょう",
        "back": "interference, intervention",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "頑丈",
        "pronunciation": "がんじょう",
        "back": "solid, firm, strong",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "感触",
        "pronunciation": "かんしょく",
        "back": "sense of touch, feeling, sensation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "肝心",
        "pronunciation": "かんじん",
        "back": "essential, fundamental, crucial",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "肝腎",
        "pronunciation": "かんじん",
        "back": "essential, fundamental, crucial",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "関税",
        "pronunciation": "かんぜい",
        "back": "customs, duty, tariff",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "岩石",
        "pronunciation": "がんせき",
        "back": "rock",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "感染",
        "pronunciation": "かんせん",
        "back": "infection, contagion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "幹線",
        "pronunciation": "かんせん",
        "back": "main line, trunk line",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "簡素",
        "pronunciation": "かんそ",
        "back": "simplicity, plain",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "観点",
        "pronunciation": "かんてん",
        "back": "point of view",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "感度",
        "pronunciation": "かんど",
        "back": "sensitivity, severity (quake)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "カンニング",
        "pronunciation": "カンニング",
        "back": "cunning, cheat",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "元年",
        "pronunciation": "がんねん",
        "back": "first year (of a specific reign)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "幹部",
        "pronunciation": "かんぶ",
        "back": "management, executive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "完ぺき",
        "pronunciation": "かんぺき",
        "back": "perfection, completeness, flawless",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勘弁",
        "pronunciation": "かんべん",
        "back": "pardon, forgiveness, forbearance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "感無量",
        "pronunciation": "かんむりょう",
        "back": "deep feeling, filled with emotion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勧誘",
        "pronunciation": "かんゆう",
        "back": "invitation, canvassing, inducement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "関与",
        "pronunciation": "かんよ",
        "back": "participation, taking part in",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "寛容",
        "pronunciation": "かんよう",
        "back": "forbearance, tolerance, generosity, involvement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "元来",
        "pronunciation": "がんらい",
        "back": "originally, naturally",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "観覧",
        "pronunciation": "かんらん",
        "back": "viewing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "慣例",
        "pronunciation": "かんれい",
        "back": "custom, precedent, of convention",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "還暦",
        "pronunciation": "かんれき",
        "back": "60th birthday",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "貫禄",
        "pronunciation": "かんろく",
        "back": "presence, dignity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "緩和",
        "pronunciation": "かんわ",
        "back": "relief, mitigation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "議案",
        "pronunciation": "ぎあん",
        "back": "legislative bill",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "危害",
        "pronunciation": "きがい",
        "back": "injury, harm, danger",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "企画",
        "pronunciation": "きかく",
        "back": "planning, project",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "規格",
        "pronunciation": "きかく",
        "back": "standard, norm",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "着飾る",
        "pronunciation": "きかざる",
        "back": "to dress up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "気兼ね",
        "pronunciation": "きがね",
        "back": "hesitance, diffidence, feeling constraint",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "気軽",
        "pronunciation": "きがる",
        "back": "cheerful, buoyant, lighthearted",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "危機",
        "pronunciation": "きき",
        "back": "crisis",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "聞き取り",
        "pronunciation": "ききとり",
        "back": "listening comprehension",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "効き目",
        "pronunciation": "ききめ",
        "back": "effect, virtue, efficacy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "帰京",
        "pronunciation": "ききょう",
        "back": "returning to Tokyo",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "戯曲",
        "pronunciation": "ぎきょく",
        "back": "play, drama",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "基金",
        "pronunciation": "ききん",
        "back": "fund, foundation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "喜劇",
        "pronunciation": "きげき",
        "back": "comedy, funny show",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "議決",
        "pronunciation": "ぎけつ",
        "back": "resolution, decision, vote",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "棄権",
        "pronunciation": "きけん",
        "back": "abstain from voting, renunciation of a right",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "既婚",
        "pronunciation": "きこん",
        "back": "married",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "気障",
        "pronunciation": "きざ",
        "back": "affectation, conceit, snobbery",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "記載",
        "pronunciation": "きさい",
        "back": "mention, entry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "兆",
        "pronunciation": "きざし",
        "back": "sign, omen, indication",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "気質",
        "pronunciation": "きしつ",
        "back": "character, trait, temperament",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "期日",
        "pronunciation": "きじつ",
        "back": "fixed date, settlement date",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "きしむ",
        "pronunciation": "きしむ",
        "back": "to jar, to creak, to grate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "議事堂",
        "pronunciation": "ぎじどう",
        "back": "Diet building",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "記述",
        "pronunciation": "きじゅつ",
        "back": "describing, descriptor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "気象",
        "pronunciation": "きしょう",
        "back": "weather, climate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "傷付く",
        "pronunciation": "きずつく",
        "back": "to be hurt, to be wounded, to get injured",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "傷付ける",
        "pronunciation": "きずつける",
        "back": "to wound, to hurt someone's feelings",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "犠牲",
        "pronunciation": "ぎせい",
        "back": "sacrifice",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "汽船",
        "pronunciation": "きせん",
        "back": "steamship",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "寄贈",
        "pronunciation": "きぞう",
        "back": "donation, presentation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "偽造",
        "pronunciation": "ぎぞう",
        "back": "forgery, fabrication, counterfeiting",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "貴族",
        "pronunciation": "きぞく",
        "back": "noble, aristocrat",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "議題",
        "pronunciation": "ぎだい",
        "back": "topic of discussion, agenda",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "鍛える",
        "pronunciation": "きたえる",
        "back": "to forge, to train, to discipline",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "気立て",
        "pronunciation": "きだて",
        "back": "good-natured, kind-hearted",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "来る",
        "pronunciation": "きたる",
        "back": "to come, to approach,",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "きちっと",
        "pronunciation": "きちっと",
        "back": "exactly, perfectly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "几帳面",
        "pronunciation": "きちょうめん",
        "back": "methodical, punctual, steady",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "きっかり",
        "pronunciation": "きっかり",
        "back": "exactly, precisely",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "きっちり",
        "pronunciation": "きっちり",
        "back": "precisely, tightly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "きっぱり",
        "pronunciation": "きっぱり",
        "back": "clearly, plainly, distinctly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "規定",
        "pronunciation": "きてい",
        "back": "regulation, provisions",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "起点",
        "pronunciation": "きてん",
        "back": "starting point",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "軌道",
        "pronunciation": "きどう",
        "back": "orbit; track",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "技能",
        "pronunciation": "ぎのう",
        "back": "technical skill, ability, capacity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "規範",
        "pronunciation": "きはん",
        "back": "model, standard, example",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "気品",
        "pronunciation": "きひん",
        "back": "grace, elegance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "気風",
        "pronunciation": "きふう",
        "back": "character, traits, ethos",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "起伏",
        "pronunciation": "きふく",
        "back": "undulation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "規模",
        "pronunciation": "きぼ",
        "back": "scale, scope, plan, structure",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "気まぐれ",
        "pronunciation": "きまぐれ",
        "back": "whim, caprice, uneven temper",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "生真面目",
        "pronunciation": "きまじめ",
        "back": "serious, sincerity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "期末",
        "pronunciation": "きまつ",
        "back": "(end of the season or term)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "きまりわるい",
        "pronunciation": "きまりわるい",
        "back": "feeling awkward, being ashamed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "記名",
        "pronunciation": "きめい",
        "back": "signature, register",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "規約",
        "pronunciation": "きやく",
        "back": "agreement, rules, code",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "脚色",
        "pronunciation": "きゃくしょく",
        "back": "dramatization (e.g., film",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "逆転",
        "pronunciation": "ぎゃくてん",
        "back": "(sudden) change, reversal, turn-around",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "脚本",
        "pronunciation": "きゃくほん",
        "back": "scenario",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "華奢",
        "pronunciation": "きゃしゃ",
        "back": "delicate, slender",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "客観",
        "pronunciation": "きゃっかん",
        "back": "objective",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "キャッチ",
        "pronunciation": "キャッチ",
        "back": "catch",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "キャリア",
        "pronunciation": "キャリア",
        "back": "career, career government employee",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "救援",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうえん",
        "back": "relief, rescue, reinforcement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "休学",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうがく",
        "back": "temporary absence from school, suspension",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "究極",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうきょく",
        "back": "ultimate, final, eventual",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "窮屈",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうくつ",
        "back": "narrow, tight, formal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "球根",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうこん",
        "back": "(plant) bulb",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "救済",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうさい",
        "back": "relief, aid, rescue",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "給仕",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうじ",
        "back": "waiter",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "給食",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうしょく",
        "back": "school lunch, providing a meal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "休戦",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうせん",
        "back": "truce, armistice",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "宮殿",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうでん",
        "back": "palace",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "旧知",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうち",
        "back": "old friend, old friendship",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "窮乏",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうぼう",
        "back": "poverty",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "寄与",
        "pronunciation": "きよ",
        "back": "contribution, service",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "強",
        "pronunciation": "きょう",
        "back": "strong",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～狂",
        "pronunciation": "～きょう",
        "back": "maniac, fan, freak",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "驚異",
        "pronunciation": "きょうい",
        "back": "wonder, miracle",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "教科",
        "pronunciation": "きょうか",
        "back": "subject, curriculum",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "協会",
        "pronunciation": "きょうかい",
        "back": "association, society, organization",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "共学",
        "pronunciation": "きょうがく",
        "back": "coeducation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "共感",
        "pronunciation": "きょうかん",
        "back": "sympathy, response",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "境遇",
        "pronunciation": "きょうぐう",
        "back": "environment, circumstances",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "教訓",
        "pronunciation": "きょうくん",
        "back": "lesson, precept, moral instruction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "強行",
        "pronunciation": "きょうこう",
        "back": "forcing, enforcement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "強硬",
        "pronunciation": "きょうこう",
        "back": "firm, vigorous, stubborn",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "教材",
        "pronunciation": "きょうざい",
        "back": "teaching materials",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "凶作",
        "pronunciation": "きょうさく",
        "back": "bad harvest, poor crop",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "業者",
        "pronunciation": "ぎょうしゃ",
        "back": "trader, merchant",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "教習",
        "pronunciation": "きょうしゅう",
        "back": "training, instruction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "郷愁",
        "pronunciation": "きょうしゅう",
        "back": "nostalgia, homesickness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "教職",
        "pronunciation": "きょうしょく",
        "back": "teaching profession",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "興じる",
        "pronunciation": "きょうじる",
        "back": "to amuse oneself, to make merry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "強制",
        "pronunciation": "きょうせい",
        "back": "obligation, compulsion, enforcement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "行政",
        "pronunciation": "ぎょうせい",
        "back": "administration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "業績",
        "pronunciation": "ぎょうせき",
        "back": "achievement, work, contribution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "共存",
        "pronunciation": "きょうぞん",
        "back": "coexistence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "協定",
        "pronunciation": "きょうてい",
        "back": "arrangement, pact, agreement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "郷土",
        "pronunciation": "きょうど",
        "back": "homeland",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "脅迫",
        "pronunciation": "きょうはく",
        "back": "threat, coercion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "業務",
        "pronunciation": "ぎょうむ",
        "back": "business, duties, work",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "共鳴",
        "pronunciation": "きょうめい",
        "back": "resonance, sympathy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "郷里",
        "pronunciation": "きょうり",
        "back": "birth-place, home town",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "強烈",
        "pronunciation": "きょうれつ",
        "back": "strong, intense, severe",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "共和",
        "pronunciation": "きょうわ",
        "back": "republicanism, cooperation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "局限",
        "pronunciation": "きょくげん",
        "back": "limit, localize",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "極端",
        "pronunciation": "きょくたん",
        "back": "extreme, extremity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "居住",
        "pronunciation": "きょじゅう",
        "back": "residence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "拒絶",
        "pronunciation": "きょぜつ",
        "back": "refusal, rejection",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "漁船",
        "pronunciation": "ぎょせん",
        "back": "fishing boat",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "漁村",
        "pronunciation": "ぎょそん",
        "back": "fishing village",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "拒否",
        "pronunciation": "きょひ",
        "back": "denial, rejection, refusal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "許容",
        "pronunciation": "きょよう",
        "back": "permission, pardon",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "清らか",
        "pronunciation": "きよらか",
        "back": "clean, pure, chaste",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "きらびやか",
        "pronunciation": "きらびやか",
        "back": "gorgeous, gaudy, dazzling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～きり",
        "pronunciation": "～きり",
        "back": "only",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "義理",
        "pronunciation": "ぎり",
        "back": "debt of gratitude, obligation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "切替",
        "pronunciation": "きりかえ",
        "back": "exchange, conversion, switchover",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "気流",
        "pronunciation": "きりゅう",
        "back": "atmospheric current",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "切れ目",
        "pronunciation": "きれめ",
        "back": "break, pause, gap",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "疑惑",
        "pronunciation": "ぎわく",
        "back": "doubt, misgivings, suspicion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "極めて",
        "pronunciation": "きわめて",
        "back": "exceedingly, extremely (written expression)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "近眼",
        "pronunciation": "きんがん",
        "back": "nearsightedness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "緊急",
        "pronunciation": "きんきゅう",
        "back": "urgent, pressing, emergency",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "近郊",
        "pronunciation": "きんこう",
        "back": "suburbs, outskirts",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "均衡",
        "pronunciation": "きんこう",
        "back": "equilibrium, balance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "禁じる",
        "pronunciation": "きんじる",
        "back": "to prohibit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勤勉",
        "pronunciation": "きんべん",
        "back": "industry, diligence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "吟味",
        "pronunciation": "ぎんみ",
        "back": "examination, careful investigation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勤務",
        "pronunciation": "きんむ",
        "back": "service, duty, work",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "禁物",
        "pronunciation": "きんもつ",
        "back": "taboo, forbidden thing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勤労",
        "pronunciation": "きんろう",
        "back": "labor, exertion, diligent service",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "クイズ",
        "pronunciation": "クイズ",
        "back": "quiz",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "食い違う",
        "pronunciation": "くいちがう",
        "back": "to cross each other, to differ",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "空間",
        "pronunciation": "くうかん",
        "back": "space, room, airspace",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "空腹",
        "pronunciation": "くうふく",
        "back": "hunger",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "区画",
        "pronunciation": "くかく",
        "back": "division, section, area",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "区間",
        "pronunciation": "くかん",
        "back": "section",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "茎",
        "pronunciation": "くき",
        "back": "stalk",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "区切り",
        "pronunciation": "くぎり",
        "back": "an end, a stop, punctuation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "くぐる",
        "pronunciation": "くぐる",
        "back": "to pass through; to go around",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "くじ (～をひく)",
        "pronunciation": "くじ (～をひく)",
        "back": "lottery, lot",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "くじびき",
        "pronunciation": "くじびき",
        "back": "lottery, drawn lot",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "くすぐったい",
        "pronunciation": "くすぐったい",
        "back": "ticklish",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "愚痴",
        "pronunciation": "ぐち",
        "back": "idle complaint, grumble",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "口吟む",
        "pronunciation": "くちずさむ",
        "back": "to humble",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "嘴",
        "pronunciation": "くちばし",
        "back": "beak, bill",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "朽ちる",
        "pronunciation": "くちる",
        "back": "to rot",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "覆す",
        "pronunciation": "くつがえす",
        "back": "to overturn, to upset, to overthrow",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "くっきり",
        "pronunciation": "くっきり",
        "back": "distinctly, clearly, boldly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "屈折",
        "pronunciation": "くっせつ",
        "back": "bending, indentation, refraction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぐっと",
        "pronunciation": "ぐっと",
        "back": "firmly, fast, more",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "首飾り",
        "pronunciation": "くびかざり",
        "back": "necklace",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "首輪",
        "pronunciation": "くびわ",
        "back": "necklace, choker",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "組み込む",
        "pronunciation": "くみこむ",
        "back": "to insert, to include, to cut in (printing)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "組み合わせる",
        "pronunciation": "くみあわせる",
        "back": "to join together, to combine, to join up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "蔵",
        "pronunciation": "くら",
        "back": "warehouse, cellar",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "グレー",
        "pronunciation": "グレー",
        "back": "grey, gray",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "クレーン",
        "pronunciation": "クレーン",
        "back": "crane",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "玄人",
        "pronunciation": "くろうと",
        "back": "expert, professional",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "黒字",
        "pronunciation": "くろじ",
        "back": "balance (figure) in the black",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "軍艦",
        "pronunciation": "ぐんかん",
        "back": "warship, battleship",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "軍事",
        "pronunciation": "ぐんじ",
        "back": "military affairs",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "君主",
        "pronunciation": "くんしゅ",
        "back": "ruler, monarch",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "群集",
        "pronunciation": "ぐんしゅう",
        "back": "(social) group, crowd, mob",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "群衆",
        "pronunciation": "ぐんしゅう",
        "back": "(social) group, crowd, mob",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "軍備",
        "pronunciation": "ぐんび",
        "back": "armaments, military preparations",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "軍服",
        "pronunciation": "ぐんぷく",
        "back": "military or naval uniform",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "芸",
        "pronunciation": "げい",
        "back": "art, accomplishment, performance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "経過",
        "pronunciation": "けいか",
        "back": "passage, progress",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "軽快",
        "pronunciation": "けいかい",
        "back": "lively, casual, light",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "警戒",
        "pronunciation": "けいかい",
        "back": "warning, admonition, vigilance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "敬具",
        "pronunciation": "けいぐ",
        "back": "Sincerely (used at the end of letter)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "軽減",
        "pronunciation": "けいげん",
        "back": "reduction, lessening",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "掲載",
        "pronunciation": "けいさい",
        "back": "appearance (e.g., article in paper)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "傾斜",
        "pronunciation": "けいしゃ",
        "back": "inclination, slope, dip",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "形成",
        "pronunciation": "けいせい",
        "back": "formation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "形勢",
        "pronunciation": "けいせい",
        "back": "condition, situation, prospects",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "軽率",
        "pronunciation": "けいそつ",
        "back": "thoughtless, careless, hasty",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "刑罰",
        "pronunciation": "けいばつ",
        "back": "judgment, penalty, punishment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "経費",
        "pronunciation": "けいひ",
        "back": "expenses, cost, outlay",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "警部",
        "pronunciation": "けいぶ",
        "back": "police inspector",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "転換",
        "pronunciation": "てんかん",
        "back": "convert, divert",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "転居",
        "pronunciation": "てんきょ",
        "back": "moving, changing residence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "転勤",
        "pronunciation": "てんきん",
        "back": "transfer (to another office of a company)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "点検",
        "pronunciation": "てんけん",
        "back": "inspection, examination, checking",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "電源",
        "pronunciation": "でんげん",
        "back": "source of electricity, power (e.g., button on TV)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "天国",
        "pronunciation": "てんごく",
        "back": "paradise, heaven, Kingdom of Heaven",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "天才",
        "pronunciation": "てんさい",
        "back": "a genius",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "天災",
        "pronunciation": "てんさい",
        "back": "natural calamity, disaster",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "展示",
        "pronunciation": "てんじ",
        "back": "exhibition, display",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "伝説",
        "pronunciation": "でんせつ",
        "back": "tradition, legend, folklore",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "点線",
        "pronunciation": "てんせん",
        "back": "dotted line",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "転じる",
        "pronunciation": "てんじる",
        "back": "to turn, to shift",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "転ずる",
        "pronunciation": "てんずる",
        "back": "to turn, to shift",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "天体",
        "pronunciation": "てんたい",
        "back": "heavenly body",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "伝達",
        "pronunciation": "でんたつ",
        "back": "transmission (e.g., news, communication, delivery)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "天地",
        "pronunciation": "てんち",
        "back": "heaven and earth, the universe",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "てんで",
        "pronunciation": "てんで",
        "back": "(not) at all, altogether, entirely",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "転任",
        "pronunciation": "てんにん",
        "back": "change of post",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "展望",
        "pronunciation": "てんぼう",
        "back": "view, outlook, prospect",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "伝来",
        "pronunciation": "でんらい",
        "back": "ancestral, hereditary, imported",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "転落",
        "pronunciation": "てんらく",
        "back": "fall, degradation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "問い合わせる",
        "pronunciation": "といあわせる",
        "back": "to inquire, to seek information",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "当～",
        "pronunciation": "とう～",
        "back": "Our ~ (e.g., Hotel, plane, etc.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "胴",
        "pronunciation": "どう",
        "back": "trunk, body, frame",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "同意",
        "pronunciation": "どうい",
        "back": "agreement, consent; same meaning",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "動員",
        "pronunciation": "どういん",
        "back": "mobilization",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "同感",
        "pronunciation": "どうかん",
        "back": "agreement, same opinion, same feeling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "陶器",
        "pronunciation": "とうき",
        "back": "pottery, ceramics",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "討議",
        "pronunciation": "とうぎ",
        "back": "debate, discussion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "動機",
        "pronunciation": "どうき",
        "back": "motive, incentive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "等級",
        "pronunciation": "とうきゅう",
        "back": "grade, class",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "同級",
        "pronunciation": "どうきゅう",
        "back": "the same grade, same class",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "同居",
        "pronunciation": "どうきょ",
        "back": "living together",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "登校",
        "pronunciation": "とうこう",
        "back": "attendance (at school)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "統合",
        "pronunciation": "とうごう",
        "back": "integration, unification, synthesis",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "動向",
        "pronunciation": "どうこう",
        "back": "trend, tendency, movement, attitude",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "投資",
        "pronunciation": "とうし",
        "back": "investment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "同情",
        "pronunciation": "どうじょう",
        "back": "sympathy, compassion, sympathize",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "道場",
        "pronunciation": "どうじょう",
        "back": "(arch) dojo, hall used for martial arts training, mandala",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "統制",
        "pronunciation": "とうせい",
        "back": "regulation, control",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "当選",
        "pronunciation": "とうせん",
        "back": "being elected, winning the prize",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "逃走",
        "pronunciation": "とうそう",
        "back": "flight, desertion, escape",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "統率",
        "pronunciation": "とうそつ",
        "back": "command, generalship, leadership",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "到達",
        "pronunciation": "とうたつ",
        "back": "reaching, attaining, arrival",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "統治",
        "pronunciation": "とうち",
        "back": "rule, reign, governing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕切る",
        "pronunciation": "しきる",
        "back": "to partition, to divide, to mark off",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "資金",
        "pronunciation": "しきん",
        "back": "funds, capital",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "軸",
        "pronunciation": "じく",
        "back": "axis, stem, shaft",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "しくじる",
        "pronunciation": "しくじる",
        "back": "to fail, to fall through, to blunder",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕組",
        "pronunciation": "しくみ",
        "back": "structure, mechanism",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "死刑",
        "pronunciation": "しけい",
        "back": "death penalty",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "湿気る",
        "pronunciation": "しける",
        "back": "to be damp, to be moist",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "施行",
        "pronunciation": "しこう",
        "back": "enforcement, operation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "思考",
        "pronunciation": "しこう",
        "back": "thought",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "志向",
        "pronunciation": "しこう",
        "back": "intention, aim",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "嗜好",
        "pronunciation": "しこう",
        "back": "taste, liking, preference",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "事項",
        "pronunciation": "じこう",
        "back": "matter(s), item(s), facts",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "時刻表",
        "pronunciation": "じこくひょう",
        "back": "timetable, (train) schedule",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "地獄",
        "pronunciation": "じごく",
        "back": "hell",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "時差",
        "pronunciation": "じさ",
        "back": "time difference",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "自在",
        "pronunciation": "じざい",
        "back": "freely, at will",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "視察",
        "pronunciation": "しさつ",
        "back": "inspection, observation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "資産",
        "pronunciation": "しさん",
        "back": "property, fortune, assets",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "支持",
        "pronunciation": "しじ",
        "back": "support",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "自主",
        "pronunciation": "じしゅ",
        "back": "independence, autonomy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "自首",
        "pronunciation": "じしゅ",
        "back": "surrender, give oneself up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "刺繍",
        "pronunciation": "ししゅう",
        "back": "embroidery",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "市場",
        "pronunciation": "しじょう",
        "back": "(the) market (as a concept)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "辞職",
        "pronunciation": "じしょく",
        "back": "resignation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雫",
        "pronunciation": "しずく",
        "back": "drop (of water)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "システム",
        "pronunciation": "システム",
        "back": "system",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "沈める",
        "pronunciation": "しずめる",
        "back": "to sink, to submerge",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "施設",
        "pronunciation": "しせつ",
        "back": "establishment, facility",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "事前",
        "pronunciation": "じぜん",
        "back": "prior, beforehand, in advance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "子息",
        "pronunciation": "しそく",
        "back": "(hon.) son",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "持続",
        "pronunciation": "じぞく",
        "back": "continuation, endurance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "自尊心",
        "pronunciation": "じそんしん",
        "back": "self-respect, conceit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "慕う",
        "pronunciation": "したう",
        "back": "to yearn to adore",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "下心",
        "pronunciation": "したごころ",
        "back": "secret intention, motive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "下地",
        "pronunciation": "したじ",
        "back": "groundwork, foundation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "親しむ",
        "pronunciation": "したしむ",
        "back": "to be intimate with, to befriend",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "下調べ",
        "pronunciation": "したしらべ",
        "back": "preliminary investigation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "愛想",
        "pronunciation": "あいそう",
        "back": "sociability",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "間柄",
        "pronunciation": "あいだがら",
        "back": "relationship",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "合間",
        "pronunciation": "あいま",
        "back": "interval",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "敢えて",
        "pronunciation": "あえて",
        "back": "dare (to do), venture (to do), challenge (to do)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仰ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "あおぐ",
        "back": "to look up (to), to respect; to ask for",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "垢",
        "pronunciation": "あか",
        "back": "dirt, filth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "赤字",
        "pronunciation": "あかじ",
        "back": "deficit, go in the red",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "明かす",
        "pronunciation": "あかす",
        "back": "to reveal; to stay up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "赤らむ",
        "pronunciation": "あからむ",
        "back": "to become red, to blush",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "上がり",
        "pronunciation": "あがり",
        "back": "ascent; income; completion, stop",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "諦め",
        "pronunciation": "あきらめ",
        "back": "resignation, reconciliation, consolation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "アクセル",
        "pronunciation": "アクセル",
        "back": "(abbr.) accelerator",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "あくどい",
        "pronunciation": "あくどい",
        "back": "gaudy vicious",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "顎",
        "pronunciation": "あご",
        "back": "chin",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "憧れ",
        "pronunciation": "あこがれ",
        "back": "yearning, longing, aspiration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "麻",
        "pronunciation": "あさ",
        "back": "hemp",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "あざ",
        "pronunciation": "あざ",
        "back": "birthmark, bruise",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "浅ましい",
        "pronunciation": "あさましい",
        "back": "shameful, mean, despicable",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "欺く",
        "pronunciation": "あざむく",
        "back": "to deceive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "鮮やか",
        "pronunciation": "あざやか",
        "back": "vivid, clear",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "嘲笑う",
        "pronunciation": "あざわらう",
        "back": "to sneer at, to ridicule",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "悪しからず",
        "pronunciation": "あしからず",
        "back": "don't take me wrong, but..., I'm sorry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "味わい",
        "pronunciation": "あじわい",
        "back": "flavor, relish",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "焦る",
        "pronunciation": "あせる",
        "back": "to be in a hurry, to be impatient",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "あせる (こえが～)",
        "pronunciation": "あせる (こえが～)",
        "back": "to fade, to discolor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "値",
        "pronunciation": "あたい",
        "back": "value, price, worth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "値する",
        "pronunciation": "あたいする",
        "back": "to be worth, to deserve",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "悪化",
        "pronunciation": "あっか",
        "back": "deterioration, worsen",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "扱い",
        "pronunciation": "あつかい",
        "back": "treatment, service",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "呆気ない",
        "pronunciation": "あっけない",
        "back": "not enough, too quick (short, long, etc.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "あっさり",
        "pronunciation": "あっさり",
        "back": "easily, readily, quickly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "斡旋",
        "pronunciation": "あっせん",
        "back": "kind offices, mediation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "圧倒",
        "pronunciation": "あっとう",
        "back": "overwhelm, overpower",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "圧迫",
        "pronunciation": "あっぱく",
        "back": "pressure, coercion, oppression",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "あつらえる",
        "pronunciation": "あつらえる",
        "back": "to give an order, to place an order",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "圧力",
        "pronunciation": "あつりょく",
        "back": "stress, pressure",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "当て",
        "pronunciation": "あて",
        "back": "expectations; depend",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～宛",
        "pronunciation": "～あて",
        "back": "for…(e.g., In a letter)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "当て字",
        "pronunciation": "あてじ",
        "back": "phonetic-equivalent character, substitute character",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "跡継ぎ",
        "pronunciation": "あとつぎ",
        "back": "heir, successor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "後回し",
        "pronunciation": "あとまわし",
        "back": "putting off, postponing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "油絵",
        "pronunciation": "あぶらえ",
        "back": "oil painting",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "アプローチ",
        "pronunciation": "アプローチ",
        "back": "approach (in golf)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "あべこべ",
        "pronunciation": "あべこべ",
        "back": "contrary, opposite, inverse",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "甘える",
        "pronunciation": "あまえる",
        "back": "to behave like a spoiled child, to fawn on",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雨具",
        "pronunciation": "あまぐ",
        "back": "rain gear",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "甘口",
        "pronunciation": "あまくち",
        "back": "sweet flavor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "アマチュア",
        "pronunciation": "アマチュア",
        "back": "amateur",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "網",
        "pronunciation": "あみ",
        "back": "net",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "操る",
        "pronunciation": "あやつる",
        "back": "to manipulate, to operate, to pull strings",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "危ぶむ",
        "pronunciation": "あやぶむ",
        "back": "to fear, to have misgivings, to be doubtful",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "あやふや",
        "pronunciation": "あやふや",
        "back": "uncertain, vague, ambiguous",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "過ち",
        "pronunciation": "あやまち",
        "back": "fault, error, indiscretion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "誤る",
        "pronunciation": "あやまる",
        "back": "to make a mistake",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "歩み",
        "pronunciation": "あゆみ",
        "back": "step, progress, history",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "歩む",
        "pronunciation": "あゆむ",
        "back": "to walk",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "予め",
        "pronunciation": "あらかじめ",
        "back": "in advance, previously",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "荒らす",
        "pronunciation": "あらす",
        "back": "to damage; to invade",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "争い",
        "pronunciation": "あらそい",
        "back": "dispute, quarrel, conflict",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "改まる",
        "pronunciation": "あらたまる",
        "back": "to be renewed; to be formal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "荒っぽい",
        "pronunciation": "あらっぽい",
        "back": "rough, rude",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "アラブ",
        "pronunciation": "アラブ",
        "back": "Arab",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "霰",
        "pronunciation": "あられ",
        "back": "hail (e.g., falling ice balls)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "有り様",
        "pronunciation": "ありさま",
        "back": "state, condition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ありのまま",
        "pronunciation": "ありのまま",
        "back": "the truth, as it is, frankly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ありふれる",
        "pronunciation": "ありふれる",
        "back": "common, ordinary, routine",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "アルカリ",
        "pronunciation": "アルカリ",
        "back": "alkali",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "アルミ",
        "pronunciation": "アルミ",
        "back": "aluminum (Al, aluminum)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "アワー",
        "pronunciation": "アワー",
        "back": "hour",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "合わす",
        "pronunciation": "あわす",
        "back": "to join together, to face, to unite",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～合せ",
        "pronunciation": "～あわせ",
        "back": "in all",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "アンコール",
        "pronunciation": "アンコール",
        "back": "encore",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "暗殺",
        "pronunciation": "あんさつ",
        "back": "assassination",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "暗算",
        "pronunciation": "あんざん",
        "back": "mental arithmetic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "暗示",
        "pronunciation": "あんじ",
        "back": "hint, suggestion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "案じる",
        "pronunciation": "あんじる",
        "back": "to be anxious, to ponder",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "安静",
        "pronunciation": "あんせい",
        "back": "rest",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "案の定",
        "pronunciation": "あんのじょう",
        "back": "sure enough, as usual",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "いい加減",
        "pronunciation": "いいかげん",
        "back": "random, irresponsible",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "言い訳",
        "pronunciation": "いいわけ",
        "back": "excuse, explanation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "イェス",
        "pronunciation": "イェス",
        "back": "yes; Jesus",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "家出",
        "pronunciation": "いえで",
        "back": "running away from home",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "生かす",
        "pronunciation": "いかす",
        "back": "to keep something alive; to make use of",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "いかに",
        "pronunciation": "いかに",
        "back": "how, in what way",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "いかにも",
        "pronunciation": "いかにも",
        "back": "truly (same as 実に (じつに))",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "異議",
        "pronunciation": "いぎ",
        "back": "objection, dissent, protest",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "生き甲斐",
        "pronunciation": "いきがい",
        "back": "something one lives for, very important",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "行き違い",
        "pronunciation": "いきちがい",
        "back": "misunderstanding, disagreement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "意気込む",
        "pronunciation": "いきごむ",
        "back": "to be enthusiastic about",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "育成",
        "pronunciation": "いくせい",
        "back": "rearing, training, cultivation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "幾多",
        "pronunciation": "いくた",
        "back": "many, numerous",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "(花を〜) 生ける, 活ける",
        "pronunciation": "(はなを～) いける",
        "back": "to arrange (flowers)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "異見",
        "pronunciation": "いけん",
        "back": "different opinion, objection",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "意向",
        "pronunciation": "いこう",
        "back": "intention, idea, inclination",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "移行",
        "pronunciation": "いこう",
        "back": "switching over to",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "いざ",
        "pronunciation": "いざ",
        "back": "now, come (now), crucial moment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "移住",
        "pronunciation": "いじゅう",
        "back": "migration, immigration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "衣装",
        "pronunciation": "いしょう",
        "back": "clothing, costume, outfit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "いじる",
        "pronunciation": "いじる",
        "back": "to touch, to tamper with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "異性",
        "pronunciation": "いせい",
        "back": "the opposite sex",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "遺跡",
        "pronunciation": "いせき",
        "back": "historic ruins",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "依存",
        "pronunciation": "いぞん",
        "back": "dependence, dependent, reliance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "委託",
        "pronunciation": "いたく",
        "back": "consign (goods (for sale) to a firm), entrust",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "いたって",
        "pronunciation": "いたって",
        "back": "very much, exceedingly, extremely",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出世",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっせ",
        "back": "promotion, successful career, eminence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出題",
        "pronunciation": "しゅつだい",
        "back": "proposing a question",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出動",
        "pronunciation": "しゅつどう",
        "back": "mobilization, action",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出費",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっぴ",
        "back": "expenses, disbursements",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出品",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっぴん",
        "back": "exhibit, display",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主導",
        "pronunciation": "しゅどう",
        "back": "main leadership",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主任",
        "pronunciation": "しゅにん",
        "back": "person in charge, responsible official",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "首脳",
        "pronunciation": "しゅのう",
        "back": "head, leader",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "守備",
        "pronunciation": "しゅび",
        "back": "defense",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手法",
        "pronunciation": "しゅほう",
        "back": "technique",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "樹木",
        "pronunciation": "じゅもく",
        "back": "trees and shrubs, arbor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "樹立",
        "pronunciation": "じゅりつ",
        "back": "establish, create",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "準急",
        "pronunciation": "じゅんきゅう",
        "back": "local express (train, slower than an express)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "準じる",
        "pronunciation": "じゅんじる",
        "back": "to follow, to conform, to apply to",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～署",
        "pronunciation": "～しょ",
        "back": "department",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～症",
        "pronunciation": "～しょう",
        "back": "disease",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～証",
        "pronunciation": "～しょう",
        "back": "proof, certificate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～嬢",
        "pronunciation": "～じょう",
        "back": "young woman",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "上位",
        "pronunciation": "じょうい",
        "back": "superior, higher order",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "上演",
        "pronunciation": "じょうえん",
        "back": "art performance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "城下",
        "pronunciation": "じょうか",
        "back": "land near the castle",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "消去",
        "pronunciation": "しょうきょ",
        "back": "elimination, erasing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "上空",
        "pronunciation": "じょうくう",
        "back": "sky, high-altitude sky, upper air",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "衝撃",
        "pronunciation": "しょうげき",
        "back": "shock, crash, impact, ballistic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "証言",
        "pronunciation": "しょうげん",
        "back": "evidence, testimony",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "証拠",
        "pronunciation": "しょうこ",
        "back": "evidence, proof",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "照合",
        "pronunciation": "しょうごう",
        "back": "check, verification",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "詳細",
        "pronunciation": "しょうさい",
        "back": "detail, particulars",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "上昇",
        "pronunciation": "じょうしょう",
        "back": "rising, ascending, climbing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "昇進",
        "pronunciation": "しょうしん",
        "back": "promotion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "称する",
        "pronunciation": "しょうする",
        "back": "to take the name of, to call oneself",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "情勢",
        "pronunciation": "じょうせい",
        "back": "state of things, condition, situation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "消息",
        "pronunciation": "しょうそく",
        "back": "news, letter, circumstances",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "承諾",
        "pronunciation": "しょうだく",
        "back": "consent, agreement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "情緒",
        "pronunciation": "じょうちょ",
        "back": "emotion, feeling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "情緒",
        "pronunciation": "じょうしょ",
        "back": "emotion, feeling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "象徴",
        "pronunciation": "しょうちょう",
        "back": "symbol",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "小児科",
        "pronunciation": "しょうにか",
        "back": "pediatrics",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "使用人",
        "pronunciation": "しようにん",
        "back": "employee, servant",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "情熱",
        "pronunciation": "じょうねつ",
        "back": "passion, enthusiasm, zeal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "譲歩",
        "pronunciation": "じょうほ",
        "back": "concession, conciliation, compromise",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "条約",
        "pronunciation": "じょうやく",
        "back": "treaty, pact",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勝利",
        "pronunciation": "しょうり",
        "back": "victory, triumph, win",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "上陸",
        "pronunciation": "じょうりく",
        "back": "landing, disembarkation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "蒸溜",
        "pronunciation": "じょうりゅう",
        "back": "distillation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "奨励",
        "pronunciation": "しょうれい",
        "back": "encouragement, promotion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ショー",
        "pronunciation": "ショー",
        "back": "show",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "除外",
        "pronunciation": "じょがい",
        "back": "exception, exclusion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "職員",
        "pronunciation": "しょくいん",
        "back": "staff member, personnel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "植民地",
        "pronunciation": "しょくみんち",
        "back": "colony",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "職務",
        "pronunciation": "しょくむ",
        "back": "professional duties",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "諸君",
        "pronunciation": "しょくん",
        "back": "Gentlemen!, Ladies!",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "助言",
        "pronunciation": "じょげん",
        "back": "advice, suggestion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "徐行",
        "pronunciation": "じょこう",
        "back": "going slowly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "所在",
        "pronunciation": "しょざい",
        "back": "whereabouts",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "所持",
        "pronunciation": "しょじ",
        "back": "possession, owning",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "所属",
        "pronunciation": "しょぞく",
        "back": "attached to, belong to",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "処置",
        "pronunciation": "しょち",
        "back": "treatment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "しょっちゅう",
        "pronunciation": "しょっちゅう",
        "back": "always, constantly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "所定",
        "pronunciation": "しょてい",
        "back": "fixed, prescribed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "所得",
        "pronunciation": "しょとく",
        "back": "income",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "処罰",
        "pronunciation": "しょばつ",
        "back": "punishment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "初版",
        "pronunciation": "しょはん",
        "back": "first edition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "書評",
        "pronunciation": "しょひょう",
        "back": "book review",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "処分",
        "pronunciation": "しょぶん",
        "back": "disposal, dealing, punishment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "庶民",
        "pronunciation": "しょみん",
        "back": "masses, common people",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "庶務",
        "pronunciation": "しょむ",
        "back": "general affairs",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "所有",
        "pronunciation": "しょゆう",
        "back": "one's possessions, ownership",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "調べ",
        "pronunciation": "しらべ",
        "back": "investigation, inspection",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "自立",
        "pronunciation": "じりつ",
        "back": "independence, self-reliance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "記す",
        "pronunciation": "しるす",
        "back": "to note, to write down",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "指令",
        "pronunciation": "しれい",
        "back": "orders, instructions, directive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～心",
        "pronunciation": "～しん",
        "back": "mind of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "陣",
        "pronunciation": "じん",
        "back": "battle formation, camp, encampment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "進化",
        "pronunciation": "しんか",
        "back": "evolution, progress",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "人格",
        "pronunciation": "じんかく",
        "back": "personality, character",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "審議",
        "pronunciation": "しんぎ",
        "back": "deliberation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "新婚",
        "pronunciation": "しんこん",
        "back": "newly-wed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "審査",
        "pronunciation": "しんさ",
        "back": "judging, inspection, examination",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "人材",
        "pronunciation": "じんざい",
        "back": "man of talent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "紳士",
        "pronunciation": "しんし",
        "back": "gentleman",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "真実",
        "pronunciation": "しんじつ",
        "back": "truth, reality",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "信者",
        "pronunciation": "しんじゃ",
        "back": "believer, devotee",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "真珠",
        "pronunciation": "しんじゅ",
        "back": "pearl",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "進出",
        "pronunciation": "しんしゅつ",
        "back": "advancement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "心情",
        "pronunciation": "しんじょう",
        "back": "mentality",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "新人",
        "pronunciation": "しんじん",
        "back": "new face, newcomer",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "神聖",
        "pronunciation": "しんせい",
        "back": "holiness, sacredness, dignity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "親善",
        "pronunciation": "しんぜん",
        "back": "friendship",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "真相",
        "pronunciation": "しんそう",
        "back": "truth, real situation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "迅速",
        "pronunciation": "じんそく",
        "back": "quick, fast, prompt",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "人体",
        "pronunciation": "じんたい",
        "back": "human body",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "新築",
        "pronunciation": "しんちく",
        "back": "new building, new construction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "心中",
        "pronunciation": "しんじゅう",
        "back": "double suicide",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "進呈",
        "pronunciation": "しんてい",
        "back": "presentation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "進展",
        "pronunciation": "しんてん",
        "back": "progress, development",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "神殿",
        "pronunciation": "しんでん",
        "back": "temple, sacred place",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "進度",
        "pronunciation": "しんど",
        "back": "progress",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "振動",
        "pronunciation": "しんどう",
        "back": "oscillation, vibration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "新入生",
        "pronunciation": "しんにゅうせい",
        "back": "new student, first-year student, freshman",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "信任",
        "pronunciation": "しんにん",
        "back": "trust, confidence, credence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "神秘",
        "pronunciation": "しんぴ",
        "back": "mystery",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "辛抱",
        "pronunciation": "しんぼう",
        "back": "patience, endurance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "人民",
        "pronunciation": "じんみん",
        "back": "people, public",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "侵略",
        "pronunciation": "しんりゃく",
        "back": "aggression, invasion, raid",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "診療",
        "pronunciation": "しんりょう",
        "back": "medical examination and treatment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "粋",
        "pronunciation": "すい",
        "back": "essence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "水源",
        "pronunciation": "すいげん",
        "back": "source of river",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "推進",
        "pronunciation": "すいしん",
        "back": "propulsion, driving force",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "吹奏",
        "pronunciation": "すいそう",
        "back": "playing wind instruments",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "推測",
        "pronunciation": "すいそく",
        "back": "guess, conjecture",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "水田",
        "pronunciation": "すいでん",
        "back": "(water-filled) paddy field",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "推理",
        "pronunciation": "すいり",
        "back": "reasoning, inference, mystery or detective genre",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "数詞",
        "pronunciation": "すうし",
        "back": "numeral",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "崇拝",
        "pronunciation": "すうはい",
        "back": "worship, adoration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "据え付ける",
        "pronunciation": "すえつける",
        "back": "to install, to equip, to mount",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "据える",
        "pronunciation": "すえる",
        "back": "to set, to lay, to place",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "すがすがしい",
        "pronunciation": "すがすがしい",
        "back": "fresh, refreshing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "救い",
        "pronunciation": "すくい",
        "back": "help, aid, relief",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "すくう (みずを～)",
        "pronunciation": "すくう (みずを～)",
        "back": "to scoop",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "健やか",
        "pronunciation": "すこやか",
        "back": "vigorous, healthy, sound",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "濯ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "すすぐ",
        "back": "to rinse, to wash out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "進み",
        "pronunciation": "すすみ",
        "back": "progress",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "裾",
        "pronunciation": "すそ",
        "back": "(trouser) cuff, (skirt) hem, cut edge of a hairdo",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "スタジオ",
        "pronunciation": "スタジオ",
        "back": "studio",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "スチーム",
        "pronunciation": "スチーム",
        "back": "steam",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ストライキ",
        "pronunciation": "ストライキ",
        "back": "strike",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "スト",
        "pronunciation": "スト",
        "back": "(abbr.) strike",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ストロー",
        "pronunciation": "ストロー",
        "back": "straw",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ストロボ",
        "pronunciation": "ストロボ",
        "back": "stroboscope (literally: strobo, strobe lamp, stroboscopic lamp)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "すばしこい",
        "pronunciation": "すばしこい",
        "back": "nimble, smart, quick",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "素早い",
        "pronunciation": "すばやい",
        "back": "fast, quick",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ずばり",
        "pronunciation": "ずばり",
        "back": "decisively, unreservedly, frankly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "スプリング",
        "pronunciation": "スプリング",
        "back": "spring",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "スペース",
        "pronunciation": "スペース",
        "back": "space",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ずぶぬれ",
        "pronunciation": "ずぶぬれ",
        "back": "soaked, dripping wet",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "スポーツカー",
        "pronunciation": "スポーツカー",
        "back": "sports car",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "澄ます",
        "pronunciation": "すます",
        "back": "to clear, to make clear, to listen for",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "清ます",
        "pronunciation": "すます",
        "back": "to clear, to make clear, to listen for",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "済ます",
        "pronunciation": "すます",
        "back": "to finish; to settle; to do without",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "すみやか",
        "pronunciation": "すみやか",
        "back": "speedy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "スラックス",
        "pronunciation": "スラックス",
        "back": "slacks",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ずらっと",
        "pronunciation": "ずらっと",
        "back": "in a line, in a row",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ずるずる",
        "pronunciation": "ずるずる",
        "back": "dragging on, sound of sniffling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ずれ",
        "pronunciation": "ずれ",
        "back": "difference, gap",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "すれちがい",
        "pronunciation": "すれちがい",
        "back": "chance encounter",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "擦れる",
        "pronunciation": "すれる",
        "back": "to rub, to chafe",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "すんなり",
        "pronunciation": "すんなり",
        "back": "pass with no objection, slim, slender",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "生育",
        "pronunciation": "せいいく",
        "back": "growth, development, breeding",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "成育",
        "pronunciation": "せいいく",
        "back": "growth, raising",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "成果",
        "pronunciation": "せいか",
        "back": "results, fruits",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "正解",
        "pronunciation": "せいかい",
        "back": "correct, right answer, solution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "正義",
        "pronunciation": "せいぎ",
        "back": "justice, right, righteousness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "生計",
        "pronunciation": "せいけい",
        "back": "livelihood, living",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "政権",
        "pronunciation": "せいけん",
        "back": "(political) administration, political power",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "星座",
        "pronunciation": "せいざ",
        "back": "constellation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "制裁",
        "pronunciation": "せいさい",
        "back": "restraint, sanctions, punishment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "政策",
        "pronunciation": "せいさく",
        "back": "political measures, policy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "生死",
        "pronunciation": "せいし",
        "back": "life and death",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "静止",
        "pronunciation": "せいし",
        "back": "stillness, repose, standing still",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "誠実",
        "pronunciation": "せいじつ",
        "back": "sincere, honest, faithful",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "成熟",
        "pronunciation": "せいじゅく",
        "back": "maturity, ripeness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "青春",
        "pronunciation": "せいしゅん",
        "back": "youth, springtime of life, adolescent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "清純",
        "pronunciation": "せいじゅん",
        "back": "purity, innocence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "聖書",
        "pronunciation": "せいしょ",
        "back": "Bible",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "正常",
        "pronunciation": "せいじょう",
        "back": "normalcy, normality, normal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "制する",
        "pronunciation": "せいする",
        "back": "to control, to command",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "整然",
        "pronunciation": "せいぜん",
        "back": "orderly, regular, well-organized",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "盛装",
        "pronunciation": "せいそう",
        "back": "be dressed up, wear rich clothes",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "盛大",
        "pronunciation": "せいだい",
        "back": "grand, prosperous, magnificent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "清濁",
        "pronunciation": "せいだく",
        "back": "good and evil, purity and impurity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "制定",
        "pronunciation": "せいてい",
        "back": "enactment, establishment, creation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "静的",
        "pronunciation": "せいてき",
        "back": "static",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "製鉄",
        "pronunciation": "せいてつ",
        "back": "iron manufacture",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "晴天",
        "pronunciation": "せいてん",
        "back": "fine weather",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "正当",
        "pronunciation": "せいとう",
        "back": "just, due, proper",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "制服",
        "pronunciation": "せいふく",
        "back": "uniform",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "征服",
        "pronunciation": "せいふく",
        "back": "conquest, subjugation, overcoming",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "製法",
        "pronunciation": "せいほう",
        "back": "manufacturing method, recipe, formula",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "精密",
        "pronunciation": "せいみつ",
        "back": "precise, exact, detailed, minute",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "税務署",
        "pronunciation": "ぜいむしょ",
        "back": "tax office",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "制約",
        "pronunciation": "せいやく",
        "back": "limitation, constraints",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勢力",
        "pronunciation": "せいりょく",
        "back": "influence, power, might, strength",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "整列",
        "pronunciation": "せいれつ",
        "back": "stand in a row, form a line",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "セール",
        "pronunciation": "セール",
        "back": "sale",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "急かす",
        "pronunciation": "せかす",
        "back": "to hurry, to urge on",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "伜",
        "pronunciation": "せがれ",
        "back": "son, my son",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "責務",
        "pronunciation": "せきむ",
        "back": "duty, obligation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "セクション",
        "pronunciation": "セクション",
        "back": "section",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "世辞",
        "pronunciation": "せじ",
        "back": "flattery, compliment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "世帯",
        "pronunciation": "せたい",
        "back": "household",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "是正",
        "pronunciation": "ぜせい",
        "back": "correction, revision",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "世代",
        "pronunciation": "せだい",
        "back": "generation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "切開",
        "pronunciation": "せっかい",
        "back": "opening up, cutting through",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "セックス",
        "pronunciation": "セックス",
        "back": "sex",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "切実",
        "pronunciation": "せつじつ",
        "back": "compelling, serious, severe, acute",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "接触",
        "pronunciation": "せっしょく",
        "back": "touch, contact",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "接続詞",
        "pronunciation": "せつぞくし",
        "back": "conjunction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "設置",
        "pronunciation": "せっち",
        "back": "establishment, institution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "折衷",
        "pronunciation": "せっちゅう",
        "back": "compromise, cross, blending, eclecticism",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "設定",
        "pronunciation": "せってい",
        "back": "establishment, creation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "説得",
        "pronunciation": "せっとく",
        "back": "persuasion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "切ない",
        "pronunciation": "せつない",
        "back": "painful, trying, sad",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "絶版",
        "pronunciation": "ぜっぱん",
        "back": "out of print",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "設立",
        "pronunciation": "せつりつ",
        "back": "establishment, foundation, institution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "攻め",
        "pronunciation": "せめ",
        "back": "attack, offense",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ゼリー",
        "pronunciation": "ゼリー",
        "back": "jelly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "セレモニー",
        "pronunciation": "セレモニー",
        "back": "ceremony",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "世論",
        "pronunciation": "せろん",
        "back": "public opinion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "先",
        "pronunciation": "せん",
        "back": "priority, precedence, previous",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "繊維",
        "pronunciation": "せんい",
        "back": "fiber, fiber, textile",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "全快",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんかい",
        "back": "complete recovery of health",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "宣教",
        "pronunciation": "せんきょう",
        "back": "religious mission",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "宣言",
        "pronunciation": "せんげん",
        "back": "declaration, proclamation, announcement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "戦災",
        "pronunciation": "せんさい",
        "back": "war damage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "専修",
        "pronunciation": "せんしゅう",
        "back": "specialization",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "戦術",
        "pronunciation": "せんじゅつ",
        "back": "tactics",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "センス",
        "pronunciation": "センス",
        "back": "sense (for music, style, tact, etc.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "潜水",
        "pronunciation": "せんすい",
        "back": "diving",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "全盛",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんせい",
        "back": "height of prosperity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "先代",
        "pronunciation": "せんだい",
        "back": "family predecessor, previous age, previous generation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "先だって",
        "pronunciation": "せんだって",
        "back": "recently, the other day",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "先着",
        "pronunciation": "せんちゃく",
        "back": "first arrival",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "前提",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんてい",
        "back": "preamble, premise, prerequisite",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "先天的",
        "pronunciation": "せんてんてき",
        "back": "inherent, congenital, hereditary",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "前途",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんと",
        "back": "future prospects, outlook, the journey ahead",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "戦闘",
        "pronunciation": "せんとう",
        "back": "battle, fight, combat",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "潜入",
        "pronunciation": "せんにゅう",
        "back": "infiltration, sneaking in",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "船舶",
        "pronunciation": "せんぱく",
        "back": "ship",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "全滅",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんめつ",
        "back": "annihilation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "専用",
        "pronunciation": "せんよう",
        "back": "exclusive use, personal use",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "占領",
        "pronunciation": "せんりょう",
        "back": "occupation, possession, have a room to oneself",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "善良",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんりょう",
        "back": "goodness, excellence, virtue",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "戦力",
        "pronunciation": "せんりょく",
        "back": "war potential",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "前例",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんれい",
        "back": "precedent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "相応",
        "pronunciation": "そうおう",
        "back": "suitability, fitness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "総会",
        "pronunciation": "そうかい",
        "back": "general meeting",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "創刊",
        "pronunciation": "そうかん",
        "back": "launching (e.g., newspaper, first issue)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雑木",
        "pronunciation": "ぞうき",
        "back": "various kinds of small trees, assorted trees",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "早急",
        "pronunciation": "そうきゅう",
        "back": "urgent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "早急",
        "pronunciation": "さっきゅう",
        "back": "urgent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "増強",
        "pronunciation": "ぞうきょう",
        "back": "reinforce, increase",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "送金",
        "pronunciation": "そうきん",
        "back": "remittance, sending money",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "走行",
        "pronunciation": "そうこう",
        "back": "running a wheeled vehicle (e.g., car, traveling)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "総合",
        "pronunciation": "そうごう",
        "back": "synthesis, generalization",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "捜索",
        "pronunciation": "そうさく",
        "back": "search (esp. for someone or something missing, investigation)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "蔵相",
        "pronunciation": "ぞうしょう",
        "back": "Minister of Finance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "装飾",
        "pronunciation": "そうしょく",
        "back": "ornament",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "増進",
        "pronunciation": "ぞうしん",
        "back": "promoting, increase, advance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "相対",
        "pronunciation": "そうたい",
        "back": "relative",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "壮大",
        "pronunciation": "そうだい",
        "back": "magnificent, grand, majestic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "騒動",
        "pronunciation": "そうどう",
        "back": "strife, riot, rebellion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "遭難",
        "pronunciation": "そうなん",
        "back": "disaster, shipwreck, accident",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "相場",
        "pronunciation": "そうば",
        "back": "market price, speculation, estimation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "装備",
        "pronunciation": "そうび",
        "back": "equipment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "創立",
        "pronunciation": "そうりつ",
        "back": "establishment, founding",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "添える",
        "pronunciation": "そえる",
        "back": "to add to, to attach, to accompany",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ソース",
        "pronunciation": "ソース",
        "back": "source",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "即座に",
        "pronunciation": "そくざに",
        "back": "immediately, right away",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "促進",
        "pronunciation": "そくしん",
        "back": "promotion, acceleration, encouragement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "即する",
        "pronunciation": "そくする",
        "back": "to conform to, to agree with, to be adapted to,",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "束縛",
        "pronunciation": "そくばく",
        "back": "restraint, restriction, confinement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "側面",
        "pronunciation": "そくめん",
        "back": "side, sidelight, lateral",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "損う",
        "pronunciation": "そこなう",
        "back": "to harm, to hurt",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "そこら",
        "pronunciation": "そこら",
        "back": "everywhere, somewhere",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "素材",
        "pronunciation": "そざい",
        "back": "raw materials, subject matter",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "阻止",
        "pronunciation": "そし",
        "back": "obstruction, check, hindrance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "訴訟",
        "pronunciation": "そしょう",
        "back": "litigation, lawsuit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "育ち",
        "pronunciation": "そだち",
        "back": "breeding, growth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "措置",
        "pronunciation": "そち",
        "back": "measure, step",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ソックス",
        "pronunciation": "ソックス",
        "back": "socks",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "素っ気無い",
        "pronunciation": "そっけない",
        "back": "cold, short, curt, blunt",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "外方",
        "pronunciation": "そっぽ",
        "back": "look (or turn) the other way",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "備え付ける",
        "pronunciation": "そなえつける",
        "back": "to provide, to equip, to install",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "備わる",
        "pronunciation": "そなわる",
        "back": "to be furnished with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "具わる",
        "pronunciation": "そなわる",
        "back": "to be furnished with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "聳える",
        "pronunciation": "そびえる",
        "back": "to rise, to tower, to soar",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "素朴",
        "pronunciation": "そぼく",
        "back": "simplicity, artlessness, naivety",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "背く",
        "pronunciation": "そむく",
        "back": "to run counter to, to go against",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "染まる",
        "pronunciation": "そまる",
        "back": "to be dyed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "染める",
        "pronunciation": "そめる",
        "back": "to dye, to color",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "そらす",
        "pronunciation": "そらす",
        "back": "to bend, to warp",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "そり (～にのる)",
        "pronunciation": "そり (～にのる)",
        "back": "sleigh, sled",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "反る",
        "pronunciation": "そる",
        "back": "to warp, to be warped, to curve",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "それゆえ",
        "pronunciation": "それゆえ",
        "back": "therefore, for that reason, so",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ソロ",
        "pronunciation": "ソロ",
        "back": "solo",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "揃い",
        "pronunciation": "そろい",
        "back": "set, suit, uniform",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぞんざい",
        "pronunciation": "ぞんざい",
        "back": "rude, careless, slovenly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "損失",
        "pronunciation": "そんしつ",
        "back": "loss",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "存続",
        "pronunciation": "そんぞく",
        "back": "duration, continuance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ダース",
        "pronunciation": "ダース",
        "back": "dozen",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "対応",
        "pronunciation": "たいおう",
        "back": "dealing with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大家",
        "pronunciation": "たいか",
        "back": "rich family, distinguished family",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "退化",
        "pronunciation": "たいか",
        "back": "degeneration, retrogression",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大概",
        "pronunciation": "たいがい",
        "back": "in general, mainly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "体格",
        "pronunciation": "たいかく",
        "back": "physique, constitution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大金",
        "pronunciation": "たいきん",
        "back": "large amount of money",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "待遇",
        "pronunciation": "たいぐう",
        "back": "treatment, reception",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "対決",
        "pronunciation": "たいけつ",
        "back": "confrontation, showdown",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "体験",
        "pronunciation": "たいけん",
        "back": "personal experience",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "対抗",
        "pronunciation": "たいこう",
        "back": "opposition, antagonism",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "退治",
        "pronunciation": "たいじ",
        "back": "extermination",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大衆",
        "pronunciation": "たいしゅう",
        "back": "general public",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "対処",
        "pronunciation": "たいしょ",
        "back": "deal with, cope",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "退職",
        "pronunciation": "たいしょく",
        "back": "retirement (from office)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "題する",
        "pronunciation": "だいする",
        "back": "to title",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "態勢",
        "pronunciation": "たいせい",
        "back": "attitude, conditions, tendency",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "対談",
        "pronunciation": "たいだん",
        "back": "talk, dialogue",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大胆",
        "pronunciation": "だいたん",
        "back": "bold, daring, audacious",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "対等",
        "pronunciation": "たいとう",
        "back": "equivalent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "台無し",
        "pronunciation": "だいなし",
        "back": "mess, spoiled, (come to) nothing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "滞納",
        "pronunciation": "たいのう",
        "back": "non-payment, default",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "対比",
        "pronunciation": "たいひ",
        "back": "contrast, comparison",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "タイピスト",
        "pronunciation": "タイピスト",
        "back": "typist",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大部",
        "pronunciation": "たいぶ",
        "back": "most (e.g., most part, greater, fairly, a good deal, much)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "大便",
        "pronunciation": "だいべん",
        "back": "feces",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "代弁",
        "pronunciation": "だいべん",
        "back": "speak for another",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "待望",
        "pronunciation": "たいぼう",
        "back": "long-expected, waiting",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "台本",
        "pronunciation": "だいほん",
        "back": "libretto, scenario",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "タイマー",
        "pronunciation": "タイマー",
        "back": "timer",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "怠慢",
        "pronunciation": "たいまん",
        "back": "negligence, carelessness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "タイミング",
        "pronunciation": "タイミング",
        "back": "timing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "タイム",
        "pronunciation": "タイム",
        "back": "time",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "タイムリー",
        "pronunciation": "タイムリー",
        "back": "timely, run-batted-in (baseball), RBI",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "対面",
        "pronunciation": "たいめん",
        "back": "interview, meeting",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "代用",
        "pronunciation": "だいよう",
        "back": "substitution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "体力",
        "pronunciation": "たいりょく",
        "back": "physical strength",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "タイル",
        "pronunciation": "タイル",
        "back": "tile",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "対話",
        "pronunciation": "たいわ",
        "back": "conversation, dialogue",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "耐える",
        "pronunciation": "たえる",
        "back": "to endure, to put up with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "堪える",
        "pronunciation": "たえる",
        "back": "to endure, to put up with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "絶える",
        "pronunciation": "たえる",
        "back": "to die out, to become extinct",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "断える",
        "pronunciation": "たえる",
        "back": "to cease, to become extinct",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "打開",
        "pronunciation": "だかい",
        "back": "solution, breakthrough",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "焚火",
        "pronunciation": "たきび",
        "back": "(open) fire",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "妥協",
        "pronunciation": "だきょう",
        "back": "compromise, giving in",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "たくましい",
        "pronunciation": "たくましい",
        "back": "burly, strong, sturdy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "巧み",
        "pronunciation": "たくみ",
        "back": "skill, cleverness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "丈",
        "pronunciation": "たけ",
        "back": "length, height",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "打撃",
        "pronunciation": "だげき",
        "back": "blow, damage; batting (baseball)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "妥結",
        "pronunciation": "だけつ",
        "back": "agreement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "駄作",
        "pronunciation": "ださく",
        "back": "poor work",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "足し算",
        "pronunciation": "たしざん",
        "back": "addition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "多数決",
        "pronunciation": "たすうけつ",
        "back": "majority rule",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "助け",
        "pronunciation": "たすけ",
        "back": "assistance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "携わる",
        "pronunciation": "たずさわる",
        "back": "to engage, to involve",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "漂う",
        "pronunciation": "ただよう",
        "back": "to drift about, to float, to hang in air",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "立ち去る",
        "pronunciation": "たちさる",
        "back": "to leave, to depart",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "立ち寄る",
        "pronunciation": "たちよる",
        "back": "to stop by, to drop in for a short visit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "抱っこ",
        "pronunciation": "だっこ",
        "back": "(child's) hug",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "達者",
        "pronunciation": "たっしゃ",
        "back": "skillful, in good health",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "脱出",
        "pronunciation": "だっしゅつ",
        "back": "escape",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "脱する",
        "pronunciation": "だっする",
        "back": "to escape from, to get out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "達成",
        "pronunciation": "たっせい",
        "back": "achievement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "脱退",
        "pronunciation": "だったい",
        "back": "secession, withdrawal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "だったら",
        "pronunciation": "だったら",
        "back": "if it's the case",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "立て替える",
        "pronunciation": "たてかえる",
        "back": "to pay in advance, to pay for another",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "建前",
        "pronunciation": "たてまえ",
        "back": "position; stance one takes in public; principle",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "奉る",
        "pronunciation": "たてまつる",
        "back": "to offer, to do respectfully",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "だと",
        "pronunciation": "だと",
        "back": "if it's the case",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "他動詞",
        "pronunciation": "たどうし",
        "back": "transitive verb (direct object)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "辿り着く",
        "pronunciation": "たどりつく",
        "back": "to reach, to make it somehow",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "辿る",
        "pronunciation": "たどる",
        "back": "to follow (road, to pursue (course), to follow up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "束ねる",
        "pronunciation": "たばねる",
        "back": "to tie up in a bundle, to control",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "だぶだぶ",
        "pronunciation": "だぶだぶ",
        "back": "loose, baggy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "他方",
        "pronunciation": "たほう",
        "back": "another side, on the other hand",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "多忙",
        "pronunciation": "たぼう",
        "back": "busy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "給う",
        "pronunciation": "たまう",
        "back": "to receive, to grant",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "魂",
        "pronunciation": "たましい",
        "back": "soul, spirit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "溜まり",
        "pronunciation": "たまり",
        "back": "collected things, gathering place, arrears",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "賜る",
        "pronunciation": "たまわる",
        "back": "to grant, to bestow",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "保つ",
        "pronunciation": "たもつ",
        "back": "to keep, to preserve, to sustain",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "たやすい",
        "pronunciation": "たやすい",
        "back": "easy, simple, light",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "多様",
        "pronunciation": "たよう",
        "back": "diversity, variety",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "だるい",
        "pronunciation": "だるい",
        "back": "sluggish, feel heavy (tired), languid",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弛み",
        "pronunciation": "たるみ",
        "back": "slack, slackening",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弛む",
        "pronunciation": "たるむ",
        "back": "to slacken, to loosen, to relax",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "垂れる",
        "pronunciation": "たれる",
        "back": "to hang, to droop; to drip",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "タレント",
        "pronunciation": "タレント",
        "back": "talent, star, personality",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "タワー",
        "pronunciation": "タワー",
        "back": "tower",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "単一",
        "pronunciation": "たんいつ",
        "back": "single, simple, sole",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "短歌",
        "pronunciation": "たんか",
        "back": "31-syllable Japanese poem",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "担架",
        "pronunciation": "たんか",
        "back": "stretcher, litter",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "短気",
        "pronunciation": "たんき",
        "back": "quick temper",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "団結",
        "pronunciation": "だんけつ",
        "back": "unity, union, solidarity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "探検",
        "pronunciation": "たんけん",
        "back": "exploration, expedition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "断言",
        "pronunciation": "だんげん",
        "back": "assertion, declaration, affirmation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "短縮",
        "pronunciation": "たんしゅく",
        "back": "shortening, abbreviation, reduction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "断然",
        "pronunciation": "だんぜん",
        "back": "firmly, absolutely, definitely",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "炭素",
        "pronunciation": "たんそ",
        "back": "carbon (C)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "短大",
        "pronunciation": "たんだい",
        "back": "junior college",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "単調",
        "pronunciation": "たんちょう",
        "back": "monotony, monotone, dullness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "単独",
        "pronunciation": "たんどく",
        "back": "sole, single",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "旦那",
        "pronunciation": "だんな",
        "back": "master (of house), husband (informal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "短波",
        "pronunciation": "たんぱ",
        "back": "short wave",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "蛋白質",
        "pronunciation": "たんぱくしつ",
        "back": "protein",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ダンプ",
        "pronunciation": "ダンプ",
        "back": "dump truck",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "断面",
        "pronunciation": "だんめん",
        "back": "cross section",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弾力",
        "pronunciation": "だんりょく",
        "back": "elasticity, flexibility",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "治安",
        "pronunciation": "ちあん",
        "back": "public order, security",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "チームワーク",
        "pronunciation": "チームワーク",
        "back": "teamwork",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "チェンジ",
        "pronunciation": "チェンジ",
        "back": "change",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "違える",
        "pronunciation": "ちがえる",
        "back": "to change",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "畜産",
        "pronunciation": "ちくさん",
        "back": "animal husbandry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "畜生",
        "pronunciation": "ちくしょう",
        "back": "beast, brute, damn",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "蓄積",
        "pronunciation": "ちくせき",
        "back": "accumulation, accumulate, store",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "地形",
        "pronunciation": "ちけい",
        "back": "landform, geographical features, topography",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "知性",
        "pronunciation": "ちせい",
        "back": "intelligence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "乳",
        "pronunciation": "ちち",
        "back": "milk, breast, loop",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "縮まる",
        "pronunciation": "ちぢまる",
        "back": "to be shortened, to be contracted, to shrink",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "秩序",
        "pronunciation": "ちつじょ",
        "back": "order, regularity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "窒息",
        "pronunciation": "ちっそく",
        "back": "suffocation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "知的",
        "pronunciation": "ちてき",
        "back": "intellectual",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "着手",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃくしゅ",
        "back": "embarkation, launch",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "着色",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃくしょく",
        "back": "coloring, coloring",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "着席",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃくせき",
        "back": "sit down, seat",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "着目",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃくもく",
        "back": "attention",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "着陸",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃくりく",
        "back": "landing, touch down",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "着工",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃっこう",
        "back": "start of (construction) work",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "茶の間",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃのま",
        "back": "living room (Japanese style)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "茶の湯",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃのゆ",
        "back": "tea ceremony",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちやほや",
        "pronunciation": "ちやほや",
        "back": "pamper, make a fuss of, spoil",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "チャンネル",
        "pronunciation": "チャンネル",
        "back": "a channel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "宙返り",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうがえり",
        "back": "somersault, looping-the-loop",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "中継",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうけい",
        "back": "relay, hook-up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "忠告",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうこく",
        "back": "advice, warning",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "中傷",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうしょう",
        "back": "slander, libel, defamation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "中枢",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうすう",
        "back": "center, mainstay, nucleus",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "抽選",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうせん",
        "back": "lottery, raffle, drawing (of lots)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "中断",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうだん",
        "back": "interruption, suspension, break",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "中毒",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうどく",
        "back": "poisoning",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "中腹",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうふく",
        "back": "mountain side, halfway up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "中立",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうりつ",
        "back": "neutrality",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "中和",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうわ",
        "back": "neutralize, counteract",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～著",
        "pronunciation": "～ちょ",
        "back": "written by ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "腸",
        "pronunciation": "ちょう",
        "back": "bowels, intestines",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "蝶",
        "pronunciation": "ちょう",
        "back": "butterfly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "超",
        "pronunciation": "ちょう",
        "back": "super-, ultra-, hyper-",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "調印",
        "pronunciation": "ちょういん",
        "back": "signature, sign, sealing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "聴覚",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうかく",
        "back": "the sense of hearing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "長官",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうかん",
        "back": "chief, (government) secretary",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "聴講",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうこう",
        "back": "lecture attendance, auditing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "徴収",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうしゅう",
        "back": "collection, levy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "聴診器",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうしんき",
        "back": "stethoscope",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "調停",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうてい",
        "back": "arbitration, conciliation, mediation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "重複",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうふく",
        "back": "duplication, repetition, overlapping, redundancy, restoration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "長編",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうへん",
        "back": "long (e.g., novel, film)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "重宝",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうほう",
        "back": "convenient, useful",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "調理",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうり",
        "back": "cooking",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "調和",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうわ",
        "back": "harmony",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちょくちょく",
        "pronunciation": "ちょくちょく",
        "back": "often, frequently, now and then, occasionally",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "直面",
        "pronunciation": "ちょくめん",
        "back": "confrontation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "著書",
        "pronunciation": "ちょしょ",
        "back": "literary work, book",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "貯蓄",
        "pronunciation": "ちょちく",
        "back": "savings",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "直感",
        "pronunciation": "ちょっかん",
        "back": "intuition, instinct",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "著名",
        "pronunciation": "ちょめい",
        "back": "well-known, noted, celebrated",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちらっと",
        "pronunciation": "ちらっと",
        "back": "at a glance, by accident",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "塵",
        "pronunciation": "ちり",
        "back": "dust, dirt",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "塵取り",
        "pronunciation": "ちりとり",
        "back": "dustpan",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "賃金",
        "pronunciation": "ちんぎん",
        "back": "wages",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "沈殿",
        "pronunciation": "ちんでん",
        "back": "precipitation, deposition, settlement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "沈没",
        "pronunciation": "ちんぼつ",
        "back": "sinking, foundering",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "沈黙",
        "pronunciation": "ちんもく",
        "back": "silence, reticence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "陳列",
        "pronunciation": "ちんれつ",
        "back": "exhibition, display, show",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "追及",
        "pronunciation": "ついきゅう",
        "back": "investigation, inquiry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "追跡",
        "pronunciation": "ついせき",
        "back": "pursuit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "追放",
        "pronunciation": "ついほう",
        "back": "exile, banishment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "費やす",
        "pronunciation": "ついやす",
        "back": "to spend, to devote, to waste",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "墜落",
        "pronunciation": "ついらく",
        "back": "falling, crashing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "痛感",
        "pronunciation": "つうかん",
        "back": "feeling keenly, fully realizing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "通常",
        "pronunciation": "つうじょう",
        "back": "common, normal, usual",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "痛切",
        "pronunciation": "つうせつ",
        "back": "keen, deep",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "杖",
        "pronunciation": "つえ",
        "back": "cane",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "使い道",
        "pronunciation": "つかいみち",
        "back": "use",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕える",
        "pronunciation": "つかえる",
        "back": "to serve, to work for",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "司る",
        "pronunciation": "つかさどる",
        "back": "to rule, to govern, to administer",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "つかの間",
        "pronunciation": "つかのま",
        "back": "moment, brief time,",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "月並",
        "pronunciation": "つきなみ",
        "back": "conventional, trite, common",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "継目",
        "pronunciation": "つぎめ",
        "back": "joint, seam",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "尽きる",
        "pronunciation": "つきる",
        "back": "to be used up, to be run out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "尽くす",
        "pronunciation": "つくす",
        "back": "to exhaust, to run out; to devote, to serve",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "つくづく",
        "pronunciation": "つくづく",
        "back": "completely, really",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "作り",
        "pronunciation": "つくり",
        "back": "make up, structure, physique",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "造り",
        "pronunciation": "つくり",
        "back": "make up, structure, physique",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "繕う",
        "pronunciation": "つくろう",
        "back": "to mend, to repair",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "付け加える",
        "pronunciation": "つけくわえる",
        "back": "to add one thing to another",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "告げる",
        "pronunciation": "つげる",
        "back": "to inform",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "つじつま (はなしの～)",
        "pronunciation": "つじつま (はなしの～)",
        "back": "coherence, consistency",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "筒",
        "pronunciation": "つつ",
        "back": "pipe, tube",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "突く",
        "pronunciation": "つつく",
        "back": "to thrust, to strike, to attack; to poke, to nudge, to pick at",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "突っ突く",
        "pronunciation": "つっつく",
        "back": "to prompt someone",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "謹む",
        "pronunciation": "つつしむ",
        "back": "to be careful, to be chaste or discreet",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "突っ張る",
        "pronunciation": "つっぱる",
        "back": "to support, to become stiff; to thrust (ones opponent), to stick to (ones opinion), to insist on",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "務まる",
        "pronunciation": "つとまる",
        "back": "be equal, be fit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勤め先",
        "pronunciation": "つとめさき",
        "back": "place of work",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "努めて",
        "pronunciation": "つとめて",
        "back": "make an effort!, work hard!",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "津波",
        "pronunciation": "つなみ",
        "back": "tsunami, tidal wave",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "つねる",
        "pronunciation": "つねる",
        "back": "to pinch",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "角",
        "pronunciation": "つの",
        "back": "horn",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "募る",
        "pronunciation": "つのる",
        "back": "to invite, to solicit help, participation, etc",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "唾",
        "pronunciation": "つば",
        "back": "saliva, spit, sputum",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "呟く",
        "pronunciation": "つぶやく",
        "back": "to mutter, to murmur",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "つぶら",
        "pronunciation": "つぶら",
        "back": "round, rotund",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "つぶる (めを～)",
        "pronunciation": "つぶる (めを～)",
        "back": "to close the eyes",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "壷",
        "pronunciation": "つぼ",
        "back": "jar, pot, vase",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "蕾",
        "pronunciation": "つぼみ",
        "back": "bud, flower bud",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "連なる",
        "pronunciation": "つらなる",
        "back": "to extend, to stretch out, to stand in a row",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "貫く",
        "pronunciation": "つらぬく",
        "back": "to go through",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "連ねる",
        "pronunciation": "つらねる",
        "back": "to link, to join, to put together",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "釣り鐘",
        "pronunciation": "つりがね",
        "back": "temple bell (for striking)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "吊り革",
        "pronunciation": "つりかわ",
        "back": "strap",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手当",
        "pronunciation": "てあて",
        "back": "allowance, compensation; treatment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "定義",
        "pronunciation": "ていぎ",
        "back": "definition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "提供",
        "pronunciation": "ていきょう",
        "back": "offer, program sponsoring",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "提携",
        "pronunciation": "ていけい",
        "back": "cooperation, tie-up, joint business",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "体裁",
        "pronunciation": "ていさい",
        "back": "decency, style, form, appearance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "提示",
        "pronunciation": "ていじ",
        "back": "presentation, exhibit, suggest, citation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ティシュペーパー",
        "pronunciation": "ティシュペーパー",
        "back": "tissue",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "定食",
        "pronunciation": "ていしょく",
        "back": "fixed-price lunch, set meal, dinner",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "訂正",
        "pronunciation": "ていせい",
        "back": "correction, revision",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "停滞",
        "pronunciation": "ていたい",
        "back": "stagnation, tie-up, congestion, retention",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "邸宅",
        "pronunciation": "ていたく",
        "back": "mansion, residence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "定年",
        "pronunciation": "ていねん",
        "back": "retirement age",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "堤防",
        "pronunciation": "ていぼう",
        "back": "bank, weir",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手遅れ",
        "pronunciation": "ておくれ",
        "back": "being (too); belated treatment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "でかい",
        "pronunciation": "でかい",
        "back": "huge",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手掛かり",
        "pronunciation": "てがかり",
        "back": "hint, clue, key",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手掛ける",
        "pronunciation": "てがける",
        "back": "to handle, to manage, to work with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手数",
        "pronunciation": "てかず",
        "back": "trouble, labor, handling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手軽",
        "pronunciation": "てがる",
        "back": "easy, simple, cheap",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "適応",
        "pronunciation": "てきおう",
        "back": "adaptation, accommodation, conformity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "適宜",
        "pronunciation": "てきぎ",
        "back": "suitability",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "適性",
        "pronunciation": "てきせい",
        "back": "aptitude",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "できもの",
        "pronunciation": "できもの",
        "back": "boil, rash",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手際",
        "pronunciation": "てぎわ",
        "back": "performance, skill, tact",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出くわす",
        "pronunciation": "でくわす",
        "back": "to happen to meet, to come across",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手順",
        "pronunciation": "てじゅん",
        "back": "process, procedure, protocol",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手錠",
        "pronunciation": "てじょう",
        "back": "handcuffs, manacles",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手数",
        "pronunciation": "てすう",
        "back": "trouble, labor, handling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "デコレーション",
        "pronunciation": "デコレーション",
        "back": "decoration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手近",
        "pronunciation": "てぢか",
        "back": "near, handy, familiar",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "てっきり",
        "pronunciation": "てっきり",
        "back": "surely, certainly, beyond doubt",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉄鋼",
        "pronunciation": "てっこう",
        "back": "iron and steel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "デッサン",
        "pronunciation": "デッサン",
        "back": "rough sketch (FRE: dessin)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "徹する",
        "pronunciation": "てっする",
        "back": "to devote oneself, to believe in",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "てっぺん",
        "pronunciation": "てっぺん",
        "back": "top, summit, apex",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉄棒",
        "pronunciation": "てつぼう",
        "back": "iron rod, crowbar, horizontal bar (gymnastics)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出直し",
        "pronunciation": "でなおし",
        "back": "adjustment, touch up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "掌",
        "pronunciation": "てのひら",
        "back": "the palm",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手配",
        "pronunciation": "てはい",
        "back": "arrangement, search (by police)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手筈",
        "pronunciation": "てはず",
        "back": "arrangement, plan, program",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手引",
        "pronunciation": "てびき",
        "back": "guidance, guide, introduction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手本",
        "pronunciation": "てほん",
        "back": "model, pattern",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手回し",
        "pronunciation": "てまわし",
        "back": "preparations, arrangements",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手元",
        "pronunciation": "てもと",
        "back": "(money) on hand or at home, one's purse; usual skill",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "デモンストレーション",
        "pronunciation": "デモンストレーション",
        "back": "demonstration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "照り返す",
        "pronunciation": "てりかえす",
        "back": "to reflect, to throw back light",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "テレックス",
        "pronunciation": "テレックス",
        "back": "telex, teletypewriter exchange",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手分け",
        "pronunciation": "てわけ",
        "back": "division of labor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "天",
        "pronunciation": "てん",
        "back": "heaven, sky",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "田園",
        "pronunciation": "でんえん",
        "back": "country, rural districts",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "天下",
        "pronunciation": "てんか",
        "back": "the world, whole country",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "転回",
        "pronunciation": "てんかい",
        "back": "revolution, rotation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "連休",
        "pronunciation": "れんきゅう",
        "back": "consecutive holidays",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "レンジ",
        "pronunciation": "レンジ",
        "back": "range, stove",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "連日",
        "pronunciation": "れんじつ",
        "back": "every day",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "連帯",
        "pronunciation": "れんたい",
        "back": "solidarity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "レンタカー",
        "pronunciation": "レンタカー",
        "back": "rented car",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "連中",
        "pronunciation": "れんちゅう",
        "back": "colleagues, company, a lot",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "レントゲン",
        "pronunciation": "レントゲン",
        "back": "X-ray (lit: Roentgen)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "連邦",
        "pronunciation": "れんぽう",
        "back": "commonwealth, federation of states",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "連盟",
        "pronunciation": "れんめい",
        "back": "league, union, alliance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "老衰",
        "pronunciation": "ろうすい",
        "back": "senility, senile decay",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "朗読",
        "pronunciation": "ろうどく",
        "back": "reading aloud, recitation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "浪費",
        "pronunciation": "ろうひ",
        "back": "waste, extravagance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "労力",
        "pronunciation": "ろうりょく",
        "back": "labor, effort, trouble",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ロープウエイ",
        "pronunciation": "ロープウエイ",
        "back": "ropeway, aerial tram",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ロープ",
        "pronunciation": "ロープ",
        "back": "rope",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ろくな",
        "pronunciation": "ろくな",
        "back": "satisfactory, decent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "露骨",
        "pronunciation": "ろこつ",
        "back": "blunt, outspoken; conspicuous; broad, suggestive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ロマンチック",
        "pronunciation": "ロマンチック",
        "back": "romantic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "論議",
        "pronunciation": "ろんぎ",
        "back": "discussion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "論理",
        "pronunciation": "ろんり",
        "back": "logic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "惑星",
        "pronunciation": "わくせい",
        "back": "planet",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "技",
        "pronunciation": "わざ",
        "back": "art, technique",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "わざわざ",
        "pronunciation": "わざわざ",
        "back": "take the trouble (to do), doing something especially rather than incidentally",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "煩わしい",
        "pronunciation": "わずらわしい",
        "back": "burdensome, troublesome, complicated",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "渡り鳥",
        "pronunciation": "わたりどり",
        "back": "migratory bird, bird of passage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ワット",
        "pronunciation": "ワット",
        "back": "watt",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "詫び",
        "pronunciation": "わび",
        "back": "apology",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "和文",
        "pronunciation": "わぶん",
        "back": "Japanese text, sentence in Japanese",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "藁",
        "pronunciation": "わら",
        "back": "straw",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～割",
        "pronunciation": "～わり",
        "back": "~ percent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "割当",
        "pronunciation": "わりあて",
        "back": "allotment, allocation, quota",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "割込む",
        "pronunciation": "わりこむ",
        "back": "to cut in, to disturb",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "悪者",
        "pronunciation": "わるもの",
        "back": "bad fellow, rascal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "我",
        "pronunciation": "われ",
        "back": "me, oneself, self, ego",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "捗る",
        "pronunciation": "はかどる",
        "back": "to make progress, to move right ahead (with the work), to advance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "はかない",
        "pronunciation": "はかない",
        "back": "short-lived, momentary, ephemeral",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ばかばかしい",
        "pronunciation": "ばかばかしい",
        "back": "stupid",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "破棄",
        "pronunciation": "はき",
        "back": "revocation, annulment, breaking (e.g., treaty)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "剥ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "はぐ",
        "back": "to tear off, to peel off, to rip off",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "迫害",
        "pronunciation": "はくがい",
        "back": "persecution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "薄弱",
        "pronunciation": "はくじゃく",
        "back": "feebleness, weakness, weak",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "白状",
        "pronunciation": "はくじょう",
        "back": "confession",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "漠然",
        "pronunciation": "ばくぜん",
        "back": "obscure, vague, equivocal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "爆弾",
        "pronunciation": "ばくだん",
        "back": "bomb",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "爆破",
        "pronunciation": "ばくは",
        "back": "blast, explosion, blow up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "暴露",
        "pronunciation": "ばくろ",
        "back": "disclosure, exposure, revelation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "励ます",
        "pronunciation": "はげます",
        "back": "to encourage, to cheer, to raise (the voice)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "励む",
        "pronunciation": "はげむ",
        "back": "to be zealous, to make an effort",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "剥げる",
        "pronunciation": "はげる",
        "back": "to come off, to be worn off, to fade, to discolor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "化ける",
        "pronunciation": "ばける",
        "back": "to disguise, to take the form of",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "派遣",
        "pronunciation": "はけん",
        "back": "dispatch, send",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "恥",
        "pronunciation": "はじ",
        "back": "shame, embarrassment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弾く",
        "pronunciation": "はじく",
        "back": "to play (piano, guitar)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "パジャマ",
        "pronunciation": "パジャマ",
        "back": "pajamas",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "恥じらう",
        "pronunciation": "はじらう",
        "back": "to feel shy, to be bashful, to blush",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "恥じる",
        "pronunciation": "はじる",
        "back": "to feel ashamed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "橋渡し",
        "pronunciation": "はしわたし",
        "back": "bridge building', mediation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弾む",
        "pronunciation": "はずむ",
        "back": "to bounce, to be encouraged, to splurge on",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "破損",
        "pronunciation": "はそん",
        "back": "damage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "叩く",
        "pronunciation": "はたく",
        "back": "to strike, to clap, to dust, to beat",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "裸足",
        "pronunciation": "はだし",
        "back": "barefoot",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "果たす",
        "pronunciation": "はたす",
        "back": "to accomplish, to fulfill, to carry out, to achieve",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "蜂蜜",
        "pronunciation": "はちみつ",
        "back": "honey",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "パチンコ",
        "pronunciation": "パチンコ",
        "back": "pachinko (Japanese pinball)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "罰",
        "pronunciation": "ばつ",
        "back": "punishment, penalty",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "発育",
        "pronunciation": "はついく",
        "back": "(physical) growth, development",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "発芽",
        "pronunciation": "はつが",
        "back": "germination",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "発掘",
        "pronunciation": "はっくつ",
        "back": "excavation, exhumation; discovery (e.g., new talent)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "発言",
        "pronunciation": "はつげん",
        "back": "utterance, speech, proposal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "バッジ",
        "pronunciation": "バッジ",
        "back": "badge",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "発生",
        "pronunciation": "はっせい",
        "back": "outbreak, spring forth, occurrence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕立てる",
        "pronunciation": "したてる",
        "back": "to tailor, to make, to prepare",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "下取り",
        "pronunciation": "したどり",
        "back": "trade in, part exchange",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "下火",
        "pronunciation": "したび",
        "back": "burning low, waning, declining",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "実",
        "pronunciation": "じつ",
        "back": "fruit, good result",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "実家",
        "pronunciation": "じっか",
        "back": "(one's parents') home",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "失格",
        "pronunciation": "しっかく",
        "back": "disqualification, elimination, incapacity (legal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "質疑",
        "pronunciation": "しつぎ",
        "back": "question",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "失脚",
        "pronunciation": "しっきゃく",
        "back": "losing one's standing, being overthrown, falling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "実業家",
        "pronunciation": "じつぎょうか",
        "back": "industrialist, businessman",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "シック",
        "pronunciation": "シック",
        "back": "chic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "じっくり",
        "pronunciation": "じっくり",
        "back": "deliberately, carefully",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "躾",
        "pronunciation": "しつけ",
        "back": "discipline, training",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "躾ける",
        "pronunciation": "しつける",
        "back": "to discipline, to teach manners",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "実践",
        "pronunciation": "じっせん",
        "back": "practice, put into practice",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "質素",
        "pronunciation": "しっそ",
        "back": "simplicity, modesty, frugality",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "実態",
        "pronunciation": "じったい",
        "back": "truth, fact",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "失調",
        "pronunciation": "しっちょう",
        "back": "lack of harmony, imbalance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "嫉妬",
        "pronunciation": "しっと",
        "back": "jealousy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "実費",
        "pronunciation": "じっぴ",
        "back": "actual expense, cost price",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "指摘",
        "pronunciation": "してき",
        "back": "pointing out, identification",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "自転",
        "pronunciation": "じてん",
        "back": "rotation, spin",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "助動詞",
        "pronunciation": "じょどうし",
        "back": "auxiliary verb",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "淑やか",
        "pronunciation": "しとやか",
        "back": "graceful",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "萎びる",
        "pronunciation": "しなびる",
        "back": "to shrivel, to fade",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "シナリオ",
        "pronunciation": "シナリオ",
        "back": "scenario",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "しなやか",
        "pronunciation": "しなやか",
        "back": "supple, flexible, elastic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "屎尿",
        "pronunciation": "しにょう",
        "back": "human waste",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "地主",
        "pronunciation": "じぬし",
        "back": "landlord",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "凌ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "しのぐ",
        "back": "to outdo, to surpass; to endure",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "芝",
        "pronunciation": "しば",
        "back": "lawn",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "始発",
        "pronunciation": "しはつ",
        "back": "first train",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "耳鼻科",
        "pronunciation": "じびか",
        "back": "otolaryngology",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "私物",
        "pronunciation": "しぶつ",
        "back": "private property, personal effects",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "しぶとい",
        "pronunciation": "しぶとい",
        "back": "tenacious, stubborn",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "司法",
        "pronunciation": "しほう",
        "back": "administration of justice",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "始末",
        "pronunciation": "しまつ",
        "back": "disposal; cleaning up afterwards",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "染みる",
        "pronunciation": "しみる",
        "back": "to soak; pierce",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "使命",
        "pronunciation": "しめい",
        "back": "mission, errand, message",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "地元",
        "pronunciation": "じもと",
        "back": "local",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "視野",
        "pronunciation": "しや",
        "back": "field of vision, outlook",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弱",
        "pronunciation": "じゃく",
        "back": "delicate, supple",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "社交",
        "pronunciation": "しゃこう",
        "back": "social life",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジャズ",
        "pronunciation": "ジャズ",
        "back": "jazz",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "謝絶",
        "pronunciation": "しゃぜつ",
        "back": "refusal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "社宅",
        "pronunciation": "しゃたく",
        "back": "company owned house",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "若干",
        "pronunciation": "じゃっかん",
        "back": "some, few, number of",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "三味線",
        "pronunciation": "しゃみせん",
        "back": "three-stringed Japanese guitar",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "斜面",
        "pronunciation": "しゃめん",
        "back": "slope, slanting surface, bevel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "砂利",
        "pronunciation": "じゃり",
        "back": "gravel, ballast, pebbles",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "洒落る",
        "pronunciation": "しゃれる",
        "back": "to joke, to play on words; stylish",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジャンパー",
        "pronunciation": "ジャンパー",
        "back": "jacket, jumper",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジャンプ",
        "pronunciation": "ジャンプ",
        "back": "jump",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジャンボ",
        "pronunciation": "ジャンボ",
        "back": "jumbo",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジャンル",
        "pronunciation": "ジャンル",
        "back": "genre",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主",
        "pronunciation": "しゅ",
        "back": "owner, master, god",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "種",
        "pronunciation": "しゅ",
        "back": "seed; variety",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "私有",
        "pronunciation": "しゆう",
        "back": "private ownership",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～宗",
        "pronunciation": "～しゅう",
        "back": "sect",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "収益",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうえき",
        "back": "earnings, proceeds, returns",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "修学",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうがく",
        "back": "learning",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "周期",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうき",
        "back": "cycle, period",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "衆議院",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうぎいん",
        "back": "Lower House, House of Representatives",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "就業",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうぎょう",
        "back": "employment, starting work",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "従業員",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうぎょういん",
        "back": "employee, worker",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "集計",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうけい",
        "back": "totalization, aggregate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "襲撃",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうげき",
        "back": "attack, charge, raid",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "収支",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうし",
        "back": "income and expenditure",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "終始",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうし",
        "back": "from beginning to end; consistent(ly)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "修士",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうし",
        "back": "Masters degree program",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "従事",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうじ",
        "back": "engaging, pursuing, following",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "終日",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうじつ",
        "back": "all day",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "充実",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうじつ",
        "back": "fullness, perfection",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "収集",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうしゅう",
        "back": "gathering up, collection",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "十字路",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうじろ",
        "back": "crossroads",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "執着",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうじゃく",
        "back": "attachment, adhesion, tenacity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "執着",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうちゃく",
        "back": "attachment, adhesion, tenacity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "柔軟",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうなん",
        "back": "flexible",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "重複",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうふく",
        "back": "duplication, repetition, overlapping",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "収容",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうよう",
        "back": "accommodation; seating; custody",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "従来",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうらい",
        "back": "up to now, so far, traditional",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "守衛",
        "pronunciation": "しゅえい",
        "back": "security guard, doorkeeper",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主演",
        "pronunciation": "しゅえん",
        "back": "starring, playing the leading part",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主観",
        "pronunciation": "しゅかん",
        "back": "subjectivity, subject, ego",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "修行",
        "pronunciation": "しゅぎょう",
        "back": "pursuit of knowledge, training, ascetic practice",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "塾",
        "pronunciation": "じゅく",
        "back": "after-school (cram) school",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "祝賀",
        "pronunciation": "しゅくが",
        "back": "celebration, congratulations",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "宿命",
        "pronunciation": "しゅくめい",
        "back": "fate, destiny, predestination",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "手芸",
        "pronunciation": "しゅげい",
        "back": "handicrafts",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主権",
        "pronunciation": "しゅけん",
        "back": "sovereignty",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主催",
        "pronunciation": "しゅさい",
        "back": "organization, sponsorship, to host",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "取材",
        "pronunciation": "しゅざい",
        "back": "coverage, collecting data",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "趣旨",
        "pronunciation": "しゅし",
        "back": "object, meaning",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "種々",
        "pronunciation": "しゅじゅ",
        "back": "variety",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主食",
        "pronunciation": "しゅしょく",
        "back": "staple food",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主人公",
        "pronunciation": "しゅじんこう",
        "back": "protagonist",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主体",
        "pronunciation": "しゅたい",
        "back": "subject, main constituent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "主題",
        "pronunciation": "しゅだい",
        "back": "subject, theme, motif",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出演",
        "pronunciation": "しゅつえん",
        "back": "leading performer, stage appearance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出血",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっけつ",
        "back": "bleeding",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出現",
        "pronunciation": "しゅつげん",
        "back": "appearance, arrival",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出産",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっさん",
        "back": "childbirth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出社",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっしゃ",
        "back": "come to work",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出生",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっしょう",
        "back": "birth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "出生",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっせい",
        "back": "birth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "微量",
        "pronunciation": "びりょう",
        "back": "minuscule amount, extremely small quantity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "昼飯",
        "pronunciation": "ひるめし",
        "back": "lunch (mid-day meal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "比例",
        "pronunciation": "ひれい",
        "back": "proportion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "疲労",
        "pronunciation": "ひろう",
        "back": "fatigue, weariness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "敏感",
        "pronunciation": "びんかん",
        "back": "sensibility, susceptibility, sensitive (to)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "貧困",
        "pronunciation": "ひんこん",
        "back": "poverty, lack",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "品質",
        "pronunciation": "ひんしつ",
        "back": "quality",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "貧弱",
        "pronunciation": "ひんじゃく",
        "back": "poor, meager, insubstantial",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "品種",
        "pronunciation": "ひんしゅ",
        "back": "breed, type, variety",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ヒント",
        "pronunciation": "ヒント",
        "back": "hint",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "頻繁",
        "pronunciation": "ひんぱん",
        "back": "frequency",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "貧乏",
        "pronunciation": "びんぼう",
        "back": "poverty, destitute, poor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ファイト",
        "pronunciation": "ファイト",
        "back": "fight",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ファイル",
        "pronunciation": "ファイル",
        "back": "file; portfolio",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ファン",
        "pronunciation": "ファン",
        "back": "fan",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不意",
        "pronunciation": "ふい",
        "back": "sudden, abrupt, unexpected",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "フィルタ",
        "pronunciation": "フィルタ",
        "back": "filter",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "封",
        "pronunciation": "ふう",
        "back": "seal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "封鎖",
        "pronunciation": "ふうさ",
        "back": "blockade, freezing (funds)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "風車",
        "pronunciation": "ふうしゃ",
        "back": "windmill",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "風習",
        "pronunciation": "ふうしゅう",
        "back": "custom",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "風俗",
        "pronunciation": "ふうぞく",
        "back": "manners, customs; sex industry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ブーツ",
        "pronunciation": "ブーツ",
        "back": "boots",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "風土",
        "pronunciation": "ふうど",
        "back": "natural features, climate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ブーム",
        "pronunciation": "ブーム",
        "back": "boom",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "フォーム",
        "pronunciation": "フォーム",
        "back": "foam; form",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "部下",
        "pronunciation": "ぶか",
        "back": "one's subordinate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不可欠",
        "pronunciation": "ふかけつ",
        "back": "indispensable, essential",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぶかぶか",
        "pronunciation": "ぶかぶか",
        "back": "too big, baggy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不吉",
        "pronunciation": "ふきつ",
        "back": "ominous, sinister, bad luck, ill omen",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不況",
        "pronunciation": "ふきょう",
        "back": "recession, depression, slump",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "布巾",
        "pronunciation": "ふきん",
        "back": "dish cloth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "複合",
        "pronunciation": "ふくごう",
        "back": "composite, complex",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "福祉",
        "pronunciation": "ふくし",
        "back": "welfare, well-being",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "覆面",
        "pronunciation": "ふくめん",
        "back": "mask, veil, disguise",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "膨れる",
        "pronunciation": "ふくれる",
        "back": "to swell (out), to be inflated, to bulge",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不景気",
        "pronunciation": "ふけいき",
        "back": "business recession, hard times, depression",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "耽る",
        "pronunciation": "ふける",
        "back": "to indulge in, to give oneself up to, to be absorbed in",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "老ける",
        "pronunciation": "ふける",
        "back": "to age",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "富豪",
        "pronunciation": "ふごう",
        "back": "wealthy person, millionaire",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "布告",
        "pronunciation": "ふこく",
        "back": "edict, ordinance, proclamation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ブザー",
        "pronunciation": "ブザー",
        "back": "buzzer",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "負債",
        "pronunciation": "ふさい",
        "back": "debt, liabilities",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不在",
        "pronunciation": "ふざい",
        "back": "absence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ふさわしい",
        "pronunciation": "ふさわしい",
        "back": "appropriate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不順",
        "pronunciation": "ふじゅん",
        "back": "irregularity, unseasonableness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "負傷",
        "pronunciation": "ふしょう",
        "back": "injury, wound",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "侮辱",
        "pronunciation": "ぶじょく",
        "back": "insult, contempt, slight",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不審",
        "pronunciation": "ふしん",
        "back": "suspicious, doubt, infidelity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不振",
        "pronunciation": "ふしん",
        "back": "dullness, slump, stagnation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "武装",
        "pronunciation": "ぶそう",
        "back": "arms, armament, armed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "札",
        "pronunciation": "ふだ",
        "back": "token, label; ticket, card; charm, talisman",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "負担",
        "pronunciation": "ふたん",
        "back": "burden; load",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不調",
        "pronunciation": "ふちょう",
        "back": "bad condition, disorder, slump",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "復活",
        "pronunciation": "ふっかつ",
        "back": "revival (e.g., musical), restoration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "物議",
        "pronunciation": "ぶつぎ",
        "back": "public discussion (criticism)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "復旧",
        "pronunciation": "ふっきゅう",
        "back": "restoration, restitution, rehabilitation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "復興",
        "pronunciation": "ふっこう",
        "back": "revival, renaissance, reconstruction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "物資",
        "pronunciation": "ぶっし",
        "back": "goods, materials",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "仏像",
        "pronunciation": "ぶつぞう",
        "back": "Buddhist image (statue)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "物体",
        "pronunciation": "ぶったい",
        "back": "object",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "沸騰",
        "pronunciation": "ふっとう",
        "back": "boiling, seething",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不当",
        "pronunciation": "ふとう",
        "back": "injustice, impropriety, unfair",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不動産",
        "pronunciation": "ふどうさん",
        "back": "real estate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無難",
        "pronunciation": "ぶなん",
        "back": "safety, security",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "赴任",
        "pronunciation": "ふにん",
        "back": "(proceeding to) new appointment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "腐敗",
        "pronunciation": "ふはい",
        "back": "decay, depravity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不評",
        "pronunciation": "ふひょう",
        "back": "bad reputation, disgrace, unpopularity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不服",
        "pronunciation": "ふふく",
        "back": "dissatisfaction, discontent, disapproval",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "普遍",
        "pronunciation": "ふへん",
        "back": "universality, ubiquity, omnipresence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "踏まえる",
        "pronunciation": "ふまえる",
        "back": "to be based on, to have origin in",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "踏み込む",
        "pronunciation": "ふみこむ",
        "back": "to step into (someone else's territory, to break into, to raid",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不明",
        "pronunciation": "ふめい",
        "back": "unknown, ambiguous",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "部門",
        "pronunciation": "ぶもん",
        "back": "class, group, category, department, field, branch",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "扶養",
        "pronunciation": "ふよう",
        "back": "support, maintenance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ふらふら",
        "pronunciation": "ふらふら",
        "back": "unsteady on one's feet, totter, dizzy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぶらぶら",
        "pronunciation": "ぶらぶら",
        "back": "dangle heavily, sway to and fro, stroll idly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "振り返る",
        "pronunciation": "ふりかえる",
        "back": "to turn head, to turn around, to look back",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "振り出し",
        "pronunciation": "ふりだし",
        "back": "outset, starting point, drawing or issuing (draft)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "不良",
        "pronunciation": "ふりょう",
        "back": "badness, delinquent, failure",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "浮力",
        "pronunciation": "ふりょく",
        "back": "buoyancy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "武力",
        "pronunciation": "ぶりょく",
        "back": "armed might, military power, the sword, force",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ブル",
        "pronunciation": "ブル",
        "back": "bull",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "震わせる",
        "pronunciation": "ふるわせる",
        "back": "to be shaking, to be trembling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無礼",
        "pronunciation": "ぶれい",
        "back": "impolite, rude",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "付録",
        "pronunciation": "ふろく",
        "back": "appendix, supplement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "フロント",
        "pronunciation": "フロント",
        "back": "front",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "憤慨",
        "pronunciation": "ふんがい",
        "back": "indignation, resentment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "文化財",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんかざい",
        "back": "cultural assets, cultural property",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "分業",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんぎょう",
        "back": "division of labor, specialization, assembly-line production",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "文語",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんご",
        "back": "written language, literary language",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "分散",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんさん",
        "back": "dispersion, decentralization, variance (statistics)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "分子",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんし",
        "back": "numerator, molecule",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "紛失",
        "pronunciation": "ふんしつ",
        "back": "losing something",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "噴出",
        "pronunciation": "ふんしゅつ",
        "back": "spewing, gushing, spouting",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "文書",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんしょ",
        "back": "document, writing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "紛争",
        "pronunciation": "ふんそう",
        "back": "dispute, trouble, strife",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ふんだん",
        "pronunciation": "ふんだん",
        "back": "plentiful, abundant, lavish",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "分担",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんたん",
        "back": "apportionment, sharing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "奮闘",
        "pronunciation": "ふんとう",
        "back": "hard struggle, strenuous effort",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "分配",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんぱい",
        "back": "division, sharing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "分母",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんぼ",
        "back": "denominator",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "粉末",
        "pronunciation": "ふんまつ",
        "back": "fine powder",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "分離",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんり",
        "back": "separation, detachment, segregation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "分裂",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんれつ",
        "back": "split, division, break up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ペア",
        "pronunciation": "ペア",
        "back": "pair, pear",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "兵器",
        "pronunciation": "へいき",
        "back": "arms, weapons, ordinance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "閉口",
        "pronunciation": "へいこう",
        "back": "shut mouth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "閉鎖",
        "pronunciation": "へいさ",
        "back": "closing, closure, shutdown",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "兵士",
        "pronunciation": "へいし",
        "back": "soldier",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "平常",
        "pronunciation": "へいじょう",
        "back": "normal, usual",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "平方",
        "pronunciation": "へいほう",
        "back": "square (e.g., meter, square)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "並列",
        "pronunciation": "へいれつ",
        "back": "arrangement, parallel, abreast",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ベース",
        "pronunciation": "ベース",
        "back": "base, bass",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "辟易",
        "pronunciation": "へきえき",
        "back": "wince, shrink back, succumbing to, being frightened",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぺこぺこ",
        "pronunciation": "ぺこぺこ",
        "back": "fawn, be very hungry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ベスト",
        "pronunciation": "ベスト",
        "back": "best; vest",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ベストセラー",
        "pronunciation": "ベストセラー",
        "back": "best-seller",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "隔たる",
        "pronunciation": "へだたる",
        "back": "to be distant",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "縁",
        "pronunciation": "へり",
        "back": "edge",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "へりくだる",
        "pronunciation": "へりくだる",
        "back": "to deprecate oneself and praise the listener",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弁解",
        "pronunciation": "べんかい",
        "back": "explanation, justification, excuse",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "変革",
        "pronunciation": "へんかく",
        "back": "change, reform(the) Reformation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "返還",
        "pronunciation": "へんかん",
        "back": "return, restoration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "便宜",
        "pronunciation": "べんぎ",
        "back": "convenience, accommodation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "偏見",
        "pronunciation": "へんけん",
        "back": "prejudice, narrow view",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弁護",
        "pronunciation": "べんご",
        "back": "defense, pleading, advocacy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "返済",
        "pronunciation": "へんさい",
        "back": "repayment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弁償",
        "pronunciation": "べんしょう",
        "back": "compensation, reparation, reimbursement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "変遷",
        "pronunciation": "へんせん",
        "back": "change, transition, vicissitudes",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "返答",
        "pronunciation": "へんとう",
        "back": "reply",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "変動",
        "pronunciation": "へんどう",
        "back": "change, fluctuation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弁論",
        "pronunciation": "べんろん",
        "back": "discussion, debate, argument",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "穂",
        "pronunciation": "ほ",
        "back": "ear (of plant), head (of plant)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "保育",
        "pronunciation": "ほいく",
        "back": "nursing, nurturing, rearing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ボイコット",
        "pronunciation": "ボイコット",
        "back": "boycott",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ポイント",
        "pronunciation": "ポイント",
        "back": "point",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "法案",
        "pronunciation": "ほうあん",
        "back": "bill (law)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "防衛",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうえい",
        "back": "defense, protection, self-defense",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "防火",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうか",
        "back": "fire prevention, fire fighting, fire proof",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "崩壊",
        "pronunciation": "ほうかい",
        "back": "collapse, decay (physics), crumbling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "妨害",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうがい",
        "back": "disturbance, obstruction, interference",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "法学",
        "pronunciation": "ほうがく",
        "back": "law, jurisprudence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "封建",
        "pronunciation": "ほうけん",
        "back": "feudalistic",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "豊作",
        "pronunciation": "ほうさく",
        "back": "abundant harvest, bumper crop",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "方策",
        "pronunciation": "ほうさく",
        "back": "plan, policy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "奉仕",
        "pronunciation": "ほうし",
        "back": "attendance, service",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "方式",
        "pronunciation": "ほうしき",
        "back": "form, method, system",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "放射",
        "pronunciation": "ほうしゃ",
        "back": "radiation, emission",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "放射能",
        "pronunciation": "ほうしゃのう",
        "back": "radioactivity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "報酬",
        "pronunciation": "ほうしゅう",
        "back": "remuneration, recompense, reward",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "放出",
        "pronunciation": "ほうしゅつ",
        "back": "release, emit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "報じる",
        "pronunciation": "ほうじる",
        "back": "to inform, to report",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "報ずる",
        "pronunciation": "ほうずる",
        "back": "to inform, to report",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "紡績",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうせき",
        "back": "spinning",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "呆然",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうぜん",
        "back": "dumbfounded, overcome with surprise",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "放置",
        "pronunciation": "ほうち",
        "back": "leave as is, leave alone, neglect",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "膨張",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうちょう",
        "back": "expansion, swelling, increase",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "法廷",
        "pronunciation": "ほうてい",
        "back": "courtroom",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "報道",
        "pronunciation": "ほうどう",
        "back": "coverage, report",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "冒頭",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうとう",
        "back": "beginning, start, outset",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "暴動",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうどう",
        "back": "insurrection, riot, uprising",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "褒美",
        "pronunciation": "ほうび",
        "back": "reward, prize",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "暴風",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうふう",
        "back": "storm, windstorm, gale",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "葬る",
        "pronunciation": "ほうむる",
        "back": "to bury, to entomb",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "放り込む",
        "pronunciation": "ほうりこむ",
        "back": "to throw into",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "放り出す",
        "pronunciation": "ほうりだす",
        "back": "to throw out, to give up, to abandon",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "暴力",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうりょく",
        "back": "violence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "飽和",
        "pronunciation": "ほうわ",
        "back": "saturation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ホース",
        "pronunciation": "ホース",
        "back": "hose",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ポーズ",
        "pronunciation": "ポーズ",
        "back": "pause",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ホール",
        "pronunciation": "ホール",
        "back": "hall; hole",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "保温",
        "pronunciation": "ほおん",
        "back": "retaining warmth, keeping heat in, heat insulation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "捕獲",
        "pronunciation": "ほかく",
        "back": "capture, seizure",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "保管",
        "pronunciation": "ほかん",
        "back": "custody, safekeeping, storage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "補給",
        "pronunciation": "ほきゅう",
        "back": "supply, supplying, replenishment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "補強",
        "pronunciation": "ほきょう",
        "back": "reinforcement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "募金",
        "pronunciation": "ぼきん",
        "back": "fund-raising, collection of funds",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "牧師",
        "pronunciation": "ぼくし",
        "back": "pastor, minister, clergyman",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "捕鯨",
        "pronunciation": "ほげい",
        "back": "whaling",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "惚ける",
        "pronunciation": "ぼける",
        "back": "to grow senile, to fade",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "保険",
        "pronunciation": "ほけん",
        "back": "insurance, guarantee",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "母校",
        "pronunciation": "ぼこう",
        "back": "alma mater",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "母国",
        "pronunciation": "ぼこく",
        "back": "one's home country (same as 自分の国 (じぶんのくに))",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "誇る",
        "pronunciation": "ほこる",
        "back": "to boast of, to be proud of",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "綻びる",
        "pronunciation": "ほころびる",
        "back": "to come apart at the seams, to smile broadly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "干し～",
        "pronunciation": "ほし～",
        "back": "dried ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ポジション",
        "pronunciation": "ポジション",
        "back": "position",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "干し物",
        "pronunciation": "ほしもの",
        "back": "dried washing (clothes",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "保守",
        "pronunciation": "ほしゅ",
        "back": "conservative, maintaining",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "補充",
        "pronunciation": "ほじゅう",
        "back": "supplementation, replenishment, replenishing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "補助",
        "pronunciation": "ほじょ",
        "back": "assistance, support, auxiliary",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "舗装",
        "pronunciation": "ほそう",
        "back": "pavement, road surface",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "補足",
        "pronunciation": "ほそく",
        "back": "supplement, complement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "墓地",
        "pronunciation": "ぼち",
        "back": "cemetery, graveyard",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "発作",
        "pronunciation": "ほっさ",
        "back": "fit, attack",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "没収",
        "pronunciation": "ぼっしゅう",
        "back": "forfeited",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "発足",
        "pronunciation": "ほっそく",
        "back": "starting, inauguration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ポット",
        "pronunciation": "ポット",
        "back": "pot",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ほっぺた",
        "pronunciation": "ほっぺた",
        "back": "cheek",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぼつぼつ",
        "pronunciation": "ぼつぼつ",
        "back": "gradually, here and there, spots",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "没落",
        "pronunciation": "ぼつらく",
        "back": "ruin, fall, collapse",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "解ける",
        "pronunciation": "ほどける",
        "back": "to come untied, to come apart",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "施す",
        "pronunciation": "ほどこす",
        "back": "to give, to conduct, to perform",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ほとり",
        "pronunciation": "ほとり",
        "back": "vicinity of lake; river",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぼやく",
        "pronunciation": "ぼやく",
        "back": "to grumble, to complain",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぼやける",
        "pronunciation": "ぼやける",
        "back": "to become dim, to become blurred",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "保養",
        "pronunciation": "ほよう",
        "back": "health preservation, recuperation, recreation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "捕虜",
        "pronunciation": "ほりょ",
        "back": "prisoner of war",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ボルト",
        "pronunciation": "ボルト",
        "back": "volt; bolt",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "滅びる",
        "pronunciation": "ほろびる",
        "back": "to be ruined, to perish, to be destroyed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "滅ぼす",
        "pronunciation": "ほろぼす",
        "back": "to destroy, to overthrow, to ruin",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "本格",
        "pronunciation": "ほんかく",
        "back": "propriety, full-scale",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "本館",
        "pronunciation": "ほんかん",
        "back": "main building",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "本気",
        "pronunciation": "ほんき",
        "back": "seriousness, truth, sanctity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "本国",
        "pronunciation": "ほんごく",
        "back": "one's own country",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "本質",
        "pronunciation": "ほんしつ",
        "back": "essence, true nature, reality",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "本体",
        "pronunciation": "ほんたい",
        "back": "substance, body, trunk",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "本音",
        "pronunciation": "ほんね",
        "back": "(one's) real intention, motive",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "本能",
        "pronunciation": "ほんのう",
        "back": "instinct",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "本場",
        "pronunciation": "ほんば",
        "back": "home, best place, genuine",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ポンプ",
        "pronunciation": "ポンプ",
        "back": "pump",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "本文",
        "pronunciation": "ほんぶん",
        "back": "text (of document), body (of letter)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "本名",
        "pronunciation": "ほんみょう",
        "back": "real name",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "マーク",
        "pronunciation": "マーク",
        "back": "mark",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "マイ～",
        "pronunciation": "マイ～",
        "back": "my ~, one's own ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "マイクロフォン",
        "pronunciation": "マイクロフォン",
        "back": "microphone",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "埋蔵",
        "pronunciation": "まいぞう",
        "back": "buried property, treasure trove",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "舞う",
        "pronunciation": "まう",
        "back": "to dance, to flutter about, to revolve",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "真上",
        "pronunciation": "まうえ",
        "back": "just above, right overhead",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "前売",
        "pronunciation": "まえうり",
        "back": "advance sale, booking",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "前置き",
        "pronunciation": "まえおき",
        "back": "preface, introduction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "任す",
        "pronunciation": "まかす",
        "back": "to entrust, to leave to a person",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "負かす",
        "pronunciation": "まかす",
        "back": "to defeat",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "賄う",
        "pronunciation": "まかなう",
        "back": "to give board to, to provide meals, to pay",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "紛らわしい",
        "pronunciation": "まぎらわしい",
        "back": "confusing, misleading, ambiguous",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "紛れる",
        "pronunciation": "まぎれる",
        "back": "to be diverted, to slip into",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "真心",
        "pronunciation": "まごころ",
        "back": "sincerity, devotion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "まごつく",
        "pronunciation": "まごつく",
        "back": "to be confused, to be flustered",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "誠",
        "pronunciation": "まこと",
        "back": "truth, faith, fidelity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "誠に",
        "pronunciation": "まことに",
        "back": "indeed, really (very polite), absolutely",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "まさしく",
        "pronunciation": "まさしく",
        "back": "surely, no doubt, evidently",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勝る",
        "pronunciation": "まさる",
        "back": "to excel, to surpass, to out-rival",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～増し",
        "pronunciation": "～まし",
        "back": "~increase",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "交える",
        "pronunciation": "まじえる",
        "back": "to mix, to converse with, to cross (swords)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "真下",
        "pronunciation": "ました",
        "back": "right under, directly below",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "まして",
        "pronunciation": "まして",
        "back": "still more, still less (with neg. verb), to say nothing of",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "交わる",
        "pronunciation": "まじわる",
        "back": "to cross, to intersect, to mingle with,",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "麻酔",
        "pronunciation": "ますい",
        "back": "anesthesia",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "またがる (うまを～)",
        "pronunciation": "またがる (うまを～)",
        "back": "to straddle",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "待ち合わせ",
        "pronunciation": "まちあわせ",
        "back": "appointment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "待ち遠しい",
        "pronunciation": "まちどおしい",
        "back": "looking forward to",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "待ち望む",
        "pronunciation": "まちのぞむ",
        "back": "to look anxiously for, to wait eagerly for",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "まちまち",
        "pronunciation": "まちまち",
        "back": "various, different",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "末期",
        "pronunciation": "まっき",
        "back": "deathbed, hour of death",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "真っ二つ",
        "pronunciation": "まっぷたつ",
        "back": "in two equal parts",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "まと",
        "pronunciation": "まと",
        "back": "mark, target",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "纏まり",
        "pronunciation": "まとまり",
        "back": "conclusion, settlement, consistency",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "纏め",
        "pronunciation": "まとめ",
        "back": "settlement, conclusion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "免れる",
        "pronunciation": "まぬがれる",
        "back": "to escape from, to be exempted",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "招き",
        "pronunciation": "まねき",
        "back": "invitation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "瞬き",
        "pronunciation": "まばたき",
        "back": "wink, twinkling (of stars), flicker (of light)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "麻痺",
        "pronunciation": "まひ",
        "back": "paralysis, palsy, numbness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～まみれ",
        "pronunciation": "～まみれ",
        "back": "covered with (by, in) ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "眉",
        "pronunciation": "まゆ",
        "back": "eyebrow",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "鞠",
        "pronunciation": "まり",
        "back": "ball",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "丸ごと",
        "pronunciation": "まるごと",
        "back": "in its entirety, whole, wholly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "まるっきり",
        "pronunciation": "まるっきり",
        "back": "completely, perfectly, just as if",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "丸々",
        "pronunciation": "まるまる",
        "back": "completely",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "丸める",
        "pronunciation": "まるめる",
        "back": "to make round, to round off, to roll up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "満月",
        "pronunciation": "まんげつ",
        "back": "full moon",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "満場",
        "pronunciation": "まんじょう",
        "back": "unanimous, whole audience",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "真ん前",
        "pronunciation": "まんまえ",
        "back": "right in front, under the nose",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "真ん丸い",
        "pronunciation": "まんまるい",
        "back": "perfectly circular",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "真ん円い",
        "pronunciation": "まんまるい",
        "back": "perfectly round",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～味",
        "pronunciation": "～み",
        "back": "~ cast (sense of taste)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見合い",
        "pronunciation": "みあい",
        "back": "formal marriage interview",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見合わせる",
        "pronunciation": "みあわせる",
        "back": "to exchange glances; to postpone",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見落とす",
        "pronunciation": "みおとす",
        "back": "to overlook, to fail to notice",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "未開",
        "pronunciation": "みかい",
        "back": "savage land, backward region, uncivilized",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "味覚",
        "pronunciation": "みかく",
        "back": "taste, palate, sense of taste",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "幹",
        "pronunciation": "みき",
        "back": "(tree) trunk",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見苦しい",
        "pronunciation": "みぐるしい",
        "back": "unsightly, ugly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見込み",
        "pronunciation": "みこみ",
        "back": "prospects, expectation, hope",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "未婚",
        "pronunciation": "みこん",
        "back": "unmarried",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "未熟",
        "pronunciation": "みじゅく",
        "back": "inexperience, unskilled, immature",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "微塵",
        "pronunciation": "みじん",
        "back": "particle, atom",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "水気",
        "pronunciation": "みずけ",
        "back": "moisture, dampness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ミスプリント",
        "pronunciation": "ミスプリント",
        "back": "misprint",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "みすぼらしい",
        "pronunciation": "みすぼらしい",
        "back": "shabby, seedy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ミセス",
        "pronunciation": "ミセス",
        "back": "Mrs.",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見せびらかす",
        "pronunciation": "みせびらかす",
        "back": "to show off, to flaunt",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見せ物",
        "pronunciation": "みせもの",
        "back": "show, exhibition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "溝",
        "pronunciation": "みぞ",
        "back": "ditch, drain, gutter, gap",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "満たす",
        "pronunciation": "みたす",
        "back": "to satisfy, to ingratiate, to fill, to fulfill",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "乱す",
        "pronunciation": "みだす",
        "back": "to throw out of order, to disarrange, to disturb",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "乱れる",
        "pronunciation": "みだれる",
        "back": "to get confused, to be disordered, to be disturbed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "未知",
        "pronunciation": "みち",
        "back": "not yet known",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "身近",
        "pronunciation": "みぢか",
        "back": "near oneself, close to one, familiar",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "導く",
        "pronunciation": "みちびく",
        "back": "to be guided, to be shown",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "密集",
        "pronunciation": "みっしゅう",
        "back": "crowd, close formation, dense",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "密接",
        "pronunciation": "みっせつ",
        "back": "connected, close, intimate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "密度",
        "pronunciation": "みつど",
        "back": "density",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見積もり",
        "pronunciation": "みつもり",
        "back": "estimation, quotation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "未定",
        "pronunciation": "みてい",
        "back": "not yet fixed, undecided, pending",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見通し",
        "pronunciation": "みとおし",
        "back": "perspective, unobstructed view, prospect",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見なす",
        "pronunciation": "みなす",
        "back": "to consider as, to regard",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "源",
        "pronunciation": "みなもと",
        "back": "source, origin",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見習う",
        "pronunciation": "みならう",
        "back": "to follow another's example",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "身なり",
        "pronunciation": "みなり",
        "back": "personal appearance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "峰",
        "pronunciation": "みね",
        "back": "peak, ridge",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "身の上",
        "pronunciation": "みのうえ",
        "back": "one's future, one's welfare, one's personal history",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見逃す",
        "pronunciation": "みのがす",
        "back": "to miss, to overlook, to leave at large",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "身の回り",
        "pronunciation": "みのまわり",
        "back": "one's personal appearance, personal belongings",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見計らう",
        "pronunciation": "みはからう",
        "back": "to choose at one's own discretion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見晴らし",
        "pronunciation": "みはらし",
        "back": "view",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "身振り",
        "pronunciation": "みぶり",
        "back": "gesture",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "脈",
        "pronunciation": "みゃく",
        "back": "pulse",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ミュージック",
        "pronunciation": "ミュージック",
        "back": "music",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "未練",
        "pronunciation": "みれん",
        "back": "lingering affection, attachment, regret(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "見渡す",
        "pronunciation": "みわたす",
        "back": "to look out over, to survey (scene), to take an extensive view of",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "民宿",
        "pronunciation": "みんしゅく",
        "back": "private house providing lodging and meals to tourists",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "民族",
        "pronunciation": "みんぞく",
        "back": "people, race",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "民俗",
        "pronunciation": "みんぞく",
        "back": "folk customs",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無意味",
        "pronunciation": "むいみ",
        "back": "nonsense, no meaning",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ムード",
        "pronunciation": "ムード",
        "back": "mood",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無口",
        "pronunciation": "むくち",
        "back": "reticence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "婿",
        "pronunciation": "むこ",
        "back": "son-in-law",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無効",
        "pronunciation": "むこう",
        "back": "invalid, no effect, unavailable",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無言",
        "pronunciation": "むごん",
        "back": "silence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無邪気",
        "pronunciation": "むじゃき",
        "back": "innocence, simple-mindedness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "むしる",
        "pronunciation": "むしる",
        "back": "to pluck, to pick, to tear",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "結び",
        "pronunciation": "むすび",
        "back": "ending, conclusion, union",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "結び付き",
        "pronunciation": "むすびつき",
        "back": "connection, relation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "結び付く",
        "pronunciation": "むすびつく",
        "back": "to be connected or related, to join together",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "結び付ける",
        "pronunciation": "むすびつける",
        "back": "to combine, to join, to tie on, to attach with a knot",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無線",
        "pronunciation": "むせん",
        "back": "wireless, radio",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無駄遣い",
        "pronunciation": "むだづかい",
        "back": "waste money on, squander money on",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無断",
        "pronunciation": "むだん",
        "back": "without permission, without notice",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無知",
        "pronunciation": "むち",
        "back": "ignorance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無茶",
        "pronunciation": "むちゃ",
        "back": "absurd, unreasonable",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無茶苦茶",
        "pronunciation": "むちゃくちゃ",
        "back": "confused, jumbled, mixed up, unreasonable",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "空しい",
        "pronunciation": "むなしい",
        "back": "vacant, futile, vain",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無念",
        "pronunciation": "むねん",
        "back": "chagrin, regret",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無能",
        "pronunciation": "むのう",
        "back": "inefficiency, incompetence",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無闇に",
        "pronunciation": "むやみに",
        "back": "unreasonably, absurdly, at random",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無用",
        "pronunciation": "むよう",
        "back": "useless, needlessness, unnecessariness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "斑",
        "pronunciation": "むら",
        "back": "unevenness, inconsistency, irregularity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "群がる",
        "pronunciation": "むらがる",
        "back": "to swarm, to gather",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "無論",
        "pronunciation": "むろん",
        "back": "of course, naturally",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "名産",
        "pronunciation": "めいさん",
        "back": "noted product",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "名称",
        "pronunciation": "めいしょう",
        "back": "name",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "命中",
        "pronunciation": "めいちゅう",
        "back": "a hit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "明白",
        "pronunciation": "めいはく",
        "back": "obvious, clear",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "名簿",
        "pronunciation": "めいぼ",
        "back": "register of names",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "名誉",
        "pronunciation": "めいよ",
        "back": "honor, credit, prestige",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "明瞭",
        "pronunciation": "めいりょう",
        "back": "clarity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "明朗",
        "pronunciation": "めいろう",
        "back": "bright, clear, cheerful",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "メーカー",
        "pronunciation": "メーカー",
        "back": "manufacturer",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "目方",
        "pronunciation": "めかた",
        "back": "weight",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "恵み",
        "pronunciation": "めぐみ",
        "back": "blessing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "恵む",
        "pronunciation": "めぐむ",
        "back": "to bless, to show mercy to",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "目覚しい",
        "pronunciation": "めざましい",
        "back": "brilliant, remarkable",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "目覚める",
        "pronunciation": "めざめる",
        "back": "to wake up",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "召す",
        "pronunciation": "めす",
        "back": "to call, to send for, to put on",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雌",
        "pronunciation": "めす",
        "back": "female (animal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "目付き",
        "pronunciation": "めつき",
        "back": "look, expression of the eyes, eyes",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "滅亡",
        "pronunciation": "めつぼう",
        "back": "downfall, collapse, destruction",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "メディア",
        "pronunciation": "メディア",
        "back": "media",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "目途",
        "pronunciation": "めど",
        "back": "goal, outlook",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "目盛",
        "pronunciation": "めもり",
        "back": "scale, gradations",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "メロディー",
        "pronunciation": "メロディー",
        "back": "melody",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "面会",
        "pronunciation": "めんかい",
        "back": "interview",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "免除",
        "pronunciation": "めんじょ",
        "back": "exemption, exoneration, discharge",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "面する",
        "pronunciation": "めんする",
        "back": "to face on, to look out on to",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "面目",
        "pronunciation": "めんぼく",
        "back": "face, honor, reputation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "面目",
        "pronunciation": "めんもく",
        "back": "face, honor, reputation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～網",
        "pronunciation": "～もう",
        "back": "~ network",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "設ける",
        "pronunciation": "もうける",
        "back": "to create, to establish",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "申し入れる",
        "pronunciation": "もうしいれる",
        "back": "to propose, to suggest",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "申込",
        "pronunciation": "もうしこみ",
        "back": "application, request, proposal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "申出",
        "pronunciation": "もうしで",
        "back": "request, claim, report",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "申し出る",
        "pronunciation": "もうしでる",
        "back": "to report to, to tell, to suggest",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "申し分",
        "pronunciation": "もうしぶん",
        "back": "objection, shortcomings",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "盲点",
        "pronunciation": "もうてん",
        "back": "blind spot",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "猛烈",
        "pronunciation": "もうれつ",
        "back": "violent, vehement, rage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "モーテル",
        "pronunciation": "モーテル",
        "back": "motel",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "もがく",
        "pronunciation": "もがく",
        "back": "to struggle, to wriggle, to be impatient",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "目録",
        "pronunciation": "もくろく",
        "back": "catalogue, catalog, list",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "目論見",
        "pronunciation": "もくろみ",
        "back": "a plan, a scheme, intention",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "模型",
        "pronunciation": "もけい",
        "back": "model, dummy, marquette",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "模索",
        "pronunciation": "もさく",
        "back": "groping (for)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "もしかして",
        "pronunciation": "もしかして",
        "back": "perhaps, possibly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "もしくは",
        "pronunciation": "もしくは",
        "back": "or, otherwise",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "もたらす",
        "pronunciation": "もたらす",
        "back": "to bring, to take, to bring about",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "持ち切り",
        "pronunciation": "もちきり",
        "back": "hot topic, talk of the town",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "目下",
        "pronunciation": "もっか",
        "back": "at present, now",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "専ら",
        "pronunciation": "もっぱら",
        "back": "wholly, solely, entirely",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "もてなす",
        "pronunciation": "もてなす",
        "back": "to entertain, to make welcome",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "もてる",
        "pronunciation": "もてる",
        "back": "to be well liked, to be popular",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "モニター",
        "pronunciation": "モニター",
        "back": "(computer) monitor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "物好き",
        "pronunciation": "ものずき",
        "back": "(idle) curiosity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "物足りない",
        "pronunciation": "ものたりない",
        "back": "unsatisfied, unsatisfactory",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "もはや",
        "pronunciation": "もはや",
        "back": "already, now",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "模範",
        "pronunciation": "もはん",
        "back": "model, example",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "模倣",
        "pronunciation": "もほう",
        "back": "imitation, copying",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "もめる",
        "pronunciation": "もめる",
        "back": "to disagree, to dispute",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "股",
        "pronunciation": "もも",
        "back": "thigh, femur",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "腿",
        "pronunciation": "もも",
        "back": "thigh, femur",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "催す",
        "pronunciation": "もよおす",
        "back": "to hold (a meeting), to give (a dinner)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "漏らす",
        "pronunciation": "もらす",
        "back": "to let leak, to reveal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "盛り上がる",
        "pronunciation": "もりあがる",
        "back": "to rouse, to swell, to rise",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "漏る",
        "pronunciation": "もる",
        "back": "to leak, to run out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "漏れる",
        "pronunciation": "もれる",
        "back": "to leak out, to escape, to filter out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "脆い",
        "pronunciation": "もろい",
        "back": "brittle, fragile, tender-hearted",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "もろに",
        "pronunciation": "もろに",
        "back": "completely, altogether, bodily",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "矢",
        "pronunciation": "や",
        "back": "arrow",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "野外",
        "pronunciation": "やがい",
        "back": "fields, outskirts, open air, suburbs",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～薬",
        "pronunciation": "～やく",
        "back": "medicine",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "夜具",
        "pronunciation": "やぐ",
        "back": "bedding",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "役職",
        "pronunciation": "やくしょく",
        "back": "post, managerial position, official position",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "役場",
        "pronunciation": "やくば",
        "back": "town hall",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "やけに",
        "pronunciation": "やけに",
        "back": "sure, very",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "屋敷",
        "pronunciation": "やしき",
        "back": "mansion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "養う",
        "pronunciation": "やしなう",
        "back": "to rear, to maintain, to cultivate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "野心",
        "pronunciation": "やしん",
        "back": "ambition, aspiration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "安っぽい",
        "pronunciation": "やすっぽい",
        "back": "cheap-looking, tawdry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "休める",
        "pronunciation": "やすめる",
        "back": "to rest, to suspend, to give relief",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "野生",
        "pronunciation": "やせい",
        "back": "wild",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "奴",
        "pronunciation": "やつ",
        "back": "(vulg.) fellow, guy, chap",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "闇",
        "pronunciation": "やみ",
        "back": "darkness, shady, illegal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "病む",
        "pronunciation": "やむ",
        "back": "to fall ill, to be ill",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ややこしい",
        "pronunciation": "ややこしい",
        "back": "puzzling, tangled, complicated, complex",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "やりとおす",
        "pronunciation": "やりとおす",
        "back": "to carry through, to achieve, to complete",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "やりとげる",
        "pronunciation": "やりとげる",
        "back": "to accomplish",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "和らげる",
        "pronunciation": "やわらげる",
        "back": "to soften, to moderate, to relieve",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ヤング",
        "pronunciation": "ヤング",
        "back": "young",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～油",
        "pronunciation": "～ゆ",
        "back": "~ oil",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "優位",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうい",
        "back": "predominance, ascendancy, superiority",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "憂鬱",
        "pronunciation": "ゆううつ",
        "back": "depression, melancholy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "有益",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうえき",
        "back": "beneficial, profitable",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "優越",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうえつ",
        "back": "supremacy, predominance, being superior to",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "勇敢",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうかん",
        "back": "bravery, heroism, gallantry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "夕暮れ",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうぐれ",
        "back": "evening, (evening) twilight",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "融資",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうし",
        "back": "financing, loan",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "有する",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうする",
        "back": "to own, to be endowed with",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "優勢",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうせい",
        "back": "superiority, superior power, predominance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "優先",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうせん",
        "back": "preference, priority",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "誘導",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうどう",
        "back": "guidance, leading, inducement",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "融通",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうずう",
        "back": "adaptability, versatility, finance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "優美",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうび",
        "back": "grace, refinement, elegance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "有望",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうぼう",
        "back": "good prospects, full of hope, promising",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "遊牧",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうぼく",
        "back": "nomadism",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "夕焼け",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうやけ",
        "back": "sunset",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "有力",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうりょく",
        "back": "influence, prominence; potent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "幽霊",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうれい",
        "back": "ghost, specter, phantom",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "誘惑",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうわく",
        "back": "temptation, allurement, lure",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "故",
        "pronunciation": "ゆえ",
        "back": "reason, cause, circumstances",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "歪む",
        "pronunciation": "ゆがむ",
        "back": "to warp, to be crooked, to be distorted",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "揺さぶる",
        "pronunciation": "ゆさぶる",
        "back": "to shake, to jolt, to rock, to swing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "濯ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "ゆすぐ",
        "back": "to rinse, to wash out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ゆとり",
        "pronunciation": "ゆとり",
        "back": "reserve, affluence, time (to spare)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ユニーク",
        "pronunciation": "ユニーク",
        "back": "unique",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ユニフォーム",
        "pronunciation": "ユニフォーム",
        "back": "uniform",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "指差す",
        "pronunciation": "ゆびさす",
        "back": "to point at",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弓",
        "pronunciation": "ゆみ",
        "back": "bow",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "揺らぐ",
        "pronunciation": "ゆらぐ",
        "back": "to swing, to sway, to shake",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "緩む",
        "pronunciation": "ゆるむ",
        "back": "to become loose, to slacken",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "緩める",
        "pronunciation": "ゆるめる",
        "back": "to loosen, to slow down",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "緩やか",
        "pronunciation": "ゆるやか",
        "back": "lenient",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "要因",
        "pronunciation": "よういん",
        "back": "primary factor, main cause",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "溶液",
        "pronunciation": "ようえき",
        "back": "solution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "用件",
        "pronunciation": "ようけん",
        "back": "business",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "養護",
        "pronunciation": "ようご",
        "back": "protection, nursing, protective care",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "用紙",
        "pronunciation": "ようし",
        "back": "a form",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "様式",
        "pronunciation": "ようしき",
        "back": "style, form, pattern",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "要する",
        "pronunciation": "ようする",
        "back": "to demand, to require, to take",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "要請",
        "pronunciation": "ようせい",
        "back": "claim, demand, request, application",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "様相",
        "pronunciation": "ようそう",
        "back": "aspect",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "用品",
        "pronunciation": "ようひん",
        "back": "articles, supplies, parts",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "洋風",
        "pronunciation": "ようふう",
        "back": "western style",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "用法",
        "pronunciation": "ようほう",
        "back": "directions, rules of use",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "要望",
        "pronunciation": "ようぼう",
        "back": "demand for, request",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "余暇",
        "pronunciation": "よか",
        "back": "leisure, leisure time, spare time",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "予感",
        "pronunciation": "よかん",
        "back": "presentiment, premonition",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "余興",
        "pronunciation": "よきょう",
        "back": "side show, entertainment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "預金",
        "pronunciation": "よきん",
        "back": "deposit, bank account",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "欲",
        "pronunciation": "よく",
        "back": "greed, wants",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "抑圧",
        "pronunciation": "よくあつ",
        "back": "restraint, oppression, suppression",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "浴室",
        "pronunciation": "よくしつ",
        "back": "bathroom, bath",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "抑制",
        "pronunciation": "よくせい",
        "back": "control, restraint, suppression",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "欲深い",
        "pronunciation": "よくふかい",
        "back": "greedy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "欲望",
        "pronunciation": "よくぼう",
        "back": "desire, appetite",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "避ける",
        "pronunciation": "よける",
        "back": "to avoid (physical contact with; to ward off, to avert",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "予言",
        "pronunciation": "よげん",
        "back": "prediction, promise, prognostication",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "横綱",
        "pronunciation": "よこづな",
        "back": "sumo grand champion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "汚れ",
        "pronunciation": "よごれ",
        "back": "dirt, filth",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "よし (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "よし (かん)",
        "back": "all right!",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "良し",
        "pronunciation": "よし",
        "back": "all right!",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "善し悪し",
        "pronunciation": "よしあし",
        "back": "good or bad, merits or demerits, quality",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "余所見",
        "pronunciation": "よそみ",
        "back": "looking away, looking aside",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "余地",
        "pronunciation": "よち",
        "back": "place, room, margin",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "よって (よりどころ)",
        "pronunciation": "よって (よりどころ)",
        "back": "therefore, consequently",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "与党",
        "pronunciation": "よとう",
        "back": "government party, (ruling) party in power, government",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "呼び止める",
        "pronunciation": "よびとめる",
        "back": "to flag down",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "夜更し",
        "pronunciation": "よふかし",
        "back": "staying up late, keeping late hours",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "夜更け",
        "pronunciation": "よふけ",
        "back": "late at night",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "余程",
        "pronunciation": "よほど",
        "back": "very, much, to a large extent, quite",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "読み上げる",
        "pronunciation": "よみあげる",
        "back": "to read out loud (and clearly), to call a roll",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "～寄り",
        "pronunciation": "～より",
        "back": "near to ~ (e.g., North by East)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "寄り掛かる",
        "pronunciation": "よりかかる",
        "back": "to lean against, to recline on, to lean on, to rely on",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "世論",
        "pronunciation": "よろん",
        "back": "public opinion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "弱る",
        "pronunciation": "よわる",
        "back": "to weaken, to be troubled, to be emaciated",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "来場",
        "pronunciation": "らいじょう",
        "back": "attendance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ライス",
        "pronunciation": "ライス",
        "back": "rice",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "酪農",
        "pronunciation": "らくのう",
        "back": "dairy farming",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "落下",
        "pronunciation": "らっか",
        "back": "fall, drop, come down",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "楽観",
        "pronunciation": "らっかん",
        "back": "optimism",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ランプ",
        "pronunciation": "ランプ",
        "back": "lamp; ramp",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "濫用",
        "pronunciation": "らんよう",
        "back": "abuse, misuse, using to excess",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "リード",
        "pronunciation": "リード",
        "back": "lead; reed",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "理屈",
        "pronunciation": "りくつ",
        "back": "theory, reason",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "利子",
        "pronunciation": "りし",
        "back": "interest (bank)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "利潤",
        "pronunciation": "りじゅん",
        "back": "profit, returns",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "理性",
        "pronunciation": "りせい",
        "back": "reason, sense",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "利息",
        "pronunciation": "りそく",
        "back": "interest (bank)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "立体",
        "pronunciation": "りったい",
        "back": "solid body",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "立方",
        "pronunciation": "りっぽう",
        "back": "cube",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "立法",
        "pronunciation": "りっぽう",
        "back": "legislation, lawmaking",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "利点",
        "pronunciation": "りてん",
        "back": "advantage, point in favor",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "略奪",
        "pronunciation": "りゃくだつ",
        "back": "pillage, looting, robbery",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "略語",
        "pronunciation": "りゃくご",
        "back": "abbreviation, acronym",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "流通",
        "pronunciation": "りゅうつう",
        "back": "circulation of money or goods, distribution",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "領域",
        "pronunciation": "りょういき",
        "back": "area, territory, region",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "了解",
        "pronunciation": "りょうかい",
        "back": "comprehension, consent, understanding",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "領海",
        "pronunciation": "りょうかい",
        "back": "territorial waters",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "両極",
        "pronunciation": "りょうきょく",
        "back": "both extremities, north and south poles",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "良好",
        "pronunciation": "りょうこう",
        "back": "favorable, satisfactory",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "良識",
        "pronunciation": "りょうしき",
        "back": "good sense",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "良質",
        "pronunciation": "りょうしつ",
        "back": "good quality, superior quality",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "了承",
        "pronunciation": "りょうしょう",
        "back": "acknowledgment, understanding",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "良心",
        "pronunciation": "りょうしん",
        "back": "conscience",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "領地",
        "pronunciation": "りょうち",
        "back": "territory",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "領土",
        "pronunciation": "りょうど",
        "back": "territory, possession",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "両立",
        "pronunciation": "りょうりつ",
        "back": "compatibility, coexistence, standing together",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "旅客",
        "pronunciation": "りょかく",
        "back": "passenger",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "旅券",
        "pronunciation": "りょけん",
        "back": "passport",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "履歴",
        "pronunciation": "りれき",
        "back": "personal history, background, log",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "理論",
        "pronunciation": "りろん",
        "back": "theory",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "林業",
        "pronunciation": "りんぎょう",
        "back": "forestry",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "類",
        "pronunciation": "るい",
        "back": "kind, class, family",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "類推",
        "pronunciation": "るいすい",
        "back": "analogy",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "類似",
        "pronunciation": "るいじ",
        "back": "analogous",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ルーズ",
        "pronunciation": "ルーズ",
        "back": "loose",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷酷",
        "pronunciation": "れいこく",
        "back": "cruelty, coldheartedness, ruthless",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷蔵",
        "pronunciation": "れいぞう",
        "back": "refrigeration",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷淡",
        "pronunciation": "れいたん",
        "back": "coolness, indifference",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "レース",
        "pronunciation": "レース",
        "back": "race; lace",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "レギュラー",
        "pronunciation": "レギュラー",
        "back": "regular",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "レッスン",
        "pronunciation": "レッスン",
        "back": "lesson",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "レディー",
        "pronunciation": "レディー",
        "back": "lady",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "レバー",
        "pronunciation": "レバー",
        "back": "lever; liver",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "恋愛",
        "pronunciation": "れんあい",
        "back": "love, romance",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "バッテリー",
        "pronunciation": "バッテリー",
        "back": "battery",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "バット",
        "pronunciation": "バット",
        "back": "bat, vat",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "発病",
        "pronunciation": "はつびょう",
        "back": "attack, to become sick",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "初耳",
        "pronunciation": "はつみみ",
        "back": "something heard for the first time",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "果て",
        "pronunciation": "はて",
        "back": "the end, the extremity, the limit(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "果てる",
        "pronunciation": "はてる",
        "back": "to end, to be finished, to be exhausted",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ばてる",
        "pronunciation": "ばてる",
        "back": "to be exhausted, to be worn out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "パトカー",
        "pronunciation": "パトカー",
        "back": "patrol car",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "甚だ",
        "pronunciation": "はなはだ",
        "back": "very, greatly, exceedingly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "華々しい",
        "pronunciation": "はなばなしい",
        "back": "brilliant, magnificent, spectacular",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "花びら",
        "pronunciation": "はなびら",
        "back": "(flower) petal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "華やか",
        "pronunciation": "はなやか",
        "back": "brilliant, gorgeous, florid",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "阻む",
        "pronunciation": "はばむ",
        "back": "to keep someone from doing, to stop, to oppose",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "浜",
        "pronunciation": "はま",
        "back": "beach, seashore",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "浜辺",
        "pronunciation": "はまべ",
        "back": "beach, foreshore",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "はまる",
        "pronunciation": "はまる",
        "back": "to get into, to go into, to fit, to be fit for, to suit",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "早める",
        "pronunciation": "はやめる",
        "back": "to hasten, to quicken, to accelerate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "腹立ち",
        "pronunciation": "はらだち",
        "back": "anger",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "原っぱ",
        "pronunciation": "はらっぱ",
        "back": "open field, empty lot, plain",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "はらはら",
        "pronunciation": "はらはら",
        "back": "feel nervous",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ばらまく",
        "pronunciation": "ばらまく",
        "back": "to disseminate, to scatter",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "張り紙",
        "pronunciation": "はりがみ",
        "back": "notice, poster",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "遥か",
        "pronunciation": "はるか",
        "back": "far, far-away, distant",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "破裂",
        "pronunciation": "はれつ",
        "back": "explosion, rupture, break off",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "腫れる",
        "pronunciation": "はれる",
        "back": "to swell (from inflammation, to become swollen)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "繁栄",
        "pronunciation": "はんえい",
        "back": "prospering, prosperity, flourishing",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "版画",
        "pronunciation": "はんが",
        "back": "art print",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ハンガー",
        "pronunciation": "ハンガー",
        "back": "(coat) hanger",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "反感",
        "pronunciation": "はんかん",
        "back": "antipathy, revolt, animosity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "反響",
        "pronunciation": "はんきょう",
        "back": "echo, reverberation, repercussion",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "パンク",
        "pronunciation": "パンク",
        "back": "puncture, bursting; punk",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "反撃",
        "pronunciation": "はんげき",
        "back": "counterattack, counteroffensive, counterblow",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "判決",
        "pronunciation": "はんけつ",
        "back": "judicial decision, judgment, sentence, decree",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "反射",
        "pronunciation": "はんしゃ",
        "back": "reflection, reverberation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "繁盛",
        "pronunciation": "はんじょう",
        "back": "prosperity, flourishing, thriving",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "繁殖",
        "pronunciation": "はんしょく",
        "back": "breed, multiply, propagation",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "反する",
        "pronunciation": "はんする",
        "back": "to be inconsistent with, to oppose, to contradict",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "判定",
        "pronunciation": "はんてい",
        "back": "judgment, decision, award, verdict",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "万人",
        "pronunciation": "ばんにん",
        "back": "all people, everybody, 10000 people",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "晩年",
        "pronunciation": "ばんねん",
        "back": "(one's) last years",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "反応",
        "pronunciation": "はんのう",
        "back": "reaction, response",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "万能",
        "pronunciation": "ばんのう",
        "back": "all-purpose, almighty, omnipotent",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "半端",
        "pronunciation": "はんぱ",
        "back": "fragment, fraction, incompleteness",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "反発",
        "pronunciation": "はんぱつ",
        "back": "repelling, rebound, oppose",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "反乱",
        "pronunciation": "はんらん",
        "back": "rebellion, revolt, uprising",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "氾濫",
        "pronunciation": "はんらん",
        "back": "overflowing, flood",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "美",
        "pronunciation": "び",
        "back": "beauty",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ひいては",
        "pronunciation": "ひいては",
        "back": "not only…but also, in addition to, consequently",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ビールス",
        "pronunciation": "ビールス",
        "back": "virus",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "控室",
        "pronunciation": "ひかえしつ",
        "back": "waiting room",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "控える",
        "pronunciation": "ひかえる",
        "back": "to hold back; to make notes",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "悲観",
        "pronunciation": "ひかん",
        "back": "pessimism, disappointment",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "引き上げる",
        "pronunciation": "ひきあげる",
        "back": "to withdraw, to leave, to pull out",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "率いる",
        "pronunciation": "ひきいる",
        "back": "to lead, to spearhead (a group), to command (troops)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "引き起こす",
        "pronunciation": "ひきおこす",
        "back": "to cause",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "引下げる",
        "pronunciation": "ひきさげる",
        "back": "to pull down, to lower, to reduce, to withdraw",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "引きずる",
        "pronunciation": "ひきずる",
        "back": "to drag along, to pull, to prolong",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "引取る",
        "pronunciation": "ひきとる",
        "back": "to take back; to adopt; to leave",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "否決",
        "pronunciation": "ひけつ",
        "back": "rejection, negation, voting down",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "日頃",
        "pronunciation": "ひごろ",
        "back": "normally, habitually",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "久しい",
        "pronunciation": "ひさしい",
        "back": "long, long-continued, old (story)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "悲惨",
        "pronunciation": "ひさん",
        "back": "tragedy, disaster; misery, wretched, pitiful",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ビジネス",
        "pronunciation": "ビジネス",
        "back": "business",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "比重",
        "pronunciation": "ひじゅう",
        "back": "specific gravity",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "美術",
        "pronunciation": "びじゅつ",
        "back": "art, fine arts",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "秘書",
        "pronunciation": "ひしょ",
        "back": "(private) secretary",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "微笑",
        "pronunciation": "びしょう",
        "back": "smile",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "歪む",
        "pronunciation": "ひずむ",
        "back": "to warp, to be distorted",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "密か",
        "pronunciation": "ひそか",
        "back": "secret, private, surreptitious",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "浸す",
        "pronunciation": "ひたす",
        "back": "to soak, to dip, to drench",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ひたすら",
        "pronunciation": "ひたすら",
        "back": "nothing but, earnestly, intently",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "左利き",
        "pronunciation": "ひだりきき",
        "back": "left-handedness, sake drinker, left-hander",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "引っ掻く",
        "pronunciation": "ひっかく",
        "back": "to scratch",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "必修",
        "pronunciation": "ひっしゅう",
        "back": "required (subject)",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "びっしょり",
        "pronunciation": "びっしょり",
        "back": "wet through, drenched",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "必然",
        "pronunciation": "ひつぜん",
        "back": "inevitable, necessary",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "匹敵",
        "pronunciation": "ひってき",
        "back": "comparing with, rival, equal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一息",
        "pronunciation": "ひといき",
        "back": "a breath, a pause, an effort",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "人影",
        "pronunciation": "ひとかげ",
        "back": "man's shadow, soul",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "人柄",
        "pronunciation": "ひとがら",
        "back": "personality, character",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "人気",
        "pronunciation": "ひとけ",
        "back": "sign of life",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一頃",
        "pronunciation": "ひところ",
        "back": "once, some time ago",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "人質",
        "pronunciation": "ひとじち",
        "back": "hostage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "一筋",
        "pronunciation": "ひとすじ",
        "back": "a line, earnestly, blindly, straightforwardly",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "人目",
        "pronunciation": "ひとめ",
        "back": "glimpse, public gaze",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "日取り",
        "pronunciation": "ひどり",
        "back": "fixed date, appointed day",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雛",
        "pronunciation": "ひな",
        "back": "young bird, chick, doll",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "雛祭",
        "pronunciation": "ひなまつり",
        "back": "Girls' (dolls') Festival",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "日向",
        "pronunciation": "ひなた",
        "back": "sunny place, in the sun",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "非難",
        "pronunciation": "ひなん",
        "back": "blame, attack, criticism",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "避難",
        "pronunciation": "ひなん",
        "back": "taking refuge, finding shelter",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "日の丸",
        "pronunciation": "ひのまる",
        "back": "the Japanese flag",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "火花",
        "pronunciation": "ひばな",
        "back": "spark",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ひび (かべの～)",
        "pronunciation": "ひび (かべの～)",
        "back": "crack, fissure, flaw",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "悲鳴",
        "pronunciation": "ひめい",
        "back": "shriek, scream",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷やかす",
        "pronunciation": "ひやかす",
        "back": "to banter, to make fun of, to jeer at, to cool, to refrigerate",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "日焼け",
        "pronunciation": "ひやけ",
        "back": "sunburn",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "標語",
        "pronunciation": "ひょうご",
        "back": "motto, slogan, catchword",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "描写",
        "pronunciation": "びょうしゃ",
        "back": "depiction, description, portrayal",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "ひょっと",
        "pronunciation": "ひょっと",
        "back": "possibly, accidentally",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "びら",
        "pronunciation": "びら",
        "back": "handout, leaflet",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "平たい",
        "pronunciation": "ひらたい",
        "back": "flat, even, level",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "びり",
        "pronunciation": "びり",
        "back": "last on the list, at the bottom",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "比率",
        "pronunciation": "ひりつ",
        "back": "ratio, proportion, percentage",
        "JLPT Level": "N1",
        "collection_id": "11"
    },
    {
        "front": "〜 (まる) ごと",
        "pronunciation": "〜 (まる) ごと",
        "back": "whole ~, all of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "(かさを～) さす",
        "pronunciation": "(かさを～) さす",
        "back": "to open; hold (an umbrella)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "〜(日本) 式",
        "pronunciation": "～(にほん) しき",
        "back": "custom,",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～位",
        "pronunciation": "～い",
        "back": "~th place",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～いち (にほんいち)",
        "pronunciation": "～いち (にほんいち)",
        "back": "No. 1 ~ (in)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～園",
        "pronunciation": "～えん",
        "back": "~ garden (especially man made)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～おしまい (おわり)",
        "pronunciation": "～おしまい (おわり)",
        "back": "end up ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～日",
        "pronunciation": "～か",
        "back": "counter for days",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～下",
        "pronunciation": "～か",
        "back": "under ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～化",
        "pronunciation": "～か",
        "back": "action of making something",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～科",
        "pronunciation": "～か",
        "back": "family, group, course",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～歌",
        "pronunciation": "～か",
        "back": "song of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～画",
        "pronunciation": "～が",
        "back": "picture, painting",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～外",
        "pronunciation": "～がい",
        "back": "out of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～難い",
        "pronunciation": "～がたい",
        "back": "hard (difficult) to do ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～がち",
        "pronunciation": "～がち",
        "back": "tend to do ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～刊",
        "pronunciation": "～かん",
        "back": "~ issued (magazine, newspaper)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～間",
        "pronunciation": "～かん",
        "back": "between, during",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～巻",
        "pronunciation": "～かん",
        "back": "volume",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～館",
        "pronunciation": "～かん",
        "back": "~ hall, ~ building",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～感",
        "pronunciation": "～かん",
        "back": "feeling, sense, impression",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～期",
        "pronunciation": "～き",
        "back": "~age, ~period",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～器",
        "pronunciation": "～き",
        "back": "device, equipment",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～機",
        "pronunciation": "～き",
        "back": "machine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～気味",
        "pronunciation": "～ぎみ",
        "back": "slightly ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～教",
        "pronunciation": "～きょう",
        "back": "religion",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～行",
        "pronunciation": "～ぎょう",
        "back": "line, row",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～業",
        "pronunciation": "～ぎょう",
        "back": "type of business",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～きる",
        "pronunciation": "～きる",
        "back": "nevertheless, to carry through",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～切れ",
        "pronunciation": "～きれ",
        "back": "out of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～口",
        "pronunciation": "～くち",
        "back": "~ opening; ~ entrance, ~ exit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～家",
        "pronunciation": "～け",
        "back": "~'s family, the house of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～形",
        "pronunciation": "～けい",
        "back": "shape of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～系",
        "pronunciation": "～けい",
        "back": "~ system, ~ lineage, ~ group",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～圏",
        "pronunciation": "～けん",
        "back": "bloc, sphere, area",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～校",
        "pronunciation": "～こう",
        "back": "counter for school",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～港",
        "pronunciation": "～こう",
        "back": "~ port",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～号",
        "pronunciation": "～ごう",
        "back": "counter for magazine; the name of ship",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～国",
        "pronunciation": "～こく",
        "back": "nation of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～毎",
        "pronunciation": "～ごと",
        "back": "every ~, each ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～山",
        "pronunciation": "～さん",
        "back": "the name of mountain",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～産",
        "pronunciation": "～さん",
        "back": "made in ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～史",
        "pronunciation": "～し",
        "back": "history of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～紙",
        "pronunciation": "～し",
        "back": "newspaper, type of paper",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～寺",
        "pronunciation": "～じ",
        "back": "the name of temple",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～時間目",
        "pronunciation": "～じかんめ",
        "back": "~th hour, ~th period",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～室",
        "pronunciation": "～しつ",
        "back": "counter for room",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～日",
        "pronunciation": "～じつ",
        "back": "day",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～車",
        "pronunciation": "～しゃ",
        "back": "~ car",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～者",
        "pronunciation": "～しゃ",
        "back": "person",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～社",
        "pronunciation": "～しゃ",
        "back": "counter for company",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～手",
        "pronunciation": "～しゅ",
        "back": "~ player, person who does ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～酒",
        "pronunciation": "～しゅ",
        "back": "kind of alcohol",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～集",
        "pronunciation": "～しゅう",
        "back": "collection of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～所",
        "pronunciation": "～しょ",
        "back": "place",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～所",
        "pronunciation": "～じょ",
        "back": "place",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～女",
        "pronunciation": "～じょ",
        "back": "count for sisters",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～省",
        "pronunciation": "～しょう",
        "back": "kind of ministry",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～商",
        "pronunciation": "～しょう",
        "back": "merchant, business",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～勝",
        "pronunciation": "～しょう",
        "back": "count for victory",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～条",
        "pronunciation": "～じょう",
        "back": "counter for article",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～場",
        "pronunciation": "～じょう",
        "back": "kind of field, ground",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～畳",
        "pronunciation": "～じょう",
        "back": "count for tatami, mat",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～色",
        "pronunciation": "～しょく",
        "back": "kind of color",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～過ぎる",
        "pronunciation": "～すぎる",
        "back": "too much ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～済",
        "pronunciation": "～ずみ",
        "back": "finished",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～席",
        "pronunciation": "～せき",
        "back": "counter for seats",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～船",
        "pronunciation": "～せん",
        "back": "counter for ships",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～戦",
        "pronunciation": "～せん",
        "back": "counter for games, matches",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～前",
        "pronunciation": "～ぜん",
        "back": "before ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～沿い",
        "pronunciation": "～そい",
        "back": "along",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～艘",
        "pronunciation": "～そう",
        "back": "counter for ships",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～足",
        "pronunciation": "～そく",
        "back": "counter for shoes",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～だらけ",
        "pronunciation": "～だらけ",
        "back": "be full of ~, be filled with ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～団",
        "pronunciation": "～だん",
        "back": "group, corps, party",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～着",
        "pronunciation": "～ちゃく",
        "back": "counter for clothes; finishing place",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～庁",
        "pronunciation": "～ちょう",
        "back": "office, agency",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～兆",
        "pronunciation": "～ちょう",
        "back": "trillion",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～長",
        "pronunciation": "～ちょう",
        "back": "leader, head",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～帳",
        "pronunciation": "～ちょう",
        "back": "~ book, notebook",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～丁目",
        "pronunciation": "～ちょうめ",
        "back": "~ district (of a town; city, block)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～通",
        "pronunciation": "～つう",
        "back": "counter for letters",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～遣い",
        "pronunciation": "～づかい",
        "back": "use of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～付",
        "pronunciation": "～つき",
        "back": "with ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～続く",
        "pronunciation": "～つづく",
        "back": "follow, continue, go on",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～辛い",
        "pronunciation": "～づらい",
        "back": "hard to do ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～滴",
        "pronunciation": "～てき",
        "back": "drop",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～点",
        "pronunciation": "～てん",
        "back": "counter for scores",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～頭",
        "pronunciation": "～とう",
        "back": "counter for animals",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～等",
        "pronunciation": "～とう",
        "back": "level, place",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～島",
        "pronunciation": "～とう",
        "back": "kind of islands",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～道",
        "pronunciation": "～どう",
        "back": "kind of path, road",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～通り",
        "pronunciation": "～とおり",
        "back": "in accordance with ~; following ~; ~ street, ~ avenue",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～ところ",
        "pronunciation": "～ところ",
        "back": "about to do ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～内",
        "pronunciation": "～ない",
        "back": "inside ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～年生",
        "pronunciation": "～ねんせい",
        "back": "counter for school year",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～泊",
        "pronunciation": "～はく",
        "back": "counter for staying (e.g., 2 nights)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～発",
        "pronunciation": "～はつ",
        "back": "counter for bullets",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～番目",
        "pronunciation": "～ばんめ",
        "back": "~th",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～費",
        "pronunciation": "～ひ",
        "back": "cost of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～病",
        "pronunciation": "～びょう",
        "back": "kind of disease",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～部",
        "pronunciation": "～ぶ",
        "back": "~ part",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～風",
        "pronunciation": "～ふう",
        "back": "~ style",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～振り",
        "pronunciation": "～ぶり",
        "back": "after an interval of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～遍",
        "pronunciation": "～へん",
        "back": "time",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～弁",
        "pronunciation": "～べん",
        "back": "speech, dialect",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～歩",
        "pronunciation": "～ほ",
        "back": "step, pace",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～ぽい",
        "pronunciation": "～ぽい",
        "back": "~ish",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～ほう (ひかく)",
        "pronunciation": "～ほう (ひかく)",
        "back": "(in comparison)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～みたい",
        "pronunciation": "～みたい",
        "back": "looks like ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～向け",
        "pronunciation": "～むけ",
        "back": "for ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～名",
        "pronunciation": "～めい",
        "back": "counter for people",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～もち",
        "pronunciation": "～もち",
        "back": "person who has ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～問",
        "pronunciation": "～もん",
        "back": "counter for questions",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～夜",
        "pronunciation": "～や",
        "back": "counter for nights",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～等",
        "pronunciation": "～ら",
        "back": "plural persons",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～流",
        "pronunciation": "～りゅう",
        "back": "fashion, manner, way",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～料",
        "pronunciation": "～りょう",
        "back": "fare, charge",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～領",
        "pronunciation": "～りょう",
        "back": "territory",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～力",
        "pronunciation": "～りょく",
        "back": "power of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～論",
        "pronunciation": "～ろん",
        "back": "theory",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "～羽",
        "pronunciation": "～わ",
        "back": "counter for rabbits; birds",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "相変わらず",
        "pronunciation": "あいかわらず",
        "back": "as usual, as always, as before, as ever, still",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "アイデア; アイディア",
        "pronunciation": "アイデア; アイディア",
        "back": "idea",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "あいまい",
        "pronunciation": "あいまい",
        "back": "vague, ambiguous",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "扇ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "あおぐ",
        "back": "to fan, to flap",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "青白い",
        "pronunciation": "あおじろい",
        "back": "pale",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "呆れる",
        "pronunciation": "あきれる",
        "back": "to be shocked, to be appalled",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "アクセント",
        "pronunciation": "アクセント",
        "back": "accent",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "あくび",
        "pronunciation": "あくび",
        "back": "yawn",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "飽くまで",
        "pronunciation": "あくまで",
        "back": "to the end, to the last, stubbornly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "明くる～",
        "pronunciation": "あくる～",
        "back": "next, following",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "明け方",
        "pronunciation": "あけがた",
        "back": "dawn",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "憧れる",
        "pronunciation": "あこがれる",
        "back": "to long for, to yearn after",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "朝寝坊",
        "pronunciation": "あさねぼう",
        "back": "oversleeping, late riser",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "足跡",
        "pronunciation": "あしあと",
        "back": "footprint",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "足元",
        "pronunciation": "あしもと",
        "back": "at one's feet",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "味わう",
        "pronunciation": "あじわう",
        "back": "to taste, to savor",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "預かる",
        "pronunciation": "あずかる",
        "back": "to keep in custody, to receive on deposit, to take charge of",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "温まる",
        "pronunciation": "あたたまる",
        "back": "to warm oneself",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "当たり前",
        "pronunciation": "あたりまえ",
        "back": "natural, reasonable, obvious, usual, common, ordinary, commonplace, the norm",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "あちらこちら",
        "pronunciation": "あちらこちら",
        "back": "here and there",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "厚かましい",
        "pronunciation": "あつかましい",
        "back": "impudent, shameless,",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "圧縮",
        "pronunciation": "あっしゅく",
        "back": "compression, condensation, pressure",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "宛名",
        "pronunciation": "あてな",
        "back": "address, direction",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "当てはまる",
        "pronunciation": "あてはまる",
        "back": "to be applicable, to come under (a category)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "当てはめる",
        "pronunciation": "あてはめる",
        "back": "to apply, to adapt",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "暴れる",
        "pronunciation": "あばれる",
        "back": "to act violently, to rage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "脂",
        "pronunciation": "あぶら",
        "back": "fat, tallow, lard",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "あぶる",
        "pronunciation": "あぶる",
        "back": "to scorch, to roast",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "あふれる",
        "pronunciation": "あふれる",
        "back": "to flood, to overflow",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "雨戸",
        "pronunciation": "あまど",
        "back": "sliding storm door",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "甘やかす",
        "pronunciation": "あまやかす",
        "back": "to pamper, to spoil",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "余る",
        "pronunciation": "あまる",
        "back": "to be left over, to be in excess",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "編み物",
        "pronunciation": "あみもの",
        "back": "knitting",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "あみもの",
        "pronunciation": "あみもの",
        "back": "knitting, web",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "編む",
        "pronunciation": "あむ",
        "back": "to knit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "危うい",
        "pronunciation": "あやうい",
        "back": "dangerous, critical",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "怪しい",
        "pronunciation": "あやしい",
        "back": "suspicious, dubious, doubtful",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "荒い",
        "pronunciation": "あらい",
        "back": "rough, rude, wild",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "粗い",
        "pronunciation": "あらい",
        "back": "coarse, rough",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "粗筋",
        "pronunciation": "あらすじ",
        "back": "outline, synopsis",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "争う",
        "pronunciation": "あらそう",
        "back": "to compete, to contest, to contend to quarrel, to argue, to dispute, to be at variance, to oppose",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "改めて",
        "pronunciation": "あらためて",
        "back": "another time, again",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "改める",
        "pronunciation": "あらためる",
        "back": "to change, to reform, to revise",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "あらわす",
        "pronunciation": "あらわす",
        "back": "to write, to publish",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "有難い",
        "pronunciation": "ありがたい",
        "back": "grateful, thankful, appreciated",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "あれこれ",
        "pronunciation": "あれこれ",
        "back": "one thing or another, this and that",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "荒れる",
        "pronunciation": "あれる",
        "back": "to be stormy, to be rough, to be ruined",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "慌ただしい",
        "pronunciation": "あわただしい",
        "back": "busy, hurried",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "慌てる",
        "pronunciation": "あわてる",
        "back": "to become confused (disconcerted, disorganized), to be flustered, to panic, to hurry, to rush, to hasten",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "安易",
        "pronunciation": "あんい",
        "back": "easy-going",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "案外",
        "pronunciation": "あんがい",
        "back": "unexpectedly, surprisingly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "アンテナ",
        "pronunciation": "アンテナ",
        "back": "antenna",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "言い出す",
        "pronunciation": "いいだす",
        "back": "to start talking, to suggest",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "言い付ける",
        "pronunciation": "いいつける",
        "back": "to tell, to order",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "意義",
        "pronunciation": "いぎ",
        "back": "meaning, significance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "生き生き",
        "pronunciation": "いきいき",
        "back": "vividly, lively",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "いきなり",
        "pronunciation": "いきなり",
        "back": "all of a sudden",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "幾～",
        "pronunciation": "いく～",
        "back": "several ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "育児",
        "pronunciation": "いくじ",
        "back": "childcare, nursing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "幾分",
        "pronunciation": "いくぶん",
        "back": "somewhat",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "生け花",
        "pronunciation": "いけばな",
        "back": "flower arrangement",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "以後",
        "pronunciation": "いご",
        "back": "after this; from now on; hereafter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "イコール",
        "pronunciation": "イコール",
        "back": "equal",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "以降",
        "pronunciation": "いこう",
        "back": "on and after, hereafter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "勇ましい",
        "pronunciation": "いさましい",
        "back": "brave, valiant",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "衣食住",
        "pronunciation": "いしょくじゅう",
        "back": "food, clothing and shelter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "いちいち",
        "pronunciation": "いちいち",
        "back": "one by one, separately",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一応",
        "pronunciation": "いちおう",
        "back": "tentatively, for the time being",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一段と",
        "pronunciation": "いちだんと",
        "back": "by far, greater",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一流",
        "pronunciation": "いちりゅう",
        "back": "first class, leading",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一昨日",
        "pronunciation": "いっさくじつ",
        "back": "day before yesterday",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一昨年",
        "pronunciation": "いっさくねん",
        "back": "year before last",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一斉",
        "pronunciation": "いっせい",
        "back": "simultaneous, all at once",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一旦",
        "pronunciation": "いったん",
        "back": "once, for a moment",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一定",
        "pronunciation": "いってい",
        "back": "fixed, settled, regular",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "行っていらっしゃい",
        "pronunciation": "いっていらっしゃい",
        "back": "have a nice day, see you",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "いってきます",
        "pronunciation": "いってきます",
        "back": "(Lit.) I'll go and come back, 'I'm going, see you later'",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "いってまいります",
        "pronunciation": "いってまいります",
        "back": "(Lit.) I'll go and come back, 'I'm going, see you later'",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "行ってらっしゃい",
        "pronunciation": "いってらっしゃい",
        "back": "have a nice day, see you",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "移転",
        "pronunciation": "いてん",
        "back": "moving, transfer",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "井戸",
        "pronunciation": "いど",
        "back": "water well",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "緯度",
        "pronunciation": "いど",
        "back": "latitude (navigation)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "威張る",
        "pronunciation": "いばる",
        "back": "to be proud, to swagger",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "嫌がる",
        "pronunciation": "いやがる",
        "back": "reluctant, to dislike",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "いよいよ",
        "pronunciation": "いよいよ",
        "back": "more and more, increasingly, at last",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "煎る",
        "pronunciation": "いる",
        "back": "to roast",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "炒る",
        "pronunciation": "いる",
        "back": "to parch, to roast",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "入れ物",
        "pronunciation": "いれもの",
        "back": "container, case",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "インキ",
        "pronunciation": "インキ",
        "back": "ink",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引力",
        "pronunciation": "いんりょく",
        "back": "gravity",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ウーマン",
        "pronunciation": "ウーマン",
        "back": "woman",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ウール",
        "pronunciation": "ウール",
        "back": "wool",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ウエートレス",
        "pronunciation": "ウエートレス",
        "back": "waitress",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "植木",
        "pronunciation": "うえき",
        "back": "garden shrubs, trees, potted plant",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "飢える",
        "pronunciation": "うえる",
        "back": "to starve",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "浮ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "うかぶ",
        "back": "to float, to rise to surface, to come to mind",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "浮かべる",
        "pronunciation": "うかべる",
        "back": "to float; to express",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "浮く",
        "pronunciation": "うく",
        "back": "to float",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "承る",
        "pronunciation": "うけたまわる",
        "back": "(humble) to hear, to be told, to know",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "受取",
        "pronunciation": "うけとり",
        "back": "receipt",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "受け持つ",
        "pronunciation": "うけもつ",
        "back": "to take (be in) charge of",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "薄暗い",
        "pronunciation": "うすぐらい",
        "back": "dim, gloomy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "薄める",
        "pronunciation": "うすめる",
        "back": "to dilute, to water down",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "打合せ",
        "pronunciation": "うちあわせ",
        "back": "business meeting, previous arrangement",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "打ち消す",
        "pronunciation": "うちけす",
        "back": "to deny, to negate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "写る",
        "pronunciation": "うつる",
        "back": "to be photographed, to be projected",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "うどん",
        "pronunciation": "うどん",
        "back": "udon noodles (Japanese traditional noodles)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "うなずく",
        "pronunciation": "うなずく",
        "back": "to nod",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "有無",
        "pronunciation": "うむ",
        "back": "existence or nonexistence, presence of absence consent or refusal, yes or no",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "埋める",
        "pronunciation": "うめる",
        "back": "to bury, to fill up, to fill (a seat, a vacant position)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "敬う",
        "pronunciation": "うやまう",
        "back": "to show respect, to honor",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "裏返す",
        "pronunciation": "うらがえす",
        "back": "to turn inside out, to turn (something) over",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "裏口",
        "pronunciation": "うらぐち",
        "back": "backdoor, rear entrance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "占う",
        "pronunciation": "うらなう",
        "back": "to predict, to divine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "恨み",
        "pronunciation": "うらみ",
        "back": "resentment",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "恨む",
        "pronunciation": "うらむ",
        "back": "to curse, to feel bitter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "羨む",
        "pronunciation": "うらやむ",
        "back": "to envy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "売上",
        "pronunciation": "うりあげ",
        "back": "amount sold, proceeds",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "売り上げ",
        "pronunciation": "うりあげ",
        "back": "amount sold, sales, proceeds, takings, turnover",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "売り切れ",
        "pronunciation": "うりきれ",
        "back": "sold-out",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "売り切れる",
        "pronunciation": "うりきれる",
        "back": "to be sold out",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "売行き",
        "pronunciation": "うれゆき",
        "back": "sales",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "売れ行き",
        "pronunciation": "うれゆき",
        "back": "sales, demand",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "うろうろ",
        "pronunciation": "うろうろ",
        "back": "loitering, aimless wandering",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "上～",
        "pronunciation": "うわ～",
        "back": "upper ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "運河",
        "pronunciation": "うんが",
        "back": "canal, waterway",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "うんと",
        "pronunciation": "うんと",
        "back": "a great deal, very much",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "英文",
        "pronunciation": "えいぶん",
        "back": "sentence in English",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "英和",
        "pronunciation": "えいわ",
        "back": "English-Japanese (e.g., dictionary)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ええと",
        "pronunciation": "ええと",
        "back": "let me see, well, er...",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "液体",
        "pronunciation": "えきたい",
        "back": "liquid, fluid",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "エチケット",
        "pronunciation": "エチケット",
        "back": "etiquette",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "絵の具",
        "pronunciation": "えのぐ",
        "back": "colors, paints",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "エプロン",
        "pronunciation": "エプロン",
        "back": "apron",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "偉い",
        "pronunciation": "えらい",
        "back": "great, celebrated, remarkable,",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "宴会",
        "pronunciation": "えんかい",
        "back": "party, banquet",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "園芸",
        "pronunciation": "えんげい",
        "back": "horticulture, gardening",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "演劇",
        "pronunciation": "えんげき",
        "back": "play (theatrical)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "円周",
        "pronunciation": "えんしゅう",
        "back": "circumference",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "遠足",
        "pronunciation": "えんそく",
        "back": "trip, hike, picnic",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "延長",
        "pronunciation": "えんちょう",
        "back": "extension, prolongation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "煙突",
        "pronunciation": "えんとつ",
        "back": "chimney",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "オーケストラ",
        "pronunciation": "オーケストラ",
        "back": "orchestra",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "オートメーション",
        "pronunciation": "オートメーション",
        "back": "automation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "追いかける",
        "pronunciation": "おいかける",
        "back": "to chase or run after someone",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "追い越す",
        "pronunciation": "おいこす",
        "back": "to pass (e.g., car), to outdistance, to outstrip",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "オイル",
        "pronunciation": "オイル",
        "back": "oil",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "応援",
        "pronunciation": "おうえん",
        "back": "aid, assistance, help, support, reinforcement cheering, rooting (for), support",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "王女",
        "pronunciation": "おうじょ",
        "back": "princess",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "応ずる",
        "pronunciation": "おうずる",
        "back": "to respond, to comply with",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "応接",
        "pronunciation": "おうせつ",
        "back": "reception",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "応対",
        "pronunciation": "おうたい",
        "back": "receiving, dealing with",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "往復",
        "pronunciation": "おうふく",
        "back": "(col) round trip, coming and going, return ticket",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "欧米",
        "pronunciation": "おうべい",
        "back": "Europe and America, the West",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "応用",
        "pronunciation": "おうよう",
        "back": "application, put to practical use",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "おおざっぱ",
        "pronunciation": "おおざっぱ",
        "back": "rough (not precise), broad, sketchy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "大通り",
        "pronunciation": "おおどおり",
        "back": "main street",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "大凡",
        "pronunciation": "おおよそ",
        "back": "about, approximately",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お帰り",
        "pronunciation": "おかえり",
        "back": "return, welcome",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "おかけください",
        "pronunciation": "おかけください",
        "back": "please sit down",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "おかげさまで",
        "pronunciation": "おかげさまで",
        "back": "Thanks to god, thanks to you",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "おかず",
        "pronunciation": "おかず",
        "back": "side dish, accompaniment for rice dishes",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "おかまいなく",
        "pronunciation": "おかまいなく",
        "back": "please don't fuss over me",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "拝む",
        "pronunciation": "おがむ",
        "back": "to worship, to pray",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お代わり",
        "pronunciation": "おかわり",
        "back": "second helping, another cup",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "補う",
        "pronunciation": "おぎなう",
        "back": "to compensate for",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お気の毒に",
        "pronunciation": "おきのどくに",
        "back": "I'm sorry to hear that…",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "屋外",
        "pronunciation": "おくがい",
        "back": "outdoors",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "送り仮名",
        "pronunciation": "おくりがな",
        "back": "part of word written in kana",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お元気で",
        "pronunciation": "おげんきで",
        "back": "Take care'",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "怠る",
        "pronunciation": "おこたる",
        "back": "to neglect, to fail",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "押さえる",
        "pronunciation": "おさえる",
        "back": "to pin down, to hold down, to press down, to hold in place, to hold steady to cover (esp. a part of one's body with one's hand), to clutch (a body part in pain), to press (a body part) to get a hold of, to obtain, to seize, to catch, to arrest",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お先に",
        "pronunciation": "おさきに",
        "back": "before, after you",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "伯父",
        "pronunciation": "おじ",
        "back": "(humble) uncle (older than one's parent)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "叔父",
        "pronunciation": "おじ",
        "back": "uncle (younger than one's parent)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "惜しい",
        "pronunciation": "おしい",
        "back": "regrettable, disappointing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "伯父さん",
        "pronunciation": "おじさん",
        "back": "(hon.) middle-aged gentleman, uncle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "小父さん",
        "pronunciation": "おじさん",
        "back": "(hon.) middle-aged gentleman, uncle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "叔父さん",
        "pronunciation": "おじさん",
        "back": "(hon.) middle-aged gentleman, uncle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お邪魔します",
        "pronunciation": "おじゃまします",
        "back": "Excuse me for disturbing you",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お世話になりました",
        "pronunciation": "おせわになりました",
        "back": "I've been in your care",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お大事に",
        "pronunciation": "おだいじに",
        "back": "Take care of yourself, Take care!, Get well soon",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "落着く",
        "pronunciation": "おちつく",
        "back": "to calm down, to settle down",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お出掛け",
        "pronunciation": "おでかけ",
        "back": "outing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お手伝いさん",
        "pronunciation": "おてつだいさん",
        "back": "maid",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "脅かす",
        "pronunciation": "おどかす",
        "back": "to threaten, to coerce",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "落し物",
        "pronunciation": "おとしもの",
        "back": "lost property",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "驚かす",
        "pronunciation": "おどろかす",
        "back": "to surprise, to frighten",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お願いします",
        "pronunciation": "おねがいします",
        "back": "Please (lit., I request)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "各々",
        "pronunciation": "おのおの",
        "back": "each, every, either",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "伯母",
        "pronunciation": "おば",
        "back": "(humble) aunt (older than one's parent)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "叔母",
        "pronunciation": "おば",
        "back": "aunt (younger than one's parent)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "小母さん",
        "pronunciation": "おばさん",
        "back": "lady, woman, ma'am",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "おはよう",
        "pronunciation": "おはよう",
        "back": "(abbr.) Good morning",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お参り",
        "pronunciation": "おまいり",
        "back": "worship, shrine visit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お待たせしました",
        "pronunciation": "おまたせしました",
        "back": "Sorry to have kept you waiting",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お待ちください",
        "pronunciation": "おまちください",
        "back": "Please wait a moment",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "おまちどおさま",
        "pronunciation": "おまちどおさま",
        "back": "Sorry to have kept you waiting",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "おめでたい",
        "pronunciation": "おめでたい",
        "back": "happy event, matter for congratulation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "思い掛けない",
        "pronunciation": "おもいがけない",
        "back": "unexpected, casual",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "思い切り",
        "pronunciation": "おもいきり",
        "back": "with all one's strength (heart), resignation, resolution",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "思い込む",
        "pronunciation": "おもいこむ",
        "back": "to be under impression that, to be convinced that",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "思いっ切り",
        "pronunciation": "おもいっきり",
        "back": "very, much, fully",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "思いっきり",
        "pronunciation": "おもいっきり",
        "back": "to the best of one's ability",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "重たい",
        "pronunciation": "おもたい",
        "back": "heavy, massive, serious",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "お休み",
        "pronunciation": "おやすみ",
        "back": "holiday, absence; (exp.) Good night",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "おやつ",
        "pronunciation": "おやつ",
        "back": "between meal snack, afternoon refreshment",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "親指",
        "pronunciation": "おやゆび",
        "back": "thumb",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "オルガン",
        "pronunciation": "オルガン",
        "back": "organ",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "御～",
        "pronunciation": "おん～",
        "back": "honorific ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "恩恵",
        "pronunciation": "おんけい",
        "back": "blessing, benefit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "温室",
        "pronunciation": "おんしつ",
        "back": "greenhouse",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "温泉",
        "pronunciation": "おんせん",
        "back": "spa, hot spring",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "温帯",
        "pronunciation": "おんたい",
        "back": "temperate zone",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "御中",
        "pronunciation": "おんちゅう",
        "back": "Messrs.",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "女の人",
        "pronunciation": "おんなのひと",
        "back": "woman",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "蚊",
        "pronunciation": "か",
        "back": "mosquito",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "カーブ",
        "pronunciation": "カーブ",
        "back": "curve; curve ball (baseball)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "貝",
        "pronunciation": "かい",
        "back": "shell, shellfish",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "外～",
        "pronunciation": "がい～",
        "back": "foreign ~, outside ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "開会",
        "pronunciation": "かいかい",
        "back": "opening of a meeting",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "会館",
        "pronunciation": "かいかん",
        "back": "meeting hall, assembly hall",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "改札",
        "pronunciation": "かいさつ",
        "back": "examination of tickets",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "解散",
        "pronunciation": "かいさん",
        "back": "breakup, dissolution",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "海水浴",
        "pronunciation": "かいすいよく",
        "back": "sea bathing, seawater bath",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "回数",
        "pronunciation": "かいすう",
        "back": "number of times, frequency",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "回数券",
        "pronunciation": "かいすうけん",
        "back": "book of tickets",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "改正",
        "pronunciation": "かいせい",
        "back": "revision, amendment, alteration",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "快晴",
        "pronunciation": "かいせい",
        "back": "good weather",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "解説",
        "pronunciation": "かいせつ",
        "back": "explanation, commentary",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "改造",
        "pronunciation": "かいぞう",
        "back": "remodeling",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "開通",
        "pronunciation": "かいつう",
        "back": "opening, open",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "回転",
        "pronunciation": "かいてん",
        "back": "rotation, turning",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "解答",
        "pronunciation": "かいとう",
        "back": "answer, solution",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "回答",
        "pronunciation": "かいとう",
        "back": "reply, answer",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "外部",
        "pronunciation": "がいぶ",
        "back": "the outside, external",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "解放",
        "pronunciation": "かいほう",
        "back": "release, liberation, emancipation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "開放",
        "pronunciation": "かいほう",
        "back": "open, throw open, liberalization",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "海洋",
        "pronunciation": "かいよう",
        "back": "ocean",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "概論",
        "pronunciation": "がいろん",
        "back": "introduction, general remark",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "却って",
        "pronunciation": "かえって",
        "back": "on the contrary, rather",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "家屋",
        "pronunciation": "かおく",
        "back": "house, building",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "係わる",
        "pronunciation": "かかわる",
        "back": "to concern oneself in, to be involved in",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "書留",
        "pronunciation": "かきとめ",
        "back": "registered mail",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "書取",
        "pronunciation": "かきとり",
        "back": "dictation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "垣根",
        "pronunciation": "かきね",
        "back": "hedge",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "限り",
        "pronunciation": "かぎり",
        "back": "limit(s), as far as possible",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "各～",
        "pronunciation": "かく～",
        "back": "every ~, each ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "架空",
        "pronunciation": "かくう",
        "back": "imaginary, fiction, fanciful",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "各自",
        "pronunciation": "かくじ",
        "back": "individual, each",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "拡充",
        "pronunciation": "かくじゅう",
        "back": "expansion",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "学術",
        "pronunciation": "がくじゅつ",
        "back": "science, learning, scholarship",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "各地",
        "pronunciation": "かくち",
        "back": "various parts of the country",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "拡張",
        "pronunciation": "かくちょう",
        "back": "expansion, extension",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "角度",
        "pronunciation": "かくど",
        "back": "angle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "学年",
        "pronunciation": "がくねん",
        "back": "year in school, grade in school",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "学部",
        "pronunciation": "がくぶ",
        "back": "department of a university undergraduate (course, program, etc.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "格別",
        "pronunciation": "かくべつ",
        "back": "exceptional",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "確率",
        "pronunciation": "かくりつ",
        "back": "probability",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "学力",
        "pronunciation": "がくりょく",
        "back": "scholarship, knowledge",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "掛け算",
        "pronunciation": "かけざん",
        "back": "multiplication",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "かけざん",
        "pronunciation": "かけざん",
        "back": "multiplication",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "可決",
        "pronunciation": "かけつ",
        "back": "approval, adoption (e.g., motion, bill), passage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "火口",
        "pronunciation": "かこう",
        "back": "crater (of a volcano)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "下降",
        "pronunciation": "かこう",
        "back": "decline, descent, fall",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "重ねる",
        "pronunciation": "かさねる",
        "back": "to pile up, to heap up, to stack up, to put on top of another to repeat many times over, to go through repeatedly, to accumulate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "飾り",
        "pronunciation": "かざり",
        "back": "decoration, ornament, trimmings",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "火山",
        "pronunciation": "かざん",
        "back": "volcano",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "かしこまりました",
        "pronunciation": "かしこまりました",
        "back": "Certainly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "貸し出し",
        "pronunciation": "かしだし",
        "back": "lending, loaning",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "過失",
        "pronunciation": "かしつ",
        "back": "error, mistake, negligence",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "果実",
        "pronunciation": "かじつ",
        "back": "fruit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "貸間",
        "pronunciation": "かしま",
        "back": "room to let",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "貸家",
        "pronunciation": "かしや",
        "back": "house for rent",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "箇所",
        "pronunciation": "かしょ",
        "back": "place, point, part",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "かしょ",
        "pronunciation": "かしょ",
        "back": "passage, place",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "過剰",
        "pronunciation": "かじょう",
        "back": "excess, over-",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "かじる",
        "pronunciation": "かじる",
        "back": "to chew, to bite (at)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "課税",
        "pronunciation": "かぜい",
        "back": "taxation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "カセット",
        "pronunciation": "カセット",
        "back": "cassette (tape)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "下線",
        "pronunciation": "かせん",
        "back": "underline, underscore",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "加速",
        "pronunciation": "かそく",
        "back": "acceleration",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "加速度",
        "pronunciation": "かそくど",
        "back": "acceleration",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "かたかな",
        "pronunciation": "かたかな",
        "back": "katakana",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "かたづく",
        "pronunciation": "かたづく",
        "back": "to put in order, to dispose of, to solve",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "塊",
        "pronunciation": "かたまり",
        "back": "lump, mass, cluster",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "固まる",
        "pronunciation": "かたまる",
        "back": "to harden, to solidify, to become firm",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "片道",
        "pronunciation": "かたみち",
        "back": "one-way (trip)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "傾く",
        "pronunciation": "かたむく",
        "back": "to incline toward, to slant, to lurch",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "片寄る",
        "pronunciation": "かたよる",
        "back": "to be one-sided, to incline, to be partial",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "学科",
        "pronunciation": "がっか",
        "back": "study subject, course of study",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "学会",
        "pronunciation": "がっかい",
        "back": "academic conference",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "楽器",
        "pronunciation": "がっき",
        "back": "musical instrument",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "学級",
        "pronunciation": "がっきゅう",
        "back": "class",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "担ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "かつぐ",
        "back": "to shoulder, to carry on shoulder",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "括弧",
        "pronunciation": "かっこ",
        "back": "parenthesis, brackets",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "活字",
        "pronunciation": "かつじ",
        "back": "printing type",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "勝手に",
        "pronunciation": "かってに",
        "back": "arbitrarily,",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "活躍",
        "pronunciation": "かつやく",
        "back": "activity (esp. energetic or successful), great efforts, active participation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "活力",
        "pronunciation": "かつりょく",
        "back": "vitality, energy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "課程",
        "pronunciation": "かてい",
        "back": "course, curriculum",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "仮名",
        "pronunciation": "かな",
        "back": "kana",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "仮名遣い",
        "pronunciation": "かなづかい",
        "back": "kana orthography, syllabary spelling",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "鐘",
        "pronunciation": "かね",
        "back": "bell (often a large hanging bell), chime",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "加熱",
        "pronunciation": "かねつ",
        "back": "heating",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "兼ねる",
        "pronunciation": "かねる",
        "back": "to simultaneously serve two or more functions",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "カバー",
        "pronunciation": "カバー",
        "back": "cover (e.g., book)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "過半数",
        "pronunciation": "かはんすう",
        "back": "majority",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "かび (～がはえる)",
        "pronunciation": "かび (～がはえる)",
        "back": "mold, mildew",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "被せる",
        "pronunciation": "かぶせる",
        "back": "to cover (with something)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "釜",
        "pronunciation": "かま",
        "back": "iron pot, kettle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "構いません",
        "pronunciation": "かまいません",
        "back": "it's all right; one doesn’t mind",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "紙屑",
        "pronunciation": "かみくず",
        "back": "wastepaper",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "神様",
        "pronunciation": "かみさま",
        "back": "god",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "剃刀",
        "pronunciation": "かみそり",
        "back": "razor",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ガム",
        "pronunciation": "ガム",
        "back": "chewing gum",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "貨物",
        "pronunciation": "かもつ",
        "back": "cargo, freight",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "歌謡",
        "pronunciation": "かよう",
        "back": "song, ballad",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "殻",
        "pronunciation": "から",
        "back": "shell, husk, hull, pod, chaff",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "カラー",
        "pronunciation": "カラー",
        "back": "collar, color",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "からかう",
        "pronunciation": "からかう",
        "back": "to ridicule, to make fun of",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "空っぽ",
        "pronunciation": "からっぽ",
        "back": "empty, vacant, hollow",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "かるた",
        "pronunciation": "かるた",
        "back": "playing cards (POR: carta)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "枯れる",
        "pronunciation": "かれる",
        "back": "to wither, to die (plant), to be blasted (plant)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "カロリー",
        "pronunciation": "カロリー",
        "back": "calorie",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "可愛がる",
        "pronunciation": "かわいがる",
        "back": "to love, to be affectionate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "乾かす",
        "pronunciation": "かわかす",
        "back": "to dry (clothes, etc.), to desiccate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "為替",
        "pronunciation": "かわせ",
        "back": "money order, exchange",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "瓦",
        "pronunciation": "かわら",
        "back": "roof tile",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "間隔",
        "pronunciation": "かんかく",
        "back": "space, interval space character, whitespace",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "換気",
        "pronunciation": "かんき",
        "back": "ventilation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "感激",
        "pronunciation": "かんげき",
        "back": "deep emotion, impression, inspiration",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "関西",
        "pronunciation": "かんさい",
        "back": "south-western half of Japan, including Osaka",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "元日",
        "pronunciation": "がんじつ",
        "back": "New Year's Day",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "鑑賞",
        "pronunciation": "かんしょう",
        "back": "appreciation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "感ずる",
        "pronunciation": "かんずる",
        "back": "to feel, to sense",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "間接",
        "pronunciation": "かんせつ",
        "back": "indirect, indirectness",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "乾燥",
        "pronunciation": "かんそう",
        "back": "dry, arid, insipid, dehydrated",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "感想",
        "pronunciation": "かんそう",
        "back": "impressions, thoughts, feelings, reactions",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "観測",
        "pronunciation": "かんそく",
        "back": "observation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "寒帯",
        "pronunciation": "かんたい",
        "back": "frigid zone",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "勘違い",
        "pronunciation": "かんちがい",
        "back": "misunderstanding, wrong guess",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "官庁",
        "pronunciation": "かんちょう",
        "back": "government office, authorities",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "缶詰",
        "pronunciation": "かんづめ",
        "back": "canning, canned goods,",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "乾電池",
        "pronunciation": "かんでんち",
        "back": "dry cell, battery",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "関東",
        "pronunciation": "かんとう",
        "back": "eastern half of Japan, including Tokyo",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "観念",
        "pronunciation": "かんねん",
        "back": "idea, notion; sense",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "乾杯",
        "pronunciation": "かんぱい",
        "back": "Cheers! (a toast)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "看板",
        "pronunciation": "かんばん",
        "back": "sign, signboard",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "看病",
        "pronunciation": "かんびょう",
        "back": "nursing (a patient)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "冠",
        "pronunciation": "かんむり",
        "back": "crown, wreath",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "漢和",
        "pronunciation": "かんわ",
        "back": "Chinese Character-Japanese (e.g., dictionary)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "気圧",
        "pronunciation": "きあつ",
        "back": "atmospheric pressure",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "着替え",
        "pronunciation": "きがえ",
        "back": "changing clothes, change of clothes",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "着替える",
        "pronunciation": "きがえる",
        "back": "to change (one's) clothes",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "機関車",
        "pronunciation": "きかんしゃ",
        "back": "locomotive, engine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "飢饉",
        "pronunciation": "ききん",
        "back": "famine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "器具",
        "pronunciation": "きぐ",
        "back": "instrument",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "期限",
        "pronunciation": "きげん",
        "back": "term, period, time frame time limit, deadline, cutoff (date)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "記号",
        "pronunciation": "きごう",
        "back": "symbol, code",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "刻む",
        "pronunciation": "きざむ",
        "back": "to mince, to carve, to engrave",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "儀式",
        "pronunciation": "ぎしき",
        "back": "ceremony, rite, ritual",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "基準",
        "pronunciation": "きじゅん",
        "back": "standard, basis, criteria",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "規準",
        "pronunciation": "きじゅん",
        "back": "standard, basis, criteria",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "起床",
        "pronunciation": "きしょう",
        "back": "rising, getting out of bed",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "着せる",
        "pronunciation": "きせる",
        "back": "to put on clothes",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "基礎",
        "pronunciation": "きそ",
        "back": "foundation, basis",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "基地",
        "pronunciation": "きち",
        "back": "base",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "きっかけ",
        "pronunciation": "きっかけ",
        "back": "prompt, trigger, cue",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "切っ掛け",
        "pronunciation": "きっかけ",
        "back": "chance, start, cue, excuse, motive, impetus, occassion",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぎっしり",
        "pronunciation": "ぎっしり",
        "back": "tightly, fully",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "基盤",
        "pronunciation": "きばん",
        "back": "foundation, basis",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "客席",
        "pronunciation": "きゃくせき",
        "back": "guest seating",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "客間",
        "pronunciation": "きゃくま",
        "back": "parlor, guest room",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ギャング",
        "pronunciation": "ギャング",
        "back": "gang",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "キャンパス",
        "pronunciation": "キャンパス",
        "back": "campus",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "休業",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうぎょう",
        "back": "closure, shutdown, holiday",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "休講",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうこう",
        "back": "lecture canceled",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "休息",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうそく",
        "back": "rest, relief, relaxation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "給与",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうよ",
        "back": "salary",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "休養",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうよう",
        "back": "rest, break, recreation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "清い",
        "pronunciation": "きよい",
        "back": "clear, pure, noble",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "強化",
        "pronunciation": "きょうか",
        "back": "strengthen, intensify, reinforce",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "境界",
        "pronunciation": "きょうかい",
        "back": "boundary",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "共産～",
        "pronunciation": "きょうさん～",
        "back": "communist ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "行事",
        "pronunciation": "ぎょうじ",
        "back": "event, function",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "恐縮",
        "pronunciation": "きょうしゅく",
        "back": "sorry to trouble",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "教養",
        "pronunciation": "きょうよう",
        "back": "culture, education, sophistication",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "行列",
        "pronunciation": "ぎょうれつ",
        "back": "line, procession; matrix (math)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "漁業",
        "pronunciation": "ぎょぎょう",
        "back": "fishing (industry)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "曲線",
        "pronunciation": "きょくせん",
        "back": "curve",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "規律",
        "pronunciation": "きりつ",
        "back": "order, rules, law",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "斬る",
        "pronunciation": "きる",
        "back": "to behead, to murder",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "気を付ける",
        "pronunciation": "きをつける",
        "back": "to be careful, to pay attention, to take care",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "琴",
        "pronunciation": "きん",
        "back": "13-string Japanese zither",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "金魚",
        "pronunciation": "きんぎょ",
        "back": "goldfish",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "クーラー",
        "pronunciation": "クーラー",
        "back": "air conditioner",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "区域",
        "pronunciation": "くいき",
        "back": "zone, district, area",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "空～",
        "pronunciation": "くう～",
        "back": "empty ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "偶数",
        "pronunciation": "ぐうすう",
        "back": "even number",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "空想",
        "pronunciation": "くうそう",
        "back": "daydream, fantasy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "空中",
        "pronunciation": "くうちゅう",
        "back": "sky, air",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "釘",
        "pronunciation": "くぎ",
        "back": "nail",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "区切る",
        "pronunciation": "くぎる",
        "back": "to punctuate, to cut off, to mark off",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "櫛",
        "pronunciation": "くし",
        "back": "comb",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "くしゃみ",
        "pronunciation": "くしゃみ",
        "back": "sneeze",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "苦情",
        "pronunciation": "くじょう",
        "back": "complaint, grievance, grumble",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "苦心",
        "pronunciation": "くしん",
        "back": "pain, trouble",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "屑",
        "pronunciation": "くず",
        "back": "waste, scrap",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "崩す",
        "pronunciation": "くずす",
        "back": "to destroy, to make change (money)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "薬指",
        "pronunciation": "くすりゆび",
        "back": "ring finger",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "崩れる",
        "pronunciation": "くずれる",
        "back": "to collapse, to crumble",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "砕く",
        "pronunciation": "くだく",
        "back": "to break, to smash",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "砕ける",
        "pronunciation": "くだける",
        "back": "to break, to be broken",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "くたびれる",
        "pronunciation": "くたびれる",
        "back": "to get tired, to wear out",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "くだらない",
        "pronunciation": "くだらない",
        "back": "good-for-nothing, stupid, worthless",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "下る",
        "pronunciation": "くだる",
        "back": "to descend, to go down, to come down",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "唇",
        "pronunciation": "くちびる",
        "back": "lip",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "口紅",
        "pronunciation": "くちべに",
        "back": "lipstick",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "くっつく",
        "pronunciation": "くっつく",
        "back": "to adhere to, to keep close to",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "くっつける",
        "pronunciation": "くっつける",
        "back": "to attach",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "くどい",
        "pronunciation": "くどい",
        "back": "verbose, importunate, heavy (taste)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "句読点",
        "pronunciation": "くとうてん",
        "back": "punctuation marks",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "配る",
        "pronunciation": "くばる",
        "back": "to distribute, to deliver",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "工夫",
        "pronunciation": "くふう",
        "back": "device, artifice, ingenuity",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "区分",
        "pronunciation": "くぶん",
        "back": "division, section, classification",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "組合せ",
        "pronunciation": "くみあわせ",
        "back": "combination",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "組み立てる",
        "pronunciation": "くみたてる",
        "back": "to assemble, to set up, to construct",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "悔やむ",
        "pronunciation": "くやむ",
        "back": "to regret, to mourn",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "クリーニング",
        "pronunciation": "クリーニング",
        "back": "cleaning, dry cleaning, laundry service",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "くるむ",
        "pronunciation": "くるむ",
        "back": "to be enveloped by, to wrap up",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "くれぐれも",
        "pronunciation": "くれぐれも",
        "back": "repeatedly, sincerely, earnestly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "郡",
        "pronunciation": "ぐん",
        "back": "district, county",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "稽古",
        "pronunciation": "けいこ",
        "back": "practice, training, study",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "敬語",
        "pronunciation": "けいご",
        "back": "honorific language (lit., respect language)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "蛍光灯",
        "pronunciation": "けいこうとう",
        "back": "fluorescent lamp",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "形式",
        "pronunciation": "けいしき",
        "back": "form, formality, format",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "継続",
        "pronunciation": "けいぞく",
        "back": "continuation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "毛糸",
        "pronunciation": "けいと",
        "back": "knitting wool",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "経度",
        "pronunciation": "けいど",
        "back": "longitude",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "系統",
        "pronunciation": "けいとう",
        "back": "system, genealogy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "芸能",
        "pronunciation": "げいのう",
        "back": "public entertainment, performing arts",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "競馬",
        "pronunciation": "けいば",
        "back": "horse racing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "警備",
        "pronunciation": "けいび",
        "back": "defense, guard, policing, security",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "形容詞",
        "pronunciation": "けいようし",
        "back": "adjective",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "形容動詞",
        "pronunciation": "けいようどうし",
        "back": "adjectival noun, quasi-adjective",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "外科",
        "pronunciation": "げか",
        "back": "surgical department",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "毛皮",
        "pronunciation": "けがわ",
        "back": "fur, skin, pelt",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "激増",
        "pronunciation": "げきぞう",
        "back": "sudden increase",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "下車",
        "pronunciation": "げしゃ",
        "back": "alighting, getting off",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "下旬",
        "pronunciation": "げじゅん",
        "back": "month (last third of)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "下水",
        "pronunciation": "げすい",
        "back": "drainage, sewage, ditch, gutter, sewerage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "削る",
        "pronunciation": "けずる",
        "back": "to cut down little by little, to take a percentage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "桁",
        "pronunciation": "けた",
        "back": "column, beam, digit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "下駄",
        "pronunciation": "げた",
        "back": "(Japanese footwear), wooden clogs",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "血圧",
        "pronunciation": "けつあつ",
        "back": "blood pressure",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "月給",
        "pronunciation": "げっきゅう",
        "back": "monthly salary",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "傑作",
        "pronunciation": "けっさく",
        "back": "masterpiece, best work",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "月末",
        "pronunciation": "げつまつ",
        "back": "end of the month",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "気配",
        "pronunciation": "けはい",
        "back": "indication, sign, hint",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "下品",
        "pronunciation": "げひん",
        "back": "vulgar, indecent, coarse",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "下品(な)",
        "pronunciation": "げひん(な)",
        "back": "vulgar",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "煙い",
        "pronunciation": "けむい",
        "back": "smoky",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "険しい",
        "pronunciation": "けわしい",
        "back": "steep, rugged; severe",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "現～",
        "pronunciation": "げん～",
        "back": "present, incumbent",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "見学",
        "pronunciation": "けんがく",
        "back": "tour, study by observation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "謙虚",
        "pronunciation": "けんきょ",
        "back": "modesty, humble",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "原稿",
        "pronunciation": "げんこう",
        "back": "manuscript, copy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "原産",
        "pronunciation": "げんさん",
        "back": "place of origin",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "原始",
        "pronunciation": "げんし",
        "back": "origin, primeval",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "研修",
        "pronunciation": "けんしゅう",
        "back": "training",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "厳重",
        "pronunciation": "げんじゅう",
        "back": "strict, severe, firm",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "謙遜",
        "pronunciation": "けんそん",
        "back": "humble, humility, modesty",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "県庁",
        "pronunciation": "けんちょう",
        "back": "prefectural office",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "限度",
        "pronunciation": "げんど",
        "back": "limit, bounds",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "現に",
        "pronunciation": "げんに",
        "back": "actually, really",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "顕微鏡",
        "pronunciation": "けんびきょう",
        "back": "microscope",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "懸命",
        "pronunciation": "けんめい",
        "back": "eagerness, strenuous",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "原理",
        "pronunciation": "げんり",
        "back": "principle, theory, fundamental truth",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "原料",
        "pronunciation": "げんりょう",
        "back": "raw materials",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "碁",
        "pronunciation": "ご",
        "back": "go (board game)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "小～",
        "pronunciation": "こ～",
        "back": "small ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "コース",
        "pronunciation": "コース",
        "back": "course",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "コーラス",
        "pronunciation": "コーラス",
        "back": "chorus",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "恋しい",
        "pronunciation": "こいしい",
        "back": "dear, beloved; to miss",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "高～",
        "pronunciation": "こう～",
        "back": "high (level) ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "工員",
        "pronunciation": "こういん",
        "back": "factory worker",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "強引",
        "pronunciation": "ごういん",
        "back": "forcible, assertive, pushy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "公害",
        "pronunciation": "こうがい",
        "back": "public nuisance, pollution",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "高級",
        "pronunciation": "こうきゅう",
        "back": "high class; first-rate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "公共",
        "pronunciation": "こうきょう",
        "back": "public, community, communal",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "工芸",
        "pronunciation": "こうげい",
        "back": "industrial arts",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "孝行",
        "pronunciation": "こうこう",
        "back": "filial piety",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "交差",
        "pronunciation": "こうさ",
        "back": "cross",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "講師",
        "pronunciation": "こうし",
        "back": "lecturer",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "工事",
        "pronunciation": "こうじ",
        "back": "construction work",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "公式",
        "pronunciation": "こうしき",
        "back": "formula, formality, official",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "口実",
        "pronunciation": "こうじつ",
        "back": "excuse",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "こうして",
        "pronunciation": "こうして",
        "back": "like this, with this",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "校舎",
        "pronunciation": "こうしゃ",
        "back": "school building, schoolhouse",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "公衆",
        "pronunciation": "こうしゅう",
        "back": "the public",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "香水",
        "pronunciation": "こうすい",
        "back": "perfume",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "公正",
        "pronunciation": "こうせい",
        "back": "justice, fairness, impartiality",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "功績",
        "pronunciation": "こうせき",
        "back": "achievements, merit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "光線",
        "pronunciation": "こうせん",
        "back": "beam, light ray",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "高層",
        "pronunciation": "こうそう",
        "back": "tall, high rise",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "構造",
        "pronunciation": "こうぞう",
        "back": "structure, construction",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "交替",
        "pronunciation": "こうたい",
        "back": "change, relief, alteration",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "交代",
        "pronunciation": "こうたい",
        "back": "alternation, change, relief, relay, shift, substitution (sports, etc.), taking turns",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "耕地",
        "pronunciation": "こうち",
        "back": "arable land",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "交通機関",
        "pronunciation": "こうつうきかん",
        "back": "transportation facilities",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "校庭",
        "pronunciation": "こうてい",
        "back": "school yard",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "肯定",
        "pronunciation": "こうてい",
        "back": "positive, affirmation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "高度",
        "pronunciation": "こうど",
        "back": "altitude, height; advanced",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "高等",
        "pronunciation": "こうとう",
        "back": "high class, high grade",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "合同",
        "pronunciation": "ごうどう",
        "back": "combination, incorporation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "高等学校",
        "pronunciation": "こうとうがっこう",
        "back": "senior high school",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "公表",
        "pronunciation": "こうひょう",
        "back": "official announcement, proclamation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉱物",
        "pronunciation": "こうぶつ",
        "back": "mineral",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "公務",
        "pronunciation": "こうむ",
        "back": "official business, public business",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "項目",
        "pronunciation": "こうもく",
        "back": "item",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "紅葉",
        "pronunciation": "こうよう",
        "back": "fall colors (of leaves)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "こうよう もみじ",
        "pronunciation": "こうよう もみじ",
        "back": "(Japanese) maple",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "合理",
        "pronunciation": "ごうり",
        "back": "rational",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "交流",
        "pronunciation": "こうりゅう",
        "back": "exchange; alternating current",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "合流",
        "pronunciation": "ごうりゅう",
        "back": "confluence, merge, join",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "効力",
        "pronunciation": "こうりょく",
        "back": "effect, efficacy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "焦がす",
        "pronunciation": "こがす",
        "back": "to burn, to scorch",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "国王",
        "pronunciation": "こくおう",
        "back": "king",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "こくせき",
        "pronunciation": "こくせき",
        "back": "nationality",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "国立",
        "pronunciation": "こくりつ",
        "back": "national",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ご苦労様",
        "pronunciation": "ごくろうさま",
        "back": "Thank you for your hard work",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "焦げる",
        "pronunciation": "こげる",
        "back": "to burn, to be burned",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "凍える",
        "pronunciation": "こごえる",
        "back": "to freeze, to be chilled, to be frozen",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "心当たり",
        "pronunciation": "こころあたり",
        "back": "having some knowledge of, happening to know",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "心得る",
        "pronunciation": "こころえる",
        "back": "to understand, to have thorough knowledge",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "腰掛け",
        "pronunciation": "こしかけ",
        "back": "seat, bench",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "腰掛",
        "pronunciation": "こしかけ",
        "back": "seat, bench",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "腰掛ける",
        "pronunciation": "こしかける",
        "back": "to sit (down)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "五十音",
        "pronunciation": "ごじゅうおん",
        "back": "the Japanese syllabary",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "こしらえる",
        "pronunciation": "こしらえる",
        "back": "to make, to manufacture",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "擦る",
        "pronunciation": "こする",
        "back": "to rub, to chafe, to file, to frost (glass), to strike (match)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "個体",
        "pronunciation": "こたい",
        "back": "an individual",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ごちそうさま",
        "pronunciation": "ごちそうさま",
        "back": "Thank you for the meal",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "こちらこそ",
        "pronunciation": "こちらこそ",
        "back": "it is I who should say so",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "小遣い",
        "pronunciation": "こづかい",
        "back": "pocket money, allowance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "コック",
        "pronunciation": "コック",
        "back": "cook; tap, cock",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "こっそり",
        "pronunciation": "こっそり",
        "back": "stealthily, secretly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "古典",
        "pronunciation": "こてん",
        "back": "classics, classic",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "言付ける",
        "pronunciation": "ことづける",
        "back": "to leave a message",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "言葉遣い",
        "pronunciation": "ことばづかい",
        "back": "speech, expression, wording",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "こないだ",
        "pronunciation": "こないだ",
        "back": "the other day, lately, recently",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "御無沙汰",
        "pronunciation": "ごぶさた",
        "back": "not writing or contacting for a while",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ゴム",
        "pronunciation": "ゴム",
        "back": "gum, rubber",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "御免",
        "pronunciation": "ごめん",
        "back": "declining (something); pardon, sorry",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ごめんください",
        "pronunciation": "ごめんください",
        "back": "May I come in, Is anyone here",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "小指",
        "pronunciation": "こゆび",
        "back": "little finger",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "堪える",
        "pronunciation": "こらえる",
        "back": "to bear, to endure, to put up with",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "娯楽",
        "pronunciation": "ごらく",
        "back": "pleasure, amusement, recreation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "御覧",
        "pronunciation": "ごらん",
        "back": "(hon.) look, inspection, try",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "コレクション",
        "pronunciation": "コレクション",
        "back": "collection; correction",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "転がす",
        "pronunciation": "ころがす",
        "back": "to roll",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "転がる",
        "pronunciation": "ころがる",
        "back": "to roll, to tumble",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "紺",
        "pronunciation": "こん",
        "back": "navy blue, deep blue",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "今～",
        "pronunciation": "こん～",
        "back": "this, current",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "コンクール",
        "pronunciation": "コンクール",
        "back": "contest (FRE: concours)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "コンクリート",
        "pronunciation": "コンクリート",
        "back": "concrete",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "混合",
        "pronunciation": "こんごう",
        "back": "mixing, mixture",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "コンセント",
        "pronunciation": "コンセント",
        "back": "consent; power outlet",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "献立",
        "pronunciation": "こんだて",
        "back": "menu",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "こんばんは",
        "pronunciation": "こんばんは",
        "back": "good evening",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "サークル",
        "pronunciation": "サークル",
        "back": "circle, sports club (e.g., at a company)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "再～",
        "pronunciation": "さい～",
        "back": "re ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "最～",
        "pronunciation": "さい～",
        "back": "the most ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "在学",
        "pronunciation": "ざいがく",
        "back": "(enrolled) in school",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "再三",
        "pronunciation": "さいさん",
        "back": "again and again, repeatedly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "祭日",
        "pronunciation": "さいじつ",
        "back": "national holiday, festival day",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "催促",
        "pronunciation": "さいそく",
        "back": "demand, urge (action), press for",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "採点",
        "pronunciation": "さいてん",
        "back": "marking, grading",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "災難",
        "pronunciation": "さいなん",
        "back": "calamity, misfortune",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "裁縫",
        "pronunciation": "さいほう",
        "back": "sewing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "材木",
        "pronunciation": "ざいもく",
        "back": "lumber, timber",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "サイレン",
        "pronunciation": "サイレン",
        "back": "siren",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "逆さ",
        "pronunciation": "さかさ",
        "back": "reverse, upside down",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "逆様",
        "pronunciation": "さかさま",
        "back": "reverse, upside down",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "捜す",
        "pronunciation": "さがす",
        "back": "to search, to seek, to look for",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "遡る",
        "pronunciation": "さかのぼる",
        "back": "to go back, to date back; ascend",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "酒場",
        "pronunciation": "さかば",
        "back": "bar, bar-room",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一昨昨日",
        "pronunciation": "さきおととい",
        "back": "two days before yesterday, three days ago",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "先程",
        "pronunciation": "さきほど",
        "back": "a little while ago",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "索引",
        "pronunciation": "さくいん",
        "back": "index, indices",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "作者",
        "pronunciation": "さくしゃ",
        "back": "author, artist",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "削除",
        "pronunciation": "さくじょ",
        "back": "elimination, deletion",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "作成",
        "pronunciation": "さくせい",
        "back": "creation, preparation, to make",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "作製",
        "pronunciation": "さくせい",
        "back": "manufacture, production",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "探る",
        "pronunciation": "さぐる",
        "back": "to search, to look for, investigate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "囁く",
        "pronunciation": "ささやく",
        "back": "to whisper, to murmur",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "刺さる",
        "pronunciation": "ささる",
        "back": "to stick, to be stuck",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "匙",
        "pronunciation": "さじ",
        "back": "spoon",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "座敷",
        "pronunciation": "ざしき",
        "back": "tatami room",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "差し支え",
        "pronunciation": "さしつかえ",
        "back": "hindrance, impediment",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "差し引き",
        "pronunciation": "さしひき",
        "back": "deduction, balance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "刺身",
        "pronunciation": "さしみ",
        "back": "sliced raw fish",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "刺す",
        "pronunciation": "さす",
        "back": "to pierce, to stab, to prick, to thrust",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "流石",
        "pronunciation": "さすが",
        "back": "indeed, truly, as one would expect",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "撮影",
        "pronunciation": "さつえい",
        "back": "photographing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "雑音",
        "pronunciation": "ざつおん",
        "back": "noise (jarring, grating)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "さっさと",
        "pronunciation": "さっさと",
        "back": "quickly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "早速",
        "pronunciation": "さっそく",
        "back": "at once, immediately, promptly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "錆",
        "pronunciation": "さび",
        "back": "rust (color)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "錆びる",
        "pronunciation": "さびる",
        "back": "to rust, to become rusty",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "座布団",
        "pronunciation": "ざぶとん",
        "back": "cushion (Japanese)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "妨げる",
        "pronunciation": "さまたげる",
        "back": "to disturb, to prevent",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "さようなら",
        "pronunciation": "さようなら",
        "back": "good-bye",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "サラリーマン",
        "pronunciation": "サラリーマン",
        "back": "salaryman; company employee",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "騒がしい",
        "pronunciation": "さわがしい",
        "back": "noisy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "さわやか",
        "pronunciation": "さわやか",
        "back": "fresh, refreshing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "三角",
        "pronunciation": "さんかく",
        "back": "triangle, triangular",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "算数",
        "pronunciation": "さんすう",
        "back": "arithmetic",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "酸性",
        "pronunciation": "さんせい",
        "back": "acidity acidic",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "産地",
        "pronunciation": "さんち",
        "back": "producing area",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "サンプル",
        "pronunciation": "サンプル",
        "back": "sample",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "山林",
        "pronunciation": "さんりん",
        "back": "mountain forest",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "シーズン",
        "pronunciation": "シーズン",
        "back": "season (sporting)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "シーツ",
        "pronunciation": "シーツ",
        "back": "sheet",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕上がる",
        "pronunciation": "しあがる",
        "back": "to be finished",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "明明後日",
        "pronunciation": "しあさって",
        "back": "two days after tomorrow",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "寺院",
        "pronunciation": "じいん",
        "back": "temple",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しいんと (する)",
        "pronunciation": "しいんと (する)",
        "back": "silent (as the grave), (deathly) quiet",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "自衛",
        "pronunciation": "じえい",
        "back": "self-defense",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "塩辛",
        "pronunciation": "しおから",
        "back": "salty (taste)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "塩辛い",
        "pronunciation": "しおからい",
        "back": "salty (taste)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "司会",
        "pronunciation": "しかい",
        "back": "host, chairperson",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しかく しかくい",
        "pronunciation": "しかく しかくい",
        "back": "square",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "四角い",
        "pronunciation": "しかくい",
        "back": "square",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕方がない",
        "pronunciation": "しかたがない",
        "back": "it can't be helped, it's inevitable",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "時間割",
        "pronunciation": "じかんわり",
        "back": "timetable, schedule",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "四季",
        "pronunciation": "しき",
        "back": "four seasons",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "敷地",
        "pronunciation": "しきち",
        "back": "site",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "敷く",
        "pronunciation": "しく",
        "back": "to spread out, to lay out",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "茂る",
        "pronunciation": "しげる",
        "back": "to grow thick",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "持参",
        "pronunciation": "じさん",
        "back": "bringing, taking, carrying",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "磁石",
        "pronunciation": "じしゃく",
        "back": "magnet",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "四捨五入",
        "pronunciation": "ししゃごにゅう",
        "back": "rounding up (fractions)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "始終",
        "pronunciation": "しじゅう",
        "back": "continuously, always, constantly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "自習",
        "pronunciation": "じしゅう",
        "back": "self-study",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "静まる",
        "pronunciation": "しずまる",
        "back": "to quieten down, to calm down",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "姿勢",
        "pronunciation": "しせい",
        "back": "attitude; posture",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "自然科学",
        "pronunciation": "しぜんかがく",
        "back": "natural science",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "時速",
        "pronunciation": "じそく",
        "back": "speed (per hour)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "子孫",
        "pronunciation": "しそん",
        "back": "descendant, offspring",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "死体",
        "pronunciation": "したい",
        "back": "corpse",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "下書き",
        "pronunciation": "したがき",
        "back": "rough copy, draft",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "自宅",
        "pronunciation": "じたく",
        "back": "one's own home (same as 自分の家 (じぶんのいえ))",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "下町",
        "pronunciation": "したまち",
        "back": "old parts of town",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "自治",
        "pronunciation": "じち",
        "back": "self-government, autonomy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "室～",
        "pronunciation": "しつ～",
        "back": "room",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "実感",
        "pronunciation": "じっかん",
        "back": "feelings, realization",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "湿気",
        "pronunciation": "しっき",
        "back": "moisture, humidity, dampness",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しつこい",
        "pronunciation": "しつこい",
        "back": "insistent, obstinate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "実習",
        "pronunciation": "じっしゅう",
        "back": "practice, training",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "実績",
        "pronunciation": "じっせき",
        "back": "achievements, actual results",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "湿度",
        "pronunciation": "しつど",
        "back": "level of humidity",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "執筆",
        "pronunciation": "しっぴつ",
        "back": "writing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "実物",
        "pronunciation": "じつぶつ",
        "back": "an actual thing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しっぽ",
        "pronunciation": "しっぽ",
        "back": "tail (animal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "実用",
        "pronunciation": "じつよう",
        "back": "practical use, utility",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "実力",
        "pronunciation": "じつりょく",
        "back": "(real) ability, true strength, merit, efficiency, competency",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "実例",
        "pronunciation": "じつれい",
        "back": "example, instance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しつれいしました (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "しつれいしました (かん)",
        "back": "Excuse me., I'm sorry.",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "失恋",
        "pronunciation": "しつれん",
        "back": "broken heart, unrequited love",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "指定",
        "pronunciation": "してい",
        "back": "designation, specification, assignment",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "私鉄",
        "pronunciation": "してつ",
        "back": "private railway",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "児童",
        "pronunciation": "じどう",
        "back": "children, juvenile",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "縛る",
        "pronunciation": "しばる",
        "back": "to tie, to bind",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "地盤",
        "pronunciation": "じばん",
        "back": "(the) ground",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しびれる",
        "pronunciation": "しびれる",
        "back": "to become numb",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "紙幣",
        "pronunciation": "しへい",
        "back": "paper money, notes, bills",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しぼむ",
        "pronunciation": "しぼむ",
        "back": "to wither, to shrivel",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "萎む",
        "pronunciation": "しぼむ",
        "back": "to wither (of flowers, dreams, etc.), to wilt",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "絞る",
        "pronunciation": "しぼる",
        "back": "to press, to wring, to squeeze",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "縞",
        "pronunciation": "しま",
        "back": "stripe",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "地味",
        "pronunciation": "じみ",
        "back": "plain, simple, subdued, sober",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しみじみ",
        "pronunciation": "しみじみ",
        "back": "keenly, deeply, heartily",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "氏名",
        "pronunciation": "しめい",
        "back": "full name",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "締切",
        "pronunciation": "しめきり",
        "back": "deadline",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "締め切り",
        "pronunciation": "しめきり",
        "back": "deadline, closing, cut-off, end",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "締め切る",
        "pronunciation": "しめきる",
        "back": "to close, cancel",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しめた (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "しめた (かん)",
        "back": "I've got it, all right, fine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しめる",
        "pronunciation": "しめる",
        "back": "to be wet, to become wet, to be damp",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "地面",
        "pronunciation": "じめん",
        "back": "ground, earth's surface",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジャーナリスト",
        "pronunciation": "ジャーナリスト",
        "back": "journalist",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "社会科学",
        "pronunciation": "しゃかいかがく",
        "back": "social science",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しゃがむ",
        "pronunciation": "しゃがむ",
        "back": "to squat",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "蛇口",
        "pronunciation": "じゃぐち",
        "back": "faucet, tap",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "弱点",
        "pronunciation": "じゃくてん",
        "back": "weak point, weakness",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "車庫",
        "pronunciation": "しゃこ",
        "back": "garage, car shed",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "車掌",
        "pronunciation": "しゃしょう",
        "back": "(train) conductor",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "写生",
        "pronunciation": "しゃせい",
        "back": "sketching, drawing from nature",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "社説",
        "pronunciation": "しゃせつ",
        "back": "editorial",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しゃっくり",
        "pronunciation": "しゃっくり",
        "back": "hiccough, hiccup",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "シャッター",
        "pronunciation": "シャッター",
        "back": "shutter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しゃぶる",
        "pronunciation": "しゃぶる",
        "back": "to suck, to chew",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "車輪",
        "pronunciation": "しゃりん",
        "back": "(car) wheel",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "洒落",
        "pronunciation": "しゃれ",
        "back": "joke, pun, witticism",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "じゃんけん",
        "pronunciation": "じゃんけん",
        "back": "rock-scissors-paper game",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "重～",
        "pronunciation": "じゅう～",
        "back": "heavy ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "集会",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうかい",
        "back": "meeting, assembly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "住居",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうきょ",
        "back": "dwelling, house, residence, address",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "集金",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうきん",
        "back": "money collection",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "集合",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうごう",
        "back": "gathering, assembly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "習字",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうじ",
        "back": "penmanship",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "修繕",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうぜん",
        "back": "repair, mending",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "重体",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうたい",
        "back": "serious condition, critical condition",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "じゅうたん (カーペット)",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうたん (カーペット)",
        "back": "carpet",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "終点",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうてん",
        "back": "terminus, last stop (e.g train)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "重点",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうてん",
        "back": "important point, lay stress on, emphasis",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "就任",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうにん",
        "back": "inauguration, assumption of office",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "周辺",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうへん",
        "back": "circumference, peripheral",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "重役",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうやく",
        "back": "director, high executive",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "終了",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうりょう",
        "back": "end, close, termination",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "重量",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうりょう",
        "back": "heavyweight",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "重力",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうりょく",
        "back": "gravity",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "熟語",
        "pronunciation": "じゅくご",
        "back": "idiom, kanji compound",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "祝日",
        "pronunciation": "しゅくじつ",
        "back": "national holiday",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "縮小",
        "pronunciation": "しゅくしょう",
        "back": "reduction, curtailment",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "受験",
        "pronunciation": "じゅけん",
        "back": "taking an examination",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "主語",
        "pronunciation": "しゅご",
        "back": "(gram) subject",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "主人",
        "pronunciation": "しゅじん",
        "back": "(one's own) husband",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "出勤",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっきん",
        "back": "going to work, at work",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "述語",
        "pronunciation": "じゅつご",
        "back": "predicate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "出張",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっちょう",
        "back": "official tour, business trip",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "寿命",
        "pronunciation": "じゅみょう",
        "back": "life span",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "主役",
        "pronunciation": "しゅやく",
        "back": "leading part",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "受話器",
        "pronunciation": "じゅわき",
        "back": "(telephone) receiver",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "循環",
        "pronunciation": "じゅんかん",
        "back": "circulation, rotation, cycle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "巡査",
        "pronunciation": "じゅんさ",
        "back": "policeman",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "順々",
        "pronunciation": "じゅんじゅん",
        "back": "in order, in turn",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "順序",
        "pronunciation": "じゅんじょ",
        "back": "order, sequence, procedure",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "純情",
        "pronunciation": "じゅんじょう",
        "back": "pure heart",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "純粋",
        "pronunciation": "じゅんすい",
        "back": "pure, genuine, unmixed",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "初～",
        "pronunciation": "しょ～",
        "back": "first ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "諸～",
        "pronunciation": "しょ～",
        "back": "various ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "女～",
        "pronunciation": "じょ～",
        "back": "things done by women",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "省～",
        "pronunciation": "しょう～",
        "back": "economizing ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "消化",
        "pronunciation": "しょうか",
        "back": "digestion",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "小学生",
        "pronunciation": "しょうがくせい",
        "back": "elementary school pupil",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しょうがない",
        "pronunciation": "しょうがない",
        "back": "It is not worth ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "将棋",
        "pronunciation": "しょうぎ",
        "back": "Japanese chess",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "蒸気",
        "pronunciation": "じょうき",
        "back": "steam, vapor",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "定規",
        "pronunciation": "じょうぎ",
        "back": "(measuring) ruler",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "上級",
        "pronunciation": "じょうきゅう",
        "back": "advanced level, high grade, senior",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "商業",
        "pronunciation": "しょうぎょう",
        "back": "commerce, trade, business",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "消極的",
        "pronunciation": "しょうきょくてき",
        "back": "passive",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "賞金",
        "pronunciation": "しょうきん",
        "back": "prize, monetary award",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "上下",
        "pronunciation": "じょうげ",
        "back": "high and low, up and down",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "障子",
        "pronunciation": "しょうじ",
        "back": "paper sliding door",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "商社",
        "pronunciation": "しょうしゃ",
        "back": "trading company",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "乗車",
        "pronunciation": "じょうしゃ",
        "back": "taking a train, entraining",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "上旬",
        "pronunciation": "じょうじゅん",
        "back": "first 10 days of month",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "小数",
        "pronunciation": "しょうすう",
        "back": "fraction (part of), decimal",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "生ずる",
        "pronunciation": "しょうずる",
        "back": "to cause, to arise, to be generated",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "商店",
        "pronunciation": "しょうてん",
        "back": "shop, business firm",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "焦点",
        "pronunciation": "しょうてん",
        "back": "focus, point",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "消毒",
        "pronunciation": "しょうどく",
        "back": "disinfection",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "勝敗",
        "pronunciation": "しょうはい",
        "back": "victory or defeat, issue (of battle)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "蒸発",
        "pronunciation": "じょうはつ",
        "back": "evaporation; unexplained disappearance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "賞品",
        "pronunciation": "しょうひん",
        "back": "prize, trophy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "上品",
        "pronunciation": "じょうひん",
        "back": "refined, elegant, well-mannered",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "勝負",
        "pronunciation": "しょうぶ",
        "back": "victory or defeat, game",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "小便",
        "pronunciation": "しょうべん",
        "back": "(col) urine, piss",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "消防署",
        "pronunciation": "しょうぼうしょ",
        "back": "fire station",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "正味",
        "pronunciation": "しょうみ",
        "back": "net (weight)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "正面",
        "pronunciation": "しょうめん",
        "back": "front",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "消耗",
        "pronunciation": "しょうもう",
        "back": "exhaustion, consumption",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "省略",
        "pronunciation": "しょうりゃく",
        "back": "omission, abbreviation, abridgment",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "初級",
        "pronunciation": "しょきゅう",
        "back": "elementary level",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "助教授",
        "pronunciation": "じょきょうじゅ",
        "back": "assistant professor",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "食塩",
        "pronunciation": "しょくえん",
        "back": "table salt",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "職人",
        "pronunciation": "しょくにん",
        "back": "artisan, craftsman",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "職場",
        "pronunciation": "しょくば",
        "back": "workplace",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "初旬",
        "pronunciation": "しょじゅん",
        "back": "first 10 days of the month",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "書籍",
        "pronunciation": "しょせき",
        "back": "book, publication",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "食器",
        "pronunciation": "しょっき",
        "back": "tableware",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ショップ",
        "pronunciation": "ショップ",
        "back": "a shop",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "書店",
        "pronunciation": "しょてん",
        "back": "bookshop",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "書道",
        "pronunciation": "しょどう",
        "back": "calligraphy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "初歩",
        "pronunciation": "しょほ",
        "back": "elements, rudiments",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "白髪",
        "pronunciation": "しらが",
        "back": "white or grey hair, trendy hair bleaching",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "シリーズ",
        "pronunciation": "シリーズ",
        "back": "series",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "知り合い",
        "pronunciation": "しりあい",
        "back": "acquaintance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "私立",
        "pronunciation": "しりつ",
        "back": "private (establishment)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "資料",
        "pronunciation": "しりょう",
        "back": "materials, data",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "汁",
        "pronunciation": "しる",
        "back": "juice, soup",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "素人",
        "pronunciation": "しろうと",
        "back": "layman, amateur, novice",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "しわ (かおの～)",
        "pronunciation": "しわ (かおの～)",
        "back": "wrinkles, creases",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "芯",
        "pronunciation": "しん",
        "back": "core, heart, wick",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "新幹線",
        "pronunciation": "しんかんせん",
        "back": "Shinkansen, \"Bullet Train\"",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "真空",
        "pronunciation": "しんくう",
        "back": "vacuum",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "人事",
        "pronunciation": "じんじ",
        "back": "human resources, personnel management",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "心身",
        "pronunciation": "しんしん",
        "back": "mind and body",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "信ずる",
        "pronunciation": "しんずる",
        "back": "to believe",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "申請",
        "pronunciation": "しんせい",
        "back": "application, request, petition",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "人造",
        "pronunciation": "じんぞう",
        "back": "man-made, synthetic, artificial",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "寝台",
        "pronunciation": "しんだい",
        "back": "bed",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "診断",
        "pronunciation": "しんだん",
        "back": "diagnosis",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "侵入",
        "pronunciation": "しんにゅう",
        "back": "invasion, raid, trespass",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "人文科学",
        "pronunciation": "じんぶんかがく",
        "back": "social sciences, humanities",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "人命",
        "pronunciation": "じんめい",
        "back": "(human) life",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "深夜",
        "pronunciation": "しんや",
        "back": "late at night",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "森林",
        "pronunciation": "しんりん",
        "back": "forest, woods",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "親類",
        "pronunciation": "しんるい",
        "back": "relative(s) (same as 親戚 (しんせき))",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "針路",
        "pronunciation": "しんろ",
        "back": "course, direction",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "神話",
        "pronunciation": "しんわ",
        "back": "myth, legend",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "酢",
        "pronunciation": "す",
        "back": "vinegar",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "水産",
        "pronunciation": "すいさん",
        "back": "marine products, fisheries",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "炊事",
        "pronunciation": "すいじ",
        "back": "cooking",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "水蒸気",
        "pronunciation": "すいじょうき",
        "back": "water vapor, steam",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "水素",
        "pronunciation": "すいそ",
        "back": "hydrogen",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "垂直",
        "pronunciation": "すいちょく",
        "back": "vertical, perpendicular",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "推定",
        "pronunciation": "すいてい",
        "back": "presumption, assumption, estimation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "水滴",
        "pronunciation": "すいてき",
        "back": "drop of water",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "水筒",
        "pronunciation": "すいとう",
        "back": "canteen, flask, water bottle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "随筆",
        "pronunciation": "ずいひつ",
        "back": "essays, miscellaneous writings",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "水分",
        "pronunciation": "すいぶん",
        "back": "moisture",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "水平",
        "pronunciation": "すいへい",
        "back": "level, horizontal",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "水平線",
        "pronunciation": "すいへいせん",
        "back": "horizon",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "水面",
        "pronunciation": "すいめん",
        "back": "water's surface",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "水曜",
        "pronunciation": "すいよう",
        "back": "Wednesday",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "図々しい",
        "pronunciation": "ずうずうしい",
        "back": "impudent, shameless",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ずうっと",
        "pronunciation": "ずうっと",
        "back": "all the time, all the way",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "末っ子",
        "pronunciation": "すえっこ",
        "back": "youngest child",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "スカーフ",
        "pronunciation": "スカーフ",
        "back": "scarf",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "図鑑",
        "pronunciation": "ずかん",
        "back": "picture book",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "隙",
        "pronunciation": "すき",
        "back": "unguarded moment, chance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "杉",
        "pronunciation": "すぎ",
        "back": "Japanese cedar",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "好き嫌い",
        "pronunciation": "すききらい",
        "back": "likes and dislikes, taste",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "好き好き",
        "pronunciation": "すきずき",
        "back": "matter of taste",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "透き通る",
        "pronunciation": "すきとおる",
        "back": "to be(come) transparent",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "隙間",
        "pronunciation": "すきま",
        "back": "crack, gap, opening",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "スクール",
        "pronunciation": "スクール",
        "back": "school",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "少なくとも",
        "pronunciation": "すくなくとも",
        "back": "at least",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "図形",
        "pronunciation": "ずけい",
        "back": "figure",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "鈴",
        "pronunciation": "すず",
        "back": "bell",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "涼む",
        "pronunciation": "すずむ",
        "back": "to cool oneself, to cool off",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "スタート",
        "pronunciation": "スタート",
        "back": "start",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "スチュワーデス",
        "pronunciation": "スチュワーデス",
        "back": "stewardess",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "すっきり",
        "pronunciation": "すっきり",
        "back": "shapely, clear, neat",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ステージ",
        "pronunciation": "ステージ",
        "back": "stage; performance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ストッキング",
        "pronunciation": "ストッキング",
        "back": "stockings",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ストップ",
        "pronunciation": "ストップ",
        "back": "stop",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "素直",
        "pronunciation": "すなお",
        "back": "obedient, meek, docile",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "頭脳",
        "pronunciation": "ずのう",
        "back": "head, brains, intellect",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "スピーカー",
        "pronunciation": "スピーカー",
        "back": "speaker",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "図表",
        "pronunciation": "ずひょう",
        "back": "chart, diagram, graph",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "スマート",
        "pronunciation": "スマート",
        "back": "smart, stylish, slim",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "住まい",
        "pronunciation": "すまい",
        "back": "dwelling, house",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "すまない",
        "pronunciation": "すまない",
        "back": "sorry (phrase)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "相撲",
        "pronunciation": "すもう",
        "back": "sumo wrestling",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "スライド",
        "pronunciation": "スライド",
        "back": "slide",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ずらす",
        "pronunciation": "ずらす",
        "back": "to put off, to delay",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ずらり",
        "pronunciation": "ずらり",
        "back": "in a line, in a row",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "スリッパ",
        "pronunciation": "スリッパ",
        "back": "slippers",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "する",
        "pronunciation": "する",
        "back": "to print",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "狡い",
        "pronunciation": "ずるい",
        "back": "sly, cunning",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "寸法",
        "pronunciation": "すんぽう",
        "back": "measurement, size, dimension",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "姓",
        "pronunciation": "せい",
        "back": "surname, family name",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "税関",
        "pronunciation": "ぜいかん",
        "back": "customs",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "製作",
        "pronunciation": "せいさく",
        "back": "manufacture, production",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "制作",
        "pronunciation": "せいさく",
        "back": "work (e.g., film, book)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "性質",
        "pronunciation": "せいしつ",
        "back": "nature, property, disposition",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "清書",
        "pronunciation": "せいしょ",
        "back": "clean copy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "青少年",
        "pronunciation": "せいしょうねん",
        "back": "youth, young person",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "整数",
        "pronunciation": "せいすう",
        "back": "integer",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "清掃",
        "pronunciation": "せいそう",
        "back": "cleaning",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "生存",
        "pronunciation": "せいぞん",
        "back": "existence, being, survival",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "生長",
        "pronunciation": "せいちょう",
        "back": "growth (of a plant)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "政党",
        "pronunciation": "せいとう",
        "back": "(member of) political party",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "生年月日",
        "pronunciation": "せいねんがっぴ",
        "back": "date of birth",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "性能",
        "pronunciation": "せいのう",
        "back": "ability, capability",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "整備",
        "pronunciation": "せいび",
        "back": "maintenance, overhaul",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "成分",
        "pronunciation": "せいぶん",
        "back": "ingredient, component, composition",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "性別",
        "pronunciation": "せいべつ",
        "back": "sex, gender",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "正方形",
        "pronunciation": "せいほうけい",
        "back": "square",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "正門",
        "pronunciation": "せいもん",
        "back": "main gate, main entrance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "成立",
        "pronunciation": "せいりつ",
        "back": "formation, establishment, completion",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "西暦",
        "pronunciation": "せいれき",
        "back": "Christian Era, after (Christ’s) death (A.D.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "背負う",
        "pronunciation": "せおう",
        "back": "to be burdened with; to carry on (one's) back or shoulder(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "赤道",
        "pronunciation": "せきどう",
        "back": "equator",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "折角",
        "pronunciation": "せっかく",
        "back": "with trouble, at great pains, long-awaited",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "接近",
        "pronunciation": "せっきん",
        "back": "getting closer, drawing nearer, approaching",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "接する",
        "pronunciation": "せっする",
        "back": "to attend to (someone); to associate with",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "せっせと",
        "pronunciation": "せっせと",
        "back": "busily, away",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "接続",
        "pronunciation": "せつぞく",
        "back": "connection, union, join, link; changing trains",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "瀬戸物",
        "pronunciation": "せともの",
        "back": "earthenware, crockery, china",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぜひとも",
        "pronunciation": "ぜひとも",
        "back": "by all means (with sense of not taking 'no' for an answer)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "迫る",
        "pronunciation": "せまる",
        "back": "to draw near, to press",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ゼミ",
        "pronunciation": "ゼミ",
        "back": "seminar",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "せめて",
        "pronunciation": "せめて",
        "back": "at least",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "攻める",
        "pronunciation": "せめる",
        "back": "to attack, to assault, to assail",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "セメント",
        "pronunciation": "セメント",
        "back": "cement",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "台詞",
        "pronunciation": "せりふ",
        "back": "speech, words, one's lines, remarks",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "栓",
        "pronunciation": "せん",
        "back": "stopper, cork, stopcock",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "前～",
        "pronunciation": "ぜん～",
        "back": "former, late ~, past ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "前後",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんご",
        "back": "front and back, before and after",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "洗剤",
        "pronunciation": "せんざい",
        "back": "detergent, cleanser, cleaning agent, washing material",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "全集",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんしゅう",
        "back": "complete works",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "全身",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんしん",
        "back": "whole (body), full-length (e.g., portrait) systemic",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "扇子",
        "pronunciation": "せんす",
        "back": "folding fan",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "専制",
        "pronunciation": "せんせい",
        "back": "despotism, autocracy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "先々月",
        "pronunciation": "せんせんげつ",
        "back": "month before last",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "先々週",
        "pronunciation": "せんせんしゅう",
        "back": "2 weeks before",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "先祖",
        "pronunciation": "せんぞ",
        "back": "ancestor",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "先端",
        "pronunciation": "せんたん",
        "back": "pointed end, tip",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "センチ",
        "pronunciation": "センチ",
        "back": "centimeter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "宣伝",
        "pronunciation": "せんでん",
        "back": "publicity, advertisement, advertising, propaganda",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "先頭",
        "pronunciation": "せんとう",
        "back": "head, lead, vanguard",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "全般",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんぱん",
        "back": "(the) whole, general",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "扇風機",
        "pronunciation": "せんぷうき",
        "back": "electric fan",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "洗面",
        "pronunciation": "せんめん",
        "back": "wash up (one's face), have a wash",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "全力",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんりょく",
        "back": "all one's power, whole energy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "線路",
        "pronunciation": "せんろ",
        "back": "line, track, roadbed",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "総～",
        "pronunciation": "そう～",
        "back": "gross, general, entire",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "相違",
        "pronunciation": "そうい",
        "back": "difference, discrepancy, variation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "そういえば",
        "pronunciation": "そういえば",
        "back": "which reminds me ..",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "雑巾",
        "pronunciation": "ぞうきん",
        "back": "house-cloth, dust cloth",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "増減",
        "pronunciation": "ぞうげん",
        "back": "increase and decrease, fluctuation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "倉庫",
        "pronunciation": "そうこ",
        "back": "storehouse, warehouse",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "相互",
        "pronunciation": "そうご",
        "back": "mutual, reciprocal",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "創作",
        "pronunciation": "そうさく",
        "back": "production, creation, work",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "葬式",
        "pronunciation": "そうしき",
        "back": "funeral",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "造船",
        "pronunciation": "ぞうせん",
        "back": "shipbuilding",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "騒々しい",
        "pronunciation": "そうぞうしい",
        "back": "noisy, boisterous",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "増大",
        "pronunciation": "ぞうだい",
        "back": "increase, growth",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "そうっと",
        "pronunciation": "そうっと",
        "back": "softly, cautiously, gently",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "送別",
        "pronunciation": "そうべつ",
        "back": "farewell, send-off",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "草履",
        "pronunciation": "ぞうり",
        "back": "Japanese sandals (footwear)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "総理大臣",
        "pronunciation": "そうりだいじん",
        "back": "Prime Minister",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "送料",
        "pronunciation": "そうりょう",
        "back": "postage, carriage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "属する",
        "pronunciation": "ぞくする",
        "back": "to belong to, to come under",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "続々",
        "pronunciation": "ぞくぞく",
        "back": "successively, one after another",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "速達",
        "pronunciation": "そくたつ",
        "back": "express, special delivery",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "測定",
        "pronunciation": "そくてい",
        "back": "measurement",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "測量",
        "pronunciation": "そくりょう",
        "back": "measurement, surveying",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "速力",
        "pronunciation": "そくりょく",
        "back": "speed",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "素質",
        "pronunciation": "そしつ",
        "back": "talent, capability",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "祖先",
        "pronunciation": "そせん",
        "back": "ancestor(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "そそっかしい",
        "pronunciation": "そそっかしい",
        "back": "careless, thoughtless",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "卒直",
        "pronunciation": "そっちょく",
        "back": "frank, candid, honest",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "率直",
        "pronunciation": "そっちょく",
        "back": "frank, candid, straightforward, openhearted, direct, outspoken",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "そのころ",
        "pronunciation": "そのころ",
        "back": "in those days, at that time, then",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "そのため",
        "pronunciation": "そのため",
        "back": "hence, for that reason",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "その他",
        "pronunciation": "そのほか",
        "back": "besides",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "そば",
        "pronunciation": "そば",
        "back": "soba (buckwheat noodles)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "剃る",
        "pronunciation": "そる",
        "back": "to shave",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "それなのに",
        "pronunciation": "それなのに",
        "back": "though, although",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "それなら",
        "pronunciation": "それなら",
        "back": "If that's the case..., If so..., That being the case...",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "それはいけませんね (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "それはいけませんね (かん)",
        "back": "that's not good",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "逸れる",
        "pronunciation": "それる",
        "back": "to stray (turn) from subject, to go astray",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "揃える",
        "pronunciation": "そろえる",
        "back": "to collect, to gather, to get together, to complete (a collection) to arrange, to put in order, to prepare, to get ready to make uniform, to make even, to match",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "算盤",
        "pronunciation": "そろばん",
        "back": "abacus",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "存じる",
        "pronunciation": "ぞんじる",
        "back": "(humble) to know",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "存ずる",
        "pronunciation": "ぞんずる",
        "back": "(humble) to know",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "損得",
        "pronunciation": "そんとく",
        "back": "loss and gain, advantage and disadvantage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "第～",
        "pronunciation": "だい～",
        "back": "~th",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "タイア",
        "pronunciation": "タイア",
        "back": "tire, tyre",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "だいいち (とりわけ)",
        "pronunciation": "だいいち (とりわけ)",
        "back": "first, foremost,&nbsp;&nbsp;#1",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "大学院",
        "pronunciation": "だいがくいん",
        "back": "graduate school",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "大工",
        "pronunciation": "だいく",
        "back": "carpenter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "体系",
        "pronunciation": "たいけい",
        "back": "system, organization",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "太鼓",
        "pronunciation": "たいこ",
        "back": "drum, tambourine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "対策",
        "pronunciation": "たいさく",
        "back": "counter-plan, counter-measure",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "大して",
        "pronunciation": "たいして",
        "back": "(not so) much, (not) very",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "対照",
        "pronunciation": "たいしょう",
        "back": "contrast, antithesis, comparison",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "大小",
        "pronunciation": "だいしょう",
        "back": "size",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "体制",
        "pronunciation": "たいせい",
        "back": "order, system, structure",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "体積",
        "pronunciation": "たいせき",
        "back": "capacity, volume",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "大層",
        "pronunciation": "たいそう",
        "back": "very much, greatly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "体操",
        "pronunciation": "たいそう",
        "back": "gymnastics, physical exercises, calisthenics",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "大分",
        "pronunciation": "だいぶん",
        "back": "considerably, greatly, a lot",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "大木",
        "pronunciation": "たいぼく",
        "back": "large tree",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "題名",
        "pronunciation": "だいめい",
        "back": "title, caption, heading",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "代名詞",
        "pronunciation": "だいめいし",
        "back": "pronoun",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ダイヤグラム",
        "pronunciation": "ダイヤグラム",
        "back": "diagram",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ダイヤモンド",
        "pronunciation": "ダイヤモンド",
        "back": "diamond",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ダイヤル",
        "pronunciation": "ダイヤル",
        "back": "dial",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "対立",
        "pronunciation": "たいりつ",
        "back": "confrontation, opposition, antagonism",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "田植え",
        "pronunciation": "たうえ",
        "back": "rice planting",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "絶えず",
        "pronunciation": "たえず",
        "back": "constantly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "楕円",
        "pronunciation": "だえん",
        "back": "ellipse",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "高める",
        "pronunciation": "たかめる",
        "back": "to raise, to lift, to boost, to enhance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "耕す",
        "pronunciation": "たがやす",
        "back": "to till, to plow, to cultivate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "滝",
        "pronunciation": "たき",
        "back": "waterfall",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "蓄える",
        "pronunciation": "たくわえる",
        "back": "to save, to store, to lay in stock",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "竹",
        "pronunciation": "たけ",
        "back": "bamboo",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ただいま",
        "pronunciation": "ただいま",
        "back": "Here I am, I'm home!",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "但し",
        "pronunciation": "ただし",
        "back": "but, however, provided that",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "畳む",
        "pronunciation": "たたむ",
        "back": "to fold (e.g., clothes, umbrella)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "立ち止まる",
        "pronunciation": "たちどまる",
        "back": "to stop, to halt, to stand still",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "たちまち",
        "pronunciation": "たちまち",
        "back": "instantly, suddenly, all at once",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "建つ",
        "pronunciation": "たつ",
        "back": "to be erected, to be built",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "脱線",
        "pronunciation": "だっせん",
        "back": "derailment, digression",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "妥当",
        "pronunciation": "だとう",
        "back": "proper, appropriate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "例える",
        "pronunciation": "たとえる",
        "back": "to compare, to liken",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "頼もしい",
        "pronunciation": "たのもしい",
        "back": "reliable, promising",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "足袋",
        "pronunciation": "たび",
        "back": "tabi, Japanese socks (with split toe)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ダブル",
        "pronunciation": "ダブル",
        "back": "double",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ダム",
        "pronunciation": "ダム",
        "back": "dam",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "溜息",
        "pronunciation": "ためいき",
        "back": "a sigh",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ためらう",
        "pronunciation": "ためらう",
        "back": "to be hesitant",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "だらしない",
        "pronunciation": "だらしない",
        "back": "slovenly, loose, a slut",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "足る",
        "pronunciation": "たる",
        "back": "to be sufficient, to be enough",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "短～",
        "pronunciation": "たん～",
        "back": "short ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "段階",
        "pronunciation": "だんかい",
        "back": "gradation, grade, stage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "短期",
        "pronunciation": "たんき",
        "back": "short term",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "炭鉱",
        "pronunciation": "たんこう",
        "back": "coal mine, coal pit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "短所",
        "pronunciation": "たんしょ",
        "back": "defect, weak point; disadvantage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "たんす",
        "pronunciation": "たんす",
        "back": "chest of drawers",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "淡水",
        "pronunciation": "たんすい",
        "back": "fresh water",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "断水",
        "pronunciation": "だんすい",
        "back": "water outage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "単数",
        "pronunciation": "たんすう",
        "back": "singular (number)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "団地",
        "pronunciation": "だんち",
        "back": "housing complex",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "断定",
        "pronunciation": "だんてい",
        "back": "conclusion, decision",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "短編",
        "pronunciation": "たんぺん",
        "back": "short (e.g., story, film)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "田ぼ",
        "pronunciation": "たんぼ",
        "back": "paddy field, farm",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "誓う",
        "pronunciation": "ちかう",
        "back": "to swear, to vow",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "地下水",
        "pronunciation": "ちかすい",
        "back": "underground water",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "近々",
        "pronunciation": "ちかぢか",
        "back": "soon, before long",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "近付ける",
        "pronunciation": "ちかづける",
        "back": "to bring near, to put close, to let come near",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "近寄る",
        "pronunciation": "ちかよる",
        "back": "to approach, to draw near",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "力強い",
        "pronunciation": "ちからづよい",
        "back": "powerful, strong, vigorous",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちぎる",
        "pronunciation": "ちぎる",
        "back": "to cut up fine, to pick (fruit)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "地質",
        "pronunciation": "ちしつ",
        "back": "geological features",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "知人",
        "pronunciation": "ちじん",
        "back": "friend, acquaintance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "地帯",
        "pronunciation": "ちたい",
        "back": "area, zone",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "縮む",
        "pronunciation": "ちぢむ",
        "back": "to shrink, to be contracted",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "縮める",
        "pronunciation": "ちぢめる",
        "back": "to shorten, to reduce, to shrink",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "縮れる",
        "pronunciation": "ちぢれる",
        "back": "to be wavy, to be curled",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "チップ",
        "pronunciation": "チップ",
        "back": "gratuity, tip; chip",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "地点",
        "pronunciation": "ちてん",
        "back": "site, point on a map",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "地名",
        "pronunciation": "ちめい",
        "back": "place name",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "茶色い",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃいろい",
        "back": "brown",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "着々",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃくちゃく",
        "back": "steadily",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "中間",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうかん",
        "back": "middle, midway, interim",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "中旬",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうじゅん",
        "back": "second third of a month",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "抽象",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうしょう",
        "back": "abstract",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "中世",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうせい",
        "back": "Middle Ages, medieval times",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "中性",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうせい",
        "back": "neuter gender, neutral",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "中途",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうと",
        "back": "in the middle, half-way",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "中年",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうねん",
        "back": "middle-aged",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "チョーク",
        "pronunciation": "チョーク",
        "back": "chalk",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "長～",
        "pronunciation": "ちょう～",
        "back": "long ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "超過",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうか",
        "back": "excess, being more than",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "彫刻",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうこく",
        "back": "carving, engraving, sculpture",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "長所",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうしょ",
        "back": "strong point, merit; advantage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "長女",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうじょ",
        "back": "eldest daughter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "調整",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうせい",
        "back": "regulation, adjustment, tuning",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "調節",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうせつ",
        "back": "regulation, adjustment, control",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "長短",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうたん",
        "back": "length, long and short, +-",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "頂点",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうてん",
        "back": "top, summit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "長男",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうなん",
        "back": "eldest son",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "長方形",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうほうけい",
        "back": "rectangle, oblong",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "調味料",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうみりょう",
        "back": "condiment, seasoning",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "直後",
        "pronunciation": "ちょくご",
        "back": "immediately following",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "直線",
        "pronunciation": "ちょくせん",
        "back": "straight line",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "直前",
        "pronunciation": "ちょくぜん",
        "back": "just before",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "直通",
        "pronunciation": "ちょくつう",
        "back": "direct connection",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "直流",
        "pronunciation": "ちょくりゅう",
        "back": "direct current",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "貯蔵",
        "pronunciation": "ちょぞう",
        "back": "storage, preservation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "直角",
        "pronunciation": "ちょっかく",
        "back": "right angle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "直径",
        "pronunciation": "ちょっけい",
        "back": "diameter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "散らかす",
        "pronunciation": "ちらかす",
        "back": "to scatter around, to leave untidy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "散らかる",
        "pronunciation": "ちらかる",
        "back": "to be in disorder",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "塵紙",
        "pronunciation": "ちりがみ",
        "back": "tissue paper, toilet paper",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "追加",
        "pronunciation": "ついか",
        "back": "addition, supplement, appendix",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ついで",
        "pronunciation": "ついで",
        "back": "opportunity, occasion",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "つうか",
        "pronunciation": "つうか",
        "back": "currency",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "通勤",
        "pronunciation": "つうきん",
        "back": "commuting to work",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "通ずる",
        "pronunciation": "つうずる",
        "back": "to lead, to run, to open",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "通知",
        "pronunciation": "つうち",
        "back": "notice, notification",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "通帳",
        "pronunciation": "つうちょう",
        "back": "bankbook",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "通訳",
        "pronunciation": "つうやく",
        "back": "interpretation (i.e., oral translation) interpreter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "通用",
        "pronunciation": "つうよう",
        "back": "popular use, circulation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "通路",
        "pronunciation": "つうろ",
        "back": "passage, pathway",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "突き当たり",
        "pronunciation": "つきあたり",
        "back": "end (e.g., of street)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "突き当たる",
        "pronunciation": "つきあたる",
        "back": "to run into, to collide with",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "月日",
        "pronunciation": "つきひ",
        "back": "time, years, days",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "次ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "つぐ",
        "back": "to follow, to come after, to come next (to)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "伝わる",
        "pronunciation": "つたわる",
        "back": "to spread (of a rumor, news, etc.), to travel, to circulate, to go around, to be passed around, to become known",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "突っ込む",
        "pronunciation": "つっこむ",
        "back": "to plunge into, to stick into",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "務める",
        "pronunciation": "つとめる",
        "back": "to serve, to act",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "努める",
        "pronunciation": "つとめる",
        "back": "to try, to aim",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "綱",
        "pronunciation": "つな",
        "back": "rope",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "繋がり",
        "pronunciation": "つながり",
        "back": "connection, link, relationship",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "繋がる",
        "pronunciation": "つながる",
        "back": "to be tied together, to be connected to, to be linked to",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "粒",
        "pronunciation": "つぶ",
        "back": "grain",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "潰す",
        "pronunciation": "つぶす",
        "back": "to smash, to waste",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "潰れる",
        "pronunciation": "つぶれる",
        "back": "to be smashed, to go bankrupt",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "つまずく",
        "pronunciation": "つまずく",
        "back": "to stumble, to trip",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "躓く",
        "pronunciation": "つまずく",
        "back": "to trip (over), to stumble",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "詰まる",
        "pronunciation": "つまる",
        "back": "to be blocked, to be packed",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "積む",
        "pronunciation": "つむ",
        "back": "to pile up, to stack",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "爪",
        "pronunciation": "つめ",
        "back": "fingernail or toenail",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "艶",
        "pronunciation": "つや",
        "back": "gloss, glaze",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "強気",
        "pronunciation": "つよき",
        "back": "firm, strong",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "釣り合う",
        "pronunciation": "つりあう",
        "back": "to balance, to be in harmony, to suit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "吊る",
        "pronunciation": "つる",
        "back": "to hang",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "吊す",
        "pronunciation": "つるす",
        "back": "to hang",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "テーマ",
        "pronunciation": "テーマ",
        "back": "theme, project, topic (GER: Thema)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "手洗い",
        "pronunciation": "てあらい",
        "back": "restroom, lavatory",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "低～",
        "pronunciation": "てい～",
        "back": "low ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "定員",
        "pronunciation": "ていいん",
        "back": "fixed number of regular personnel, capacity (e.g., of boat)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "定価",
        "pronunciation": "ていか",
        "back": "established price",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "低下",
        "pronunciation": "ていか",
        "back": "fall, decline",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "定期券",
        "pronunciation": "ていきけん",
        "back": "commuter pass, season ticket",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "定休日",
        "pronunciation": "ていきゅうび",
        "back": "regular holiday",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "停止",
        "pronunciation": "ていし",
        "back": "suspension, interruption, stoppage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "停車",
        "pronunciation": "ていしゃ",
        "back": "stopping (e.g., train)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "停電",
        "pronunciation": "ていでん",
        "back": "power outage, electricity outage, blackout",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "出入り",
        "pronunciation": "でいり",
        "back": "in and out, coming and going",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "出入口",
        "pronunciation": "でいりぐち",
        "back": "exit and entrance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "出入り口",
        "pronunciation": "でいりぐち",
        "back": "exit and entrance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "手入れ",
        "pronunciation": "ていれ",
        "back": "repairs, maintenance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "出来上がり",
        "pronunciation": "できあがり",
        "back": "be finished, ready",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "出来上がる",
        "pronunciation": "できあがる",
        "back": "to be finished, to be ready",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "的確",
        "pronunciation": "てきかく",
        "back": "precise, accurate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "適確",
        "pronunciation": "てきかく",
        "back": "precise, accurate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "手首",
        "pronunciation": "てくび",
        "back": "wrist",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "凸凹",
        "pronunciation": "でこぼこ",
        "back": "unevenness, roughness, ruggedness",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "手頃",
        "pronunciation": "てごろ",
        "back": "moderate, handy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "手ごろ",
        "pronunciation": "てごろ",
        "back": "handy, convenient suitable, reasoanble, moderate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "弟子",
        "pronunciation": "でし",
        "back": "pupil, disciple, apprentice",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "でたらめ",
        "pronunciation": "でたらめ",
        "back": "irresponsible utterance, nonsense; random",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "手帳",
        "pronunciation": "てちょう",
        "back": "notebook",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉄橋",
        "pronunciation": "てっきょう",
        "back": "iron bridge",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "手続き",
        "pronunciation": "てつづき",
        "back": "procedure, (legal) process, formalities",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉄砲",
        "pronunciation": "てっぽう",
        "back": "gun",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "テニスコート",
        "pronunciation": "テニスコート",
        "back": "tennis court",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "手拭い",
        "pronunciation": "てぬぐい",
        "back": "(hand) towel",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "手前",
        "pronunciation": "てまえ",
        "back": "before, this side",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "出迎え",
        "pronunciation": "でむかえ",
        "back": "meeting, reception",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "出迎える",
        "pronunciation": "でむかえる",
        "back": "to meet, to greet",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "照らす",
        "pronunciation": "てらす",
        "back": "to shine on, to illuminate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "照る",
        "pronunciation": "てる",
        "back": "to shine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "展開",
        "pronunciation": "てんかい",
        "back": "develop, expansion (opposite of compression)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "伝記",
        "pronunciation": "でんき",
        "back": "biography, life story",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "電球",
        "pronunciation": "でんきゅう",
        "back": "light bulb",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "点数",
        "pronunciation": "てんすう",
        "back": "marks, points, score",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "伝染",
        "pronunciation": "でんせん",
        "back": "contagion",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "電池",
        "pronunciation": "でんち",
        "back": "battery",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "電柱",
        "pronunciation": "でんちゅう",
        "back": "telephone pole, telegraph pole, light pole",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "点々",
        "pronunciation": "てんてん",
        "back": "here and there, little by little",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "転々",
        "pronunciation": "てんてん",
        "back": "from one to another",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "天皇",
        "pronunciation": "てんのう",
        "back": "Emperor of Japan",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "電波",
        "pronunciation": "でんぱ",
        "back": "electro-magnetic wave",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "テンポ",
        "pronunciation": "テンポ",
        "back": "tempo",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "電流",
        "pronunciation": "でんりゅう",
        "back": "electric current",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "電力",
        "pronunciation": "でんりょく",
        "back": "electric power",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "問い合わせ",
        "pronunciation": "といあわせ",
        "back": "inquiry",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "銅",
        "pronunciation": "どう",
        "back": "copper",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "同～",
        "pronunciation": "どう～",
        "back": "same ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "どういたしまして (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "どういたしまして (かん)",
        "back": "you are welcome, don't mention it",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "統一",
        "pronunciation": "とういつ",
        "back": "unity, consolidation, uniformity",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "同格",
        "pronunciation": "どうかく",
        "back": "the same rank, equality, apposition",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "峠",
        "pronunciation": "とうげ",
        "back": "ridge, (mountain) pass, difficult part",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "統計",
        "pronunciation": "とうけい",
        "back": "scattering, a scatter, dispersion",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "動作",
        "pronunciation": "どうさ",
        "back": "action, movements, motions",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "東西",
        "pronunciation": "とうざい",
        "back": "East and West, whole country",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "当日",
        "pronunciation": "とうじつ",
        "back": "appointed day, very day",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "投書",
        "pronunciation": "とうしょ",
        "back": "letter to the editor, letter from a reader, contribution",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "登場",
        "pronunciation": "とうじょう",
        "back": "entry (on stage)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "どうせ",
        "pronunciation": "どうせ",
        "back": "anyhow, in any case, at any rate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "灯台",
        "pronunciation": "とうだい",
        "back": "lighthouse",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "盗難",
        "pronunciation": "とうなん",
        "back": "theft, robbery",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "当番",
        "pronunciation": "とうばん",
        "back": "being on duty",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "等分",
        "pronunciation": "とうぶん",
        "back": "division into equal parts",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "透明",
        "pronunciation": "とうめい",
        "back": "transparency, cleanness",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "灯油",
        "pronunciation": "とうゆ",
        "back": "lamp oil, kerosene",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "東洋",
        "pronunciation": "とうよう",
        "back": "the East, the Orient",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "童話",
        "pronunciation": "どうわ",
        "back": "fairy tale",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "通り掛かる",
        "pronunciation": "とおりかかる",
        "back": "to happen to pass by",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "溶かす",
        "pronunciation": "とかす",
        "back": "to melt, to dissolve",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "尖る",
        "pronunciation": "とがる",
        "back": "to taper to a point, to become sharp",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "どきどき",
        "pronunciation": "どきどき",
        "back": "throb, beat (fast)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "特殊",
        "pronunciation": "とくしゅ",
        "back": "special, unique",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "特色",
        "pronunciation": "とくしょく",
        "back": "characteristic, feature",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "特定",
        "pronunciation": "とくてい",
        "back": "specific, special, particular",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "特売",
        "pronunciation": "とくばい",
        "back": "special sale",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "溶け込む",
        "pronunciation": "とけこむ",
        "back": "to melt into; to become a part of",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "溶ける",
        "pronunciation": "とける",
        "back": "(intransitive) to melt, to thaw, to fuse, to dissolve",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "退ける",
        "pronunciation": "どける",
        "back": "to dislodge, to put something out of the way",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "床の間",
        "pronunciation": "とこのま",
        "back": "alcove",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "所々",
        "pronunciation": "ところどころ",
        "back": "here and there, some parts (of something)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "都心",
        "pronunciation": "としん",
        "back": "heart (of city)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "戸棚",
        "pronunciation": "とだな",
        "back": "cupboard, cabinet",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "とっくに",
        "pronunciation": "とっくに",
        "back": "long ago, already, a long time ago",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "どっと",
        "pronunciation": "どっと",
        "back": "suddenly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "整う",
        "pronunciation": "ととのう",
        "back": "to be prepared, to be in order, to be arranged",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "留まる",
        "pronunciation": "とどまる",
        "back": "to be fixed; to abide, to stay (in the one place)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "怒鳴る",
        "pronunciation": "どなる",
        "back": "to shout, to yell",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "殿",
        "pronunciation": "どの",
        "back": "Mister (mostly in addressing someone on an envelope)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "飛び込む",
        "pronunciation": "とびこむ",
        "back": "to jump in, to leap in, to plunge into",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "留まる",
        "pronunciation": "とまる",
        "back": "to be fixed; to abide, to stay (in the one place)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "泊める",
        "pronunciation": "とめる",
        "back": "to give shelter to, to lodge",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ともかく",
        "pronunciation": "ともかく",
        "back": "anyhow, at any rate, anyway",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "捕える",
        "pronunciation": "とらえる",
        "back": "to seize, to capture, to arrest",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り入れる",
        "pronunciation": "とりいれる",
        "back": "to harvest, to take in, to adopt",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り消す",
        "pronunciation": "とりけす",
        "back": "to cancel",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り出す",
        "pronunciation": "とりだす",
        "back": "to take out, to pick out",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "採る",
        "pronunciation": "とる",
        "back": "to adopt (measure, proposal); to pick (fruit)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "捕る",
        "pronunciation": "とる",
        "back": "to take, to catch (fish)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "丼",
        "pronunciation": "どんぶり",
        "back": "porcelain bowl, bowl of rice with food on top",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "内科",
        "pronunciation": "ないか",
        "back": "internist clinic, internal medicine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "内線",
        "pronunciation": "ないせん",
        "back": "phone extension",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ナイロン",
        "pronunciation": "ナイロン",
        "back": "nylon",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "長～",
        "pronunciation": "なが～",
        "back": "long ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "仲直り",
        "pronunciation": "なかなおり",
        "back": "reconciliation, make peace with",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "長引く",
        "pronunciation": "ながびく",
        "back": "to be prolonged, to drag on",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "中身",
        "pronunciation": "なかみ",
        "back": "contents, interior, filling substance, content",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "中指",
        "pronunciation": "なかゆび",
        "back": "middle finger",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "仲良し",
        "pronunciation": "なかよし",
        "back": "intimate friend, bosom buddy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "慰める",
        "pronunciation": "なぐさめる",
        "back": "to comfort, to console",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "殴る",
        "pronunciation": "なぐる",
        "back": "to strike, to hit, to beat, to punch",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "為す",
        "pronunciation": "なす",
        "back": "to accomplish, to do",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "謎謎",
        "pronunciation": "なぞなぞ",
        "back": "riddle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "傾らか",
        "pronunciation": "なだらか",
        "back": "gradual, gentle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "懐かしい",
        "pronunciation": "なつかしい",
        "back": "dear, desired, missed",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "撫でる",
        "pronunciation": "なでる",
        "back": "to brush gently, to stroke",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "斜め",
        "pronunciation": "ななめ",
        "back": "diagonal, oblique",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "なにしろ",
        "pronunciation": "なにしろ",
        "back": "at any rate, in any case",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "何しろ",
        "pronunciation": "なにしろ",
        "back": "in any case, at any rate, anyhow, anyway, as you know, for you see, particularly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "何々",
        "pronunciation": "なになに",
        "back": "such and such, What?",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "何分",
        "pronunciation": "なにぶん",
        "back": "by all means, please",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "生意気",
        "pronunciation": "なまいき",
        "back": "impertinent, impudent",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "生意気な",
        "pronunciation": "なまいきな",
        "back": "impertinent, saucy, cheeky, impudent, audacious, cocky, pert, brash",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "並木",
        "pronunciation": "なみき",
        "back": "roadside tree, row of trees",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "倣う",
        "pronunciation": "ならう",
        "back": "to imitate, to follow, to emulate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "生る",
        "pronunciation": "なる",
        "back": "to bear fruit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "南極",
        "pronunciation": "なんきょく",
        "back": "south pole, Antarctic",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "なんとなく",
        "pronunciation": "なんとなく",
        "back": "somehow or other, for some reason or another",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "なんとも",
        "pronunciation": "なんとも",
        "back": "nothing (with neg. verb), quite, not a bit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "何とも",
        "pronunciation": "なんとも",
        "back": "really, very, extremely, terribly, awfully (not) anything, (not) at all, (not) a bit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ナンバー",
        "pronunciation": "ナンバー",
        "back": "number",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "南米",
        "pronunciation": "なんべい",
        "back": "South America",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "南北",
        "pronunciation": "なんぼく",
        "back": "south and north",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "匂う",
        "pronunciation": "におう",
        "back": "to be fragrant, to smell",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "逃がす",
        "pronunciation": "にがす",
        "back": "to let loose, to set free, to let escape",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "憎い",
        "pronunciation": "にくい",
        "back": "hateful, abominable, detestable",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "憎む",
        "pronunciation": "にくむ",
        "back": "to hate, to detest",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "憎らしい",
        "pronunciation": "にくらしい",
        "back": "odious, hateful",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "にこにこ",
        "pronunciation": "にこにこ",
        "back": "smile sweetly, smiley",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "濁る",
        "pronunciation": "にごる",
        "back": "to become muddy, to get cloudy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "虹",
        "pronunciation": "にじ",
        "back": "rainbow",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日時",
        "pronunciation": "にちじ",
        "back": "date and time",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日用品",
        "pronunciation": "にちようひん",
        "back": "daily necessities",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日課",
        "pronunciation": "にっか",
        "back": "daily work, daily routine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日程",
        "pronunciation": "にってい",
        "back": "schedule",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "鈍い",
        "pronunciation": "にぶい",
        "back": "dull (e.g., a knife), thickheaded, slow (opposite of fast), stupid",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "入社",
        "pronunciation": "にゅうしゃ",
        "back": "entry to a company",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "女房",
        "pronunciation": "にょうぼう",
        "back": "wife",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "睨む",
        "pronunciation": "にらむ",
        "back": "to glare at, to stare; to keep an eye on",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "煮る",
        "pronunciation": "にる",
        "back": "to boil, to simmer, to stew, seethe",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "俄",
        "pronunciation": "にわか",
        "back": "sudden, abrupt, unexpected",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "縫う",
        "pronunciation": "ぬう",
        "back": "to sew",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ねじ",
        "pronunciation": "ねじ",
        "back": "(a) screw",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "捩る",
        "pronunciation": "ねじる",
        "back": "to twist",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ネックレス",
        "pronunciation": "ネックレス",
        "back": "necklace",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "熱する",
        "pronunciation": "ねっする",
        "back": "to heat",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "寝間着",
        "pronunciation": "ねまき",
        "back": "sleep-wear, pajamas",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "寝巻",
        "pronunciation": "ねまき",
        "back": "sleep-wear, pajamas",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "狙い",
        "pronunciation": "ねらい",
        "back": "aim",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "狙う",
        "pronunciation": "ねらう",
        "back": "to aim at",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "年度",
        "pronunciation": "ねんど",
        "back": "year, fiscal year",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "農産物",
        "pronunciation": "のうさんぶつ",
        "back": "agricultural produce",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "農村",
        "pronunciation": "のうそん",
        "back": "agricultural community",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "濃度",
        "pronunciation": "のうど",
        "back": "concentration, density",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "農薬",
        "pronunciation": "のうやく",
        "back": "agricultural chemicals",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "能率",
        "pronunciation": "のうりつ",
        "back": "efficiency",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "のこぎり",
        "pronunciation": "のこぎり",
        "back": "saw",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "残らず",
        "pronunciation": "のこらず",
        "back": "completely, without exception",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "上り",
        "pronunciation": "のぼり",
        "back": "up-train (going to Tokyo), ascent",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "糊",
        "pronunciation": "のり",
        "back": "glue, paste, starch",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "乗換",
        "pronunciation": "のりかえ",
        "back": "a transfer (e.g., trains, buses)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "乗り換え",
        "pronunciation": "のりかえ",
        "back": "(n) transfer (trains, buses, etc.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "乗り越し",
        "pronunciation": "のりこし",
        "back": "riding past (one's station)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "鈍い",
        "pronunciation": "のろい",
        "back": "dull (e.g., a knife), slow (opposite of fast), stupid",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "のろのろ",
        "pronunciation": "のろのろ",
        "back": "slowly, sluggishly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "呑気",
        "pronunciation": "のんき",
        "back": "carefree, optimistic, careless",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "はい (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "はい (かん)",
        "back": "yes",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "灰色",
        "pronunciation": "はいいろ",
        "back": "grey, ashen",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "俳句",
        "pronunciation": "はいく",
        "back": "haiku poetry",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "売店",
        "pronunciation": "ばいてん",
        "back": "shop, stand",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "バイバイ",
        "pronunciation": "バイバイ",
        "back": "bye bye",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "売買",
        "pronunciation": "ばいばい",
        "back": "trade, buying and selling",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "這う",
        "pronunciation": "はう",
        "back": "to creep, to crawl",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "剥す",
        "pronunciation": "はがす",
        "back": "to tear off, to peel off, to rip off",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "剥がす",
        "pronunciation": "はがす",
        "back": "to tear off, to peel off, to rip off, to strip off, to skin, to flay, to disrobe, to deprive of, to detach, to disconnect",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ばからしい",
        "pronunciation": "ばからしい",
        "back": "absurd",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "秤",
        "pronunciation": "はかり",
        "back": "scales, weighing machine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "吐き気",
        "pronunciation": "はきけ",
        "back": "nausea, sickness in the stomach",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "はきはき",
        "pronunciation": "はきはき",
        "back": "clearly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "掃く",
        "pronunciation": "はく",
        "back": "to sweep, to brush, to gather up",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "歯車",
        "pronunciation": "はぐるま",
        "back": "gear, cog-wheel",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "バケツ",
        "pronunciation": "バケツ",
        "back": "bucket, pail",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "挟まる",
        "pronunciation": "はさまる",
        "back": "to get between, to be caught in",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "挟む",
        "pronunciation": "はさむ",
        "back": "to pinch; to hold between; to insert",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "梯子",
        "pronunciation": "はしご",
        "back": "ladder, stairs",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "始めに",
        "pronunciation": "はじめに",
        "back": "to begin with, first of all",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "初めに",
        "pronunciation": "はじめに",
        "back": "to begin with, first of all",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "はじめまして",
        "pronunciation": "はじめまして",
        "back": "How do you do, I am glad to meet you",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "斜",
        "pronunciation": "はす",
        "back": "diagonal",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "外れる",
        "pronunciation": "はずれる",
        "back": "to be disconnected, to get out of place, to be off, to be out (e.g., of gear)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "パターン",
        "pronunciation": "パターン",
        "back": "pattern",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "肌着",
        "pronunciation": "はだぎ",
        "back": "underwear",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "果して",
        "pronunciation": "はたして",
        "back": "as was expected, really",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "果たして",
        "pronunciation": "はたして",
        "back": "as was expected, just as one thought, sure enough",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉢",
        "pronunciation": "はち",
        "back": "a bowl, a pot",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "発",
        "pronunciation": "はつ",
        "back": "to depart (e.g., on a plane, train)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "×",
        "pronunciation": "ばつ",
        "back": "cross",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "発揮",
        "pronunciation": "はっき",
        "back": "exhibition, demonstration, display",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "バック",
        "pronunciation": "バック",
        "back": "back",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "発想",
        "pronunciation": "はっそう",
        "back": "idea; way of thinking (same as 考え方 (かんがえかた))",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "発電",
        "pronunciation": "はつでん",
        "back": "generation (e.g., power)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "発売",
        "pronunciation": "はつばい",
        "back": "sale",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "派手",
        "pronunciation": "はで",
        "back": "showy, loud, flashy, gaudy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "話合い",
        "pronunciation": "はなしあい",
        "back": "discussion, talk",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "話し合い",
        "pronunciation": "はなしあい",
        "back": "discussion, talk, conference",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "話し掛ける",
        "pronunciation": "はなしかける",
        "back": "to accost a person, to talk (to someone)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "話中",
        "pronunciation": "はなしちゅう",
        "back": "while talking, the line is busy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "甚だしい",
        "pronunciation": "はなはだしい",
        "back": "extreme, excessive, terrible",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "花火",
        "pronunciation": "はなび",
        "back": "fireworks",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "花嫁",
        "pronunciation": "はなよめ",
        "back": "bride",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ばね",
        "pronunciation": "ばね",
        "back": "spring (e.g., coil, leaf)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "跳ねる",
        "pronunciation": "はねる",
        "back": "to jump, to leap",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "破片",
        "pronunciation": "はへん",
        "back": "fragment, broken piece",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "歯磨き",
        "pronunciation": "はみがき",
        "back": "toothbrushing, toothpaste",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "はめる",
        "pronunciation": "はめる",
        "back": "(col) to get in, to insert, to put on",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "早口",
        "pronunciation": "はやくち",
        "back": "fast-talking",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "払い込む",
        "pronunciation": "はらいこむ",
        "back": "to deposit, to pay in",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "払い戻す",
        "pronunciation": "はらいもどす",
        "back": "to repay, to pay back",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "針金",
        "pronunciation": "はりがね",
        "back": "wire",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "張り切る",
        "pronunciation": "はりきる",
        "back": "to be in high spirits, to be full of vigor",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "反～",
        "pronunciation": "はん～",
        "back": "anti ~, counter ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "反映",
        "pronunciation": "はんえい",
        "back": "reflection, influence",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "半径",
        "pronunciation": "はんけい",
        "back": "radius",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "判子",
        "pronunciation": "はんこ",
        "back": "seal (used for signature)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "万歳",
        "pronunciation": "ばんざい",
        "back": "banzai, Long live ~!",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "判事",
        "pronunciation": "はんじ",
        "back": "judge, justice",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "反省",
        "pronunciation": "はんせい",
        "back": "reflection, reconsideration",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "番地",
        "pronunciation": "ばんち",
        "back": "house number, address",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "パンツ",
        "pronunciation": "パンツ",
        "back": "underpants",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "バンド",
        "pronunciation": "バンド",
        "back": "band",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "半島",
        "pronunciation": "はんとう",
        "back": "peninsula",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ハンドル",
        "pronunciation": "ハンドル",
        "back": "handle, steering wheel",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "非～",
        "pronunciation": "ひ～",
        "back": "anti~, counter~, an~, non~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日当たり",
        "pronunciation": "ひあたり",
        "back": "exposure to the sun, sunny place",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日帰り",
        "pronunciation": "ひがえり",
        "back": "day trip",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "比較的",
        "pronunciation": "ひかくてき",
        "back": "comparatively; relatively",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日陰",
        "pronunciation": "ひかげ",
        "back": "shadow",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぴかぴか",
        "pronunciation": "ぴかぴか",
        "back": "glitter, sparkle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引受る",
        "pronunciation": "ひきうける",
        "back": "to undertake, to take up, to take over",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引き返す",
        "pronunciation": "ひきかえす",
        "back": "to turn back, to go back, reverse",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引算",
        "pronunciation": "ひきざん",
        "back": "subtraction",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引き出す",
        "pronunciation": "ひきだす",
        "back": "to pull out, to take out, to withdraw",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引き止める",
        "pronunciation": "ひきとめる",
        "back": "to keep back, to prevent, to hold back",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "卑怯",
        "pronunciation": "ひきょう",
        "back": "cowardice, meanness, unfairness",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引分け",
        "pronunciation": "ひきわけ",
        "back": "a draw (in competition), tie game",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引き分け",
        "pronunciation": "ひきわけ",
        "back": "draw (in competition), tie game",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "陽射",
        "pronunciation": "ひざし",
        "back": "sunlight, rays of the sun",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日差し",
        "pronunciation": "ひざし",
        "back": "sunlight",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "肘",
        "pronunciation": "ひじ",
        "back": "elbow",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ピストル",
        "pronunciation": "ピストル",
        "back": "pistol",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ビタミン",
        "pronunciation": "ビタミン",
        "back": "vitamin",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぴたり",
        "pronunciation": "ぴたり",
        "back": "exactly; close-fitting",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引っ掛かる",
        "pronunciation": "ひっかかる",
        "back": "to be caught in, to be stuck in",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "筆記",
        "pronunciation": "ひっき",
        "back": "note taking, writing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引っ繰り返す",
        "pronunciation": "ひっくりかえす",
        "back": "to turn over, to overturn, to knock over",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引っ繰り返る",
        "pronunciation": "ひっくりかえる",
        "back": "to be overturned, to be upset, to topple over, to be reversed",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引っ越し",
        "pronunciation": "ひっこし",
        "back": "moving (dwelling, office, etc.), changing residence",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "引っ込む",
        "pronunciation": "ひっこむ",
        "back": "to draw back, to sink, to cave in",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "筆者",
        "pronunciation": "ひっしゃ",
        "back": "writer, author",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "必需品",
        "pronunciation": "ひつじゅひん",
        "back": "necessities, essential",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一～",
        "pronunciation": "ひと～",
        "back": "one ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "人差指",
        "pronunciation": "ひとさしゆび",
        "back": "index finger",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一通り",
        "pronunciation": "ひととおり",
        "back": "general, briefly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "人通り",
        "pronunciation": "ひとどおり",
        "back": "pedestrian traffic",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ひとまず",
        "pronunciation": "ひとまず",
        "back": "for the present, once, for the time being",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "瞳",
        "pronunciation": "ひとみ",
        "back": "pupil (of eye)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "一休み",
        "pronunciation": "ひとやすみ",
        "back": "a rest",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "独り言",
        "pronunciation": "ひとりごと",
        "back": "a soliloquy, a monologue, speaking to oneself",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ひとりでに",
        "pronunciation": "ひとりでに",
        "back": "by itself, automatically, naturally",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ビニール",
        "pronunciation": "ビニール",
        "back": "vinyl",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "皮肉",
        "pronunciation": "ひにく",
        "back": "cynicism, sarcasm",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日日",
        "pronunciation": "ひにち",
        "back": "date",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日にち",
        "pronunciation": "ひにち",
        "back": "date (of a planned event, act, etc.), day",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "捻る",
        "pronunciation": "ひねる",
        "back": "to twist, to turn",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日の入り",
        "pronunciation": "ひのいり",
        "back": "sunset",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "日の出",
        "pronunciation": "ひので",
        "back": "sunrise",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "響き",
        "pronunciation": "ひびき",
        "back": "echo, sound",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "響く",
        "pronunciation": "ひびく",
        "back": "to resound; to affect",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "皮膚",
        "pronunciation": "ひふ",
        "back": "skin",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷やす",
        "pronunciation": "ひやす",
        "back": "to cool (from room temperature), to chill, to refrigerate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ひゃっかじてん",
        "pronunciation": "ひゃっかじてん",
        "back": "encyclopedia",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "百科事典",
        "pronunciation": "ひゃっかじてん",
        "back": "encyclopedia",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "美容",
        "pronunciation": "びよう",
        "back": "beauty of figure or form",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "表紙",
        "pronunciation": "ひょうし",
        "back": "front cover, binding",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "標識",
        "pronunciation": "ひょうしき",
        "back": "sign, mark",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "標準",
        "pronunciation": "ひょうじゅん",
        "back": "standard, level",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "標本",
        "pronunciation": "ひょうほん",
        "back": "example, specimen",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "評論",
        "pronunciation": "ひょうろん",
        "back": "criticism, critique",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ビルディング",
        "pronunciation": "ビルディング",
        "back": "building",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "昼寝",
        "pronunciation": "ひるね",
        "back": "nap (at home), siesta",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "広げる",
        "pronunciation": "ひろげる",
        "back": "to spread, to extend, to expand, to enlarge, to widen, to broaden",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "広さ",
        "pronunciation": "ひろさ",
        "back": "extent",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "広場",
        "pronunciation": "ひろば",
        "back": "plaza",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "広々",
        "pronunciation": "ひろびろ",
        "back": "extensive, spacious",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ピンク",
        "pronunciation": "ピンク",
        "back": "pink",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "便箋",
        "pronunciation": "びんせん",
        "back": "writing paper, stationery",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "瓶詰",
        "pronunciation": "びんづめ",
        "back": "bottling, bottled",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ファスナー",
        "pronunciation": "ファスナー",
        "back": "fastener, zipper",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "風船",
        "pronunciation": "ふうせん",
        "back": "balloon",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "不運",
        "pronunciation": "ふうん",
        "back": "unlucky, misfortune, bad luck",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "深まる",
        "pronunciation": "ふかまる",
        "back": "to deepen, to heighten, to intensify",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "不規則",
        "pronunciation": "ふきそく",
        "back": "irregularity, unsteadiness",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "普及",
        "pronunciation": "ふきゅう",
        "back": "diffusion, spread",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "付近",
        "pronunciation": "ふきん",
        "back": "neighborhood, vicinity",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "副～",
        "pronunciation": "ふく～",
        "back": "vice ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "副詞",
        "pronunciation": "ふくし",
        "back": "adverb",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "複写",
        "pronunciation": "ふくしゃ",
        "back": "copy, duplicate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "複数",
        "pronunciation": "ふくすう",
        "back": "plural, multiple",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ふくめる",
        "pronunciation": "ふくめる",
        "back": "to include, to instruct, to make one understand",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "膨らます",
        "pronunciation": "ふくらます",
        "back": "to swell, to expand, to inflate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "膨らむ",
        "pronunciation": "ふくらむ",
        "back": "to expand, to swell (out), to become inflated",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "不潔",
        "pronunciation": "ふけつ",
        "back": "unclean, dirty",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "更ける",
        "pronunciation": "ふける",
        "back": "to get late, to wear on",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "符号",
        "pronunciation": "ふごう",
        "back": "sign, mark, symbol",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "夫妻",
        "pronunciation": "ふさい",
        "back": "man and wife, married couple",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "塞がる",
        "pronunciation": "ふさがる",
        "back": "to be plugged up, to be shut up",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "塞ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "ふさぐ",
        "back": "to stuff, to close up, to block (up)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ふざける",
        "pronunciation": "ふざける",
        "back": "to romp, to gambol, to frolic",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "無沙汰",
        "pronunciation": "ぶさた",
        "back": "neglecting to stay in contact",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "武士",
        "pronunciation": "ぶし",
        "back": "warrior, samurai",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "部首",
        "pronunciation": "ぶしゅ",
        "back": "radical (of a kanji character)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "蒸す",
        "pronunciation": "ふす",
        "back": "to steam (food, towel, etc.) to be hot and humid, to be sultry",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "襖",
        "pronunciation": "ふすま",
        "back": "sliding screen",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "附属",
        "pronunciation": "ふぞく",
        "back": "attached, belonging, affiliated",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "付属",
        "pronunciation": "ふぞく",
        "back": "being attached (to), being affiliated (to), belonging (to), going with",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "蓋",
        "pronunciation": "ふた",
        "back": "cover, lid, cap",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "不通",
        "pronunciation": "ふつう",
        "back": "suspension, interruption, stoppage, tie-up, cessation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "物騒",
        "pronunciation": "ぶっそう",
        "back": "dangerous, disturbed, insecure",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぶつぶつ",
        "pronunciation": "ぶつぶつ",
        "back": "grumbling, complaining in a small voice",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "船便",
        "pronunciation": "ふなびん",
        "back": "surface mail (ship)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "部品",
        "pronunciation": "ぶひん",
        "back": "parts, accessories",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "吹雪",
        "pronunciation": "ふぶき",
        "back": "snow storm",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "父母",
        "pronunciation": "ふぼ",
        "back": "father and mother, parents",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "踏切",
        "pronunciation": "ふみきり",
        "back": "railway crossing, level crossing, starting line, scratch, crossover",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "麓",
        "pronunciation": "ふもと",
        "back": "the foot, the bottom, the base (of a mountain)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "フライパン",
        "pronunciation": "フライパン",
        "back": "fry pan, frying pan",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ブラウス",
        "pronunciation": "ブラウス",
        "back": "blouse",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぶらさげる",
        "pronunciation": "ぶらさげる",
        "back": "to hang, to suspend, to swing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ブラシ",
        "pronunciation": "ブラシ",
        "back": "brush",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "プラットホーム",
        "pronunciation": "プラットホーム",
        "back": "platform",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "フリー",
        "pronunciation": "フリー",
        "back": "free",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "振り仮名",
        "pronunciation": "ふりがな",
        "back": "pronunciation key",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "振り向く",
        "pronunciation": "ふりむく",
        "back": "to turn one's face, to turn around",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "プリント",
        "pronunciation": "プリント",
        "back": "print, handout",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "古～",
        "pronunciation": "ふる～",
        "back": "old ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "故郷",
        "pronunciation": "ふるさと",
        "back": "home town, birthplace",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "古里",
        "pronunciation": "ふるさと",
        "back": "home town, birthplace",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "振舞う",
        "pronunciation": "ふるまう",
        "back": "to behave, to conduct",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ブローチ",
        "pronunciation": "ブローチ",
        "back": "brooch",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "プログラム",
        "pronunciation": "プログラム",
        "back": "program",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "風呂敷",
        "pronunciation": "ふろしき",
        "back": "wrapping cloth, cloth wrapper",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ふわふわ",
        "pronunciation": "ふわふわ",
        "back": "light, soft",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "噴火",
        "pronunciation": "ふんか",
        "back": "eruption",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "分解",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんかい",
        "back": "analysis, disassembly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "文芸",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんげい",
        "back": "literature, art and literature",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "文献",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんけん",
        "back": "literature, books (reference)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "噴水",
        "pronunciation": "ふんすい",
        "back": "water fountain",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "分数",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんすう",
        "back": "fraction (in math)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "文体",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんたい",
        "back": "literary style",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "分布",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんぷ",
        "back": "distribution",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "文房具",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんぼうぐ",
        "back": "stationery",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "文脈",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんみゃく",
        "back": "context",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "分量",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんりょう",
        "back": "amount, quantity",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "分類",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんるい",
        "back": "classification",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "閉会",
        "pronunciation": "へいかい",
        "back": "closure",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "平気",
        "pronunciation": "へいき",
        "back": "coolness, calmness, unconcern",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "並行",
        "pronunciation": "へいこう",
        "back": "(going) side by side, concurrent, at the same time",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "平日",
        "pronunciation": "へいじつ",
        "back": "weekday",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "兵隊",
        "pronunciation": "へいたい",
        "back": "soldier",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "平凡",
        "pronunciation": "へいぼん",
        "back": "common, ordinary",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "平野",
        "pronunciation": "へいや",
        "back": "plain, open field",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "凹む",
        "pronunciation": "へこむ",
        "back": "to be dented, to be indented",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "へそ",
        "pronunciation": "へそ",
        "back": "navel, belly-button",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "隔てる",
        "pronunciation": "へだてる",
        "back": "to be shut out",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "別荘",
        "pronunciation": "べっそう",
        "back": "villa; vacation home; summer cottage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "別々",
        "pronunciation": "べつべつ",
        "back": "separately, individually",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ベテラン",
        "pronunciation": "ベテラン",
        "back": "veteran",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ヘリコプター",
        "pronunciation": "ヘリコプター",
        "back": "helicopter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "編集",
        "pronunciation": "へんしゅう",
        "back": "editing, compilation, editorial (e.g., committee)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "便所",
        "pronunciation": "べんじょ",
        "back": "toilet, lavatory",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ペンチ",
        "pronunciation": "ペンチ",
        "back": "pliers (lit: pinchers)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ボーナス",
        "pronunciation": "ボーナス",
        "back": "bonus",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "防～",
        "pronunciation": "ぼう～",
        "back": "~ prevention",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "望遠鏡",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうえんきょう",
        "back": "telescope",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "方角",
        "pronunciation": "ほうがく",
        "back": "direction, way",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "箒",
        "pronunciation": "ほうき",
        "back": "broom",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "方言",
        "pronunciation": "ほうげん",
        "back": "dialect",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "坊さん",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうさん",
        "back": "Buddhist priest, monk",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "防止",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうし",
        "back": "prevention, check",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "方針",
        "pronunciation": "ほうしん",
        "back": "objective, plan, policy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "包装",
        "pronunciation": "ほうそう",
        "back": "packing, wrapping",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "法則",
        "pronunciation": "ほうそく",
        "back": "law, rule",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "包帯",
        "pronunciation": "ほうたい",
        "back": "bandage",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "膨大",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうだい",
        "back": "enormous, extensive",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "包丁",
        "pronunciation": "ほうちょう",
        "back": "kitchen knife, carving knife",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "方程式",
        "pronunciation": "ほうていしき",
        "back": "equation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "防犯",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうはん",
        "back": "prevention of crime",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "方面",
        "pronunciation": "ほうめん",
        "back": "direction; area",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "坊や",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうや",
        "back": "boy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "放る",
        "pronunciation": "ほうる",
        "back": "to let go",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "朗らか",
        "pronunciation": "ほがらか",
        "back": "bright, cheerful, melodious",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "朗らか(な)",
        "pronunciation": "ほがらか(な)",
        "back": "cheerful, merry bright (sky, day, etc.), fine, clear",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "牧場",
        "pronunciation": "ぼくじょう",
        "back": "farm (livestock); pasture land",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "牧畜",
        "pronunciation": "ぼくちく",
        "back": "stock-farming",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "保健",
        "pronunciation": "ほけん",
        "back": "health preservation, hygiene, sanitation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "募集",
        "pronunciation": "ぼしゅう",
        "back": "recruitment",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "干す",
        "pronunciation": "ほす",
        "back": "to air, to dry, to drink up",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ポスター",
        "pronunciation": "ポスター",
        "back": "poster",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "北極",
        "pronunciation": "ほっきょく",
        "back": "North Pole",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "坊っちゃん",
        "pronunciation": "ぼっちゃん",
        "back": "son (of others)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "解く",
        "pronunciation": "ほどく",
        "back": "to unfasten",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "掘る",
        "pronunciation": "ほる",
        "back": "to dig, to excavate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "彫る",
        "pronunciation": "ほる",
        "back": "to carve, to chisel",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぼろ",
        "pronunciation": "ぼろ",
        "back": "rag, tattered clothes",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "盆",
        "pronunciation": "ぼん",
        "back": "Festival of the Dead; tray",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "盆地",
        "pronunciation": "ぼんち",
        "back": "basin (e.g., between mountains)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ほんの～",
        "pronunciation": "ほんの～",
        "back": "mere, just",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "本部",
        "pronunciation": "ほんぶ",
        "back": "headquarters",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "本来",
        "pronunciation": "ほんらい",
        "back": "essentially, naturally, by nature",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "まあまあ",
        "pronunciation": "まあまあ",
        "back": "okay; so-so; decent",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "毎～",
        "pronunciation": "まい～",
        "back": "every ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "枚数",
        "pronunciation": "まいすう",
        "back": "the number of flat things",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "毎度",
        "pronunciation": "まいど",
        "back": "each time, common service-sector greeting",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "まく",
        "pronunciation": "まく",
        "back": "to wind, to coil, to roll",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "枕",
        "pronunciation": "まくら",
        "back": "pillow",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "曲げる",
        "pronunciation": "まげる",
        "back": "to bend, to crook, to lean",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "まごまご",
        "pronunciation": "まごまご",
        "back": "confused, be at a loss",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "摩擦",
        "pronunciation": "まさつ",
        "back": "friction; rubbing; chafe",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "まざる",
        "pronunciation": "まざる",
        "back": "to be mixed, to be blended with, to associate with",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "まじる",
        "pronunciation": "まじる",
        "back": "to be mixed, to be blended with, to associate with",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "マスク",
        "pronunciation": "マスク",
        "back": "mask",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "まぜる",
        "pronunciation": "まぜる",
        "back": "to mix, to stir",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "またぐ",
        "pronunciation": "またぐ",
        "back": "to straddle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "跨ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "またぐ",
        "back": "to step over/across, to stride over/across, to cross to stretch over, to span, to bridge, to saddle, to straddle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "待合室",
        "pronunciation": "まちあいしつ",
        "back": "waiting room",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "待ち合わせる",
        "pronunciation": "まちあわせる",
        "back": "to rendezvous, to meet at a prearranged place and time",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "街角",
        "pronunciation": "まちかど",
        "back": "street corner",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "真っ暗",
        "pronunciation": "まっくら",
        "back": "total darkness",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "真っ黒",
        "pronunciation": "まっくろ",
        "back": "pitch black",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "真っ青",
        "pronunciation": "まっさお",
        "back": "deep blue, ghastly pale",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "真っ先",
        "pronunciation": "まっさき",
        "back": "foremost, beginning",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "真っ白",
        "pronunciation": "まっしろ",
        "back": "pure white",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "祭る",
        "pronunciation": "まつる",
        "back": "to deify, to enshrine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "窓口",
        "pronunciation": "まどぐち",
        "back": "(ticket) window",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "真似る",
        "pronunciation": "まねる",
        "back": "to mimic, to imitate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "まぶた",
        "pronunciation": "まぶた",
        "back": "eyelids",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "マフラー",
        "pronunciation": "マフラー",
        "back": "a winter scarf",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "間も無く",
        "pronunciation": "まもなく",
        "back": "soon, in a short time",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "間もなく",
        "pronunciation": "まもなく",
        "back": "soon, shortly, before long, in a short time, in a little while",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "マラソン",
        "pronunciation": "マラソン",
        "back": "marathon",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "稀",
        "pronunciation": "まれ",
        "back": "rare, seldom",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "回り道",
        "pronunciation": "まわりみち",
        "back": "detour",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "満員",
        "pronunciation": "まんいん",
        "back": "full house, no vacancy, sold out",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "マンション",
        "pronunciation": "マンション",
        "back": "multistory apartment house, condominium",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "満点",
        "pronunciation": "まんてん",
        "back": "perfect score",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "未～",
        "pronunciation": "み～",
        "back": "not yet ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "見上げる",
        "pronunciation": "みあげる",
        "back": "to look up at, to admire",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "見送る",
        "pronunciation": "みおくる",
        "back": "to see off; to escort; to let pass",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "見下ろす",
        "pronunciation": "みおろす",
        "back": "to overlook, to look down on something",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "見掛け",
        "pronunciation": "みかけ",
        "back": "outward appearance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "三日月",
        "pronunciation": "みかづき",
        "back": "crescent moon",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "岬",
        "pronunciation": "みさき",
        "back": "cape (on coast)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "みじめ",
        "pronunciation": "みじめ",
        "back": "sad, pitiful, wretched",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "惨めな",
        "pronunciation": "みじめな",
        "back": "miserable, wretched, unhappy, sad, pitiable",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ミシン",
        "pronunciation": "ミシン",
        "back": "sewing machine",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "自ら",
        "pronunciation": "みずから",
        "back": "for one's self, personally",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "水着",
        "pronunciation": "みずぎ",
        "back": "bathing suit (woman's)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "店屋",
        "pronunciation": "みせや",
        "back": "store, shop",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "見出し",
        "pronunciation": "みだし",
        "back": "heading, index",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "道順",
        "pronunciation": "みちじゅん",
        "back": "itinerary, route",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "みっともない",
        "pronunciation": "みっともない",
        "back": "shameful, indecent",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "見詰める",
        "pronunciation": "みつめる",
        "back": "to stare at, to gaze at",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "見直す",
        "pronunciation": "みなおす",
        "back": "to look over again, to review",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "見慣れる",
        "pronunciation": "みなれる",
        "back": "to become used to seeing, to be familiar with",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "醜い",
        "pronunciation": "みにくい",
        "back": "ugly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "実る",
        "pronunciation": "みのる",
        "back": "to bear fruit, to ripen",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "身分",
        "pronunciation": "みぶん",
        "back": "position, status",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "見本",
        "pronunciation": "みほん",
        "back": "sample",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "見舞う",
        "pronunciation": "みまう",
        "back": "to ask after (health), to visit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "未満",
        "pronunciation": "みまん",
        "back": "less than, insufficient",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "名字",
        "pronunciation": "みょうじ",
        "back": "surname, family name",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ミリ (メートル)",
        "pronunciation": "ミリ (メートル)",
        "back": "milli-",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "診る",
        "pronunciation": "みる",
        "back": "to examine (medically)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "民間",
        "pronunciation": "みんかん",
        "back": "private, civilian",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "民主～",
        "pronunciation": "みんしゅ～",
        "back": "democratic",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "民謡",
        "pronunciation": "みんよう",
        "back": "folk song, popular song",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "無限",
        "pronunciation": "むげん",
        "back": "infinite",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "無地",
        "pronunciation": "むじ",
        "back": "plain",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "蒸し暑い",
        "pronunciation": "むしあつい",
        "back": "humid, sultry",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "矛盾",
        "pronunciation": "むじゅん",
        "back": "contradiction, inconsistency",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "無数",
        "pronunciation": "むすう",
        "back": "countless number, infinite number",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "紫",
        "pronunciation": "むらさき",
        "back": "purple color, violet",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "群れ",
        "pronunciation": "むれ",
        "back": "crowd, flock, herd",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "姪",
        "pronunciation": "めい",
        "back": "niece",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "名～",
        "pronunciation": "めい～",
        "back": "famous ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "名作",
        "pronunciation": "めいさく",
        "back": "masterpiece",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "名詞",
        "pronunciation": "めいし",
        "back": "noun",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "名刺",
        "pronunciation": "めいし",
        "back": "business card",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "名所",
        "pronunciation": "めいしょ",
        "back": "famous place",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "迷信",
        "pronunciation": "めいしん",
        "back": "superstition",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "命ずる",
        "pronunciation": "めいずる",
        "back": "to command, to appoint",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "名物",
        "pronunciation": "めいぶつ",
        "back": "famous product, special product, speciality",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "銘々",
        "pronunciation": "めいめい",
        "back": "each, individual",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "恵まれる",
        "pronunciation": "めぐまれる",
        "back": "to be blessed with, to be rich in",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "巡る",
        "pronunciation": "めぐる",
        "back": "to go around",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "目指す",
        "pronunciation": "めざす",
        "back": "to aim at, to have an eye on",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "目覚し",
        "pronunciation": "めざまし",
        "back": "alarm-clock",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "目下",
        "pronunciation": "めした",
        "back": "at present, now",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "目印",
        "pronunciation": "めじるし",
        "back": "mark, sign, landmark",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "目立つ",
        "pronunciation": "めだつ",
        "back": "to be conspicuous, to stand out",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "めちゃくちゃ",
        "pronunciation": "めちゃくちゃ",
        "back": "absurd, messed up, wrecked",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "めっきり",
        "pronunciation": "めっきり",
        "back": "remarkably",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "めでたい",
        "pronunciation": "めでたい",
        "back": "happy, propitious, joyous",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "メニュー",
        "pronunciation": "メニュー",
        "back": "menu",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "めまい",
        "pronunciation": "めまい",
        "back": "dizziness, giddiness",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "目安",
        "pronunciation": "めやす",
        "back": "criterion, aim",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "免税",
        "pronunciation": "めんぜい",
        "back": "tax exemption",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "面積",
        "pronunciation": "めんせき",
        "back": "area",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "面接",
        "pronunciation": "めんせつ",
        "back": "interview",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "面倒臭い",
        "pronunciation": "めんどうくさい",
        "back": "bother to do, tiresome",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "モーター",
        "pronunciation": "モーター",
        "back": "motor",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "儲かる",
        "pronunciation": "もうかる",
        "back": "to be profitable, to yield a profit",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "儲ける",
        "pronunciation": "もうける",
        "back": "to earn, to have (bear, beget) a child",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "申し訳ない",
        "pronunciation": "もうしわけない",
        "back": "inexcusable, I am sorry",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "木材",
        "pronunciation": "もくざい",
        "back": "lumber, timber, wood",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "目次",
        "pronunciation": "もくじ",
        "back": "table of contents",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "潜る",
        "pronunciation": "もぐる",
        "back": "to dive, to pass through; to evade, to hide",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "もしかしたら",
        "pronunciation": "もしかしたら",
        "back": "perhaps, maybe, by some chance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "もたれる",
        "pronunciation": "もたれる",
        "back": "to lean against, to lean on",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "凭れる",
        "pronunciation": "もたれる",
        "back": "to lean against, to lean on, to recline on",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "モダン",
        "pronunciation": "モダン",
        "back": "modern",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "餅",
        "pronunciation": "もち",
        "back": "sticky rice cake",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "モデル",
        "pronunciation": "モデル",
        "back": "a fashion model",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "元々",
        "pronunciation": "もともと",
        "back": "originally, by nature, from the start",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "物置",
        "pronunciation": "ものおき",
        "back": "storage room",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "物語る",
        "pronunciation": "ものがたる",
        "back": "to tell, to indicate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "物差し",
        "pronunciation": "ものさし",
        "back": "ruler, measure",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "物凄い",
        "pronunciation": "ものすごい",
        "back": "earth-shattering, staggering, to a very great extent",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "モノレール",
        "pronunciation": "モノレール",
        "back": "monorail",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "紅葉",
        "pronunciation": "もみじ",
        "back": "(Japanese) maple",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "揉む",
        "pronunciation": "もむ",
        "back": "to rub, to crumple (up), to wrinkle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "もやす",
        "pronunciation": "もやす",
        "back": "to burn",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "催し",
        "pronunciation": "もよおし",
        "back": "event, festivities, function",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "盛る",
        "pronunciation": "もる",
        "back": "to serve (food); to fill up; to prescribe",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "問答",
        "pronunciation": "もんどう",
        "back": "questions and answers, dialogue",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "やかましい",
        "pronunciation": "やかましい",
        "back": "to be fussy, to be overly critical",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "喧しい",
        "pronunciation": "やかましい",
        "back": "noisy, loud, clamorous, boisterous",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "夜間",
        "pronunciation": "やかん",
        "back": "at night, nighttime",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "やかん",
        "pronunciation": "やかん",
        "back": "kettle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "やかん",
        "pronunciation": "やかん",
        "back": "kettle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "役者",
        "pronunciation": "やくしゃ",
        "back": "actor",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "役所",
        "pronunciation": "やくしょ",
        "back": "government office, public office",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "役人",
        "pronunciation": "やくにん",
        "back": "government official",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "薬品",
        "pronunciation": "やくひん",
        "back": "medicine(s), chemical(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "役目",
        "pronunciation": "やくめ",
        "back": "duty, business",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "火傷",
        "pronunciation": "やけど",
        "back": "burn, scald",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "夜行",
        "pronunciation": "やこう",
        "back": "night train, night travel",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "矢印",
        "pronunciation": "やじるし",
        "back": "directing arrow",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "やたらに",
        "pronunciation": "やたらに",
        "back": "randomly, recklessly, blindly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "薬局",
        "pronunciation": "やっきょく",
        "back": "pharmacy, drugstore",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "やっつける",
        "pronunciation": "やっつける",
        "back": "to attack (an enemy), to beat, to finish off",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "やっぱり",
        "pronunciation": "やっぱり",
        "back": "after all, anyway",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "家主",
        "pronunciation": "やぬし",
        "back": "landlord",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "破く",
        "pronunciation": "やぶく",
        "back": "to tear",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "やむをえない",
        "pronunciation": "やむをえない",
        "back": "cannot be helped, unavoidable",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "軟らかい",
        "pronunciation": "やわらかい",
        "back": "soft, tender, limp",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "遊園地",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうえんち",
        "back": "amusement park",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "夕刊",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうかん",
        "back": "evening paper",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "友好",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうこう",
        "back": "friendship",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "郵送",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうそう",
        "back": "mailing",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "夕立",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうだち",
        "back": "(sudden) evening shower (rain)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "夕日",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうひ",
        "back": "(in) the evening sun, setting sun",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "悠々",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうゆう",
        "back": "quiet, calm, leisurely",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "有料",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうりょう",
        "back": "admission-paid, toll",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "浴衣",
        "pronunciation": "ゆかた",
        "back": "bathrobe, informal summer kimono",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "行方",
        "pronunciation": "ゆくえ",
        "back": "one's whereabouts",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "湯気",
        "pronunciation": "ゆげ",
        "back": "steam",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "輸血",
        "pronunciation": "ゆけつ",
        "back": "blood transfusion",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "輸送",
        "pronunciation": "ゆそう",
        "back": "transport, transportation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "油断",
        "pronunciation": "ゆだん",
        "back": "negligence, unpreparedness",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "湯飲み",
        "pronunciation": "ゆのみ",
        "back": "teacup",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "湯飲",
        "pronunciation": "ゆのみ",
        "back": "teacup",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "緩い",
        "pronunciation": "ゆるい",
        "back": "loose, lenient, slow",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "溶岩",
        "pronunciation": "ようがん",
        "back": "lava",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "容器",
        "pronunciation": "ようき",
        "back": "container, receptacle, vessel, packaging",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "用語",
        "pronunciation": "ようご",
        "back": "term, terminology",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "要旨",
        "pronunciation": "ようし",
        "back": "gist, essentials, summary",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "幼児",
        "pronunciation": "ようじ",
        "back": "infant, baby, child",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "容積",
        "pronunciation": "ようせき",
        "back": "capacity, volume",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "幼稚",
        "pronunciation": "ようち",
        "back": "infancy, childish, infantile",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "幼稚園",
        "pronunciation": "ようちえん",
        "back": "kindergarten",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "用途",
        "pronunciation": "ようと",
        "back": "use, usefulness",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "洋品店",
        "pronunciation": "ようひんてん",
        "back": "clothes store",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "養分",
        "pronunciation": "ようぶん",
        "back": "nourishment, nutrient",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "羊毛",
        "pronunciation": "ようもう",
        "back": "wool",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "漸く",
        "pronunciation": "ようやく",
        "back": "at last, finally, hardly",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "要領",
        "pronunciation": "ようりょう",
        "back": "gist, essentials, outline",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "翌～",
        "pronunciation": "よく～",
        "back": "next ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "欲張り",
        "pronunciation": "よくばり",
        "back": "greedy",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "余計",
        "pronunciation": "よけい",
        "back": "too much, unnecessary, abundance, surplus, excess, superfluity",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "よこす",
        "pronunciation": "よこす",
        "back": "to send, to forward; to hand over (e.g., money)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "よごす",
        "pronunciation": "よごす",
        "back": "(1) to disgrace, to dishonour, (2) to pollute, to contaminate, to soil, to make dirty, to stain",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "寄せる",
        "pronunciation": "よせる",
        "back": "to come near, to let someone approach to bring near, to bring together, to collect, to gather to deliver (opinion, news, etc.), to send (e.g. a letter), to contribute, to donate to let someone drop by",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "余所",
        "pronunciation": "よそ",
        "back": "another place, somewhere else, strange parts",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "四つ角",
        "pronunciation": "よつかど",
        "back": "four corners, crossroads",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "酔っ払い",
        "pronunciation": "よっぱらい",
        "back": "drunkard",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "予備",
        "pronunciation": "よび",
        "back": "preparation, spare",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "呼び掛ける",
        "pronunciation": "よびかける",
        "back": "to call out to, to accost, to address (crowd), to appeal",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "呼び出す",
        "pronunciation": "よびだす",
        "back": "to summon, to call (e.g., phone)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "蘇る",
        "pronunciation": "よみがえる",
        "back": "to be resurrected, to be revived",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "慶ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "よろこぶ",
        "back": "to be delighted, to be glad",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "来日",
        "pronunciation": "らいにち",
        "back": "coming to Japan, visit to Japan",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "落第",
        "pronunciation": "らくだい",
        "back": "failure, dropping out of a class",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ラッシュアワー",
        "pronunciation": "ラッシュアワー",
        "back": "rush hour",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "欄",
        "pronunciation": "らん",
        "back": "column of text (e.g., as in a newspaper)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ランチ",
        "pronunciation": "ランチ",
        "back": "lunch",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ランニング",
        "pronunciation": "ランニング",
        "back": "running; tank top",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "乱暴",
        "pronunciation": "らんぼう",
        "back": "rude, violent, rough",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "理科",
        "pronunciation": "りか",
        "back": "science",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "利害",
        "pronunciation": "りがい",
        "back": "advantages and disadvantages, interest",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "リズム",
        "pronunciation": "リズム",
        "back": "rhythm",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "リットル",
        "pronunciation": "リットル",
        "back": "liter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "リポート",
        "pronunciation": "リポート",
        "back": "report, paper",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "リボン",
        "pronunciation": "リボン",
        "back": "ribbon",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "略す",
        "pronunciation": "りゃくす",
        "back": "to abbreviate",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "流域",
        "pronunciation": "りゅういき",
        "back": "(river) basin",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "寮",
        "pronunciation": "りょう",
        "back": "hostel, dormitory",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "両～",
        "pronunciation": "りょう～",
        "back": "both ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "両側",
        "pronunciation": "りょうがわ",
        "back": "both sides",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "漁師",
        "pronunciation": "りょうし",
        "back": "fisherman",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "領事",
        "pronunciation": "りょうじ",
        "back": "consul",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "領収",
        "pronunciation": "りょうしゅう",
        "back": "receipt, voucher",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "臨時",
        "pronunciation": "りんじ",
        "back": "temporary, special, extraordinary",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "留守番",
        "pronunciation": "るすばん",
        "back": "care-taking, caretaker, house-watching",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "例外",
        "pronunciation": "れいがい",
        "back": "exception",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "零点",
        "pronunciation": "れいてん",
        "back": "zero, no marks",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷凍",
        "pronunciation": "れいとう",
        "back": "freezing, cold storage, refrigeration",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "レインコート",
        "pronunciation": "レインコート",
        "back": "raincoat",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "レクリェーション",
        "pronunciation": "レクリェーション",
        "back": "recreation",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "レジャー",
        "pronunciation": "レジャー",
        "back": "leisure",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "列島",
        "pronunciation": "れっとう",
        "back": "chain of islands",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "煉瓦",
        "pronunciation": "れんが",
        "back": "brick",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "連合",
        "pronunciation": "れんごう",
        "back": "union, alliance",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "レンズ",
        "pronunciation": "レンズ",
        "back": "lens",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ローマ字",
        "pronunciation": "ローマじ",
        "back": "romanization, Roman letters (alphabet)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ろうそく",
        "pronunciation": "ろうそく",
        "back": "candle",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "録音",
        "pronunciation": "ろくおん",
        "back": "(audio) recording",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ロッカー",
        "pronunciation": "ロッカー",
        "back": "locker",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ロビー",
        "pronunciation": "ロビー",
        "back": "lobby",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "論ずる",
        "pronunciation": "ろんずる",
        "back": "to argue, to discuss",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "和～",
        "pronunciation": "わ～",
        "back": "Japanese style",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "和英",
        "pronunciation": "わえい",
        "back": "Japanese-English",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "我～",
        "pronunciation": "わが～",
        "back": "our ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "分かれる",
        "pronunciation": "わかれる",
        "back": "to branch, to fork, to diverge to separate, to split, to divide to disperse, to scatter",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "若々しい",
        "pronunciation": "わかわかしい",
        "back": "youthful, young",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "詫びる",
        "pronunciation": "わびる",
        "back": "to apologize",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "和服",
        "pronunciation": "わふく",
        "back": "Japanese clothes",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "割合に",
        "pronunciation": "わりあいに",
        "back": "relatively, comparatively",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "割算",
        "pronunciation": "わりざん",
        "back": "division (math)",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "割と",
        "pronunciation": "わりと",
        "back": "relatively, comparatively",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "割引",
        "pronunciation": "わりびき",
        "back": "discount",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "ワンピース",
        "pronunciation": "ワンピース",
        "back": "one-piece dress",
        "JLPT Level": "N2",
        "collection_id": "10"
    },
    {
        "front": "作法",
        "pronunciation": "さほう",
        "back": "manners, etiquette, propriety",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "様々",
        "pronunciation": "さまざま",
        "back": "varied, various",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷ます",
        "pronunciation": "さます",
        "back": "to cool, to let cool",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "覚ます",
        "pronunciation": "さます",
        "back": "to awaken",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷める",
        "pronunciation": "さめる",
        "back": "to become cool, to wear off",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "覚める",
        "pronunciation": "さめる",
        "back": "to wake, to wake up",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "左右",
        "pronunciation": "さゆう",
        "back": "left and right; influence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "皿",
        "pronunciation": "さら",
        "back": "plate, dish",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "更に",
        "pronunciation": "さらに",
        "back": "furthermore, moreover",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "去る",
        "pronunciation": "さる",
        "back": "to leave, to go away",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "猿",
        "pronunciation": "さる",
        "back": "monkey",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "騒ぎ",
        "pronunciation": "さわぎ",
        "back": "uproar, disturbance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "参加",
        "pronunciation": "さんか",
        "back": "participation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "参考",
        "pronunciation": "さんこう",
        "back": "reference, consultation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "賛成",
        "pronunciation": "さんせい",
        "back": "approval, agreement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "酸性",
        "pronunciation": "さんせい",
        "back": "acidity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "酸素",
        "pronunciation": "さんそ",
        "back": "oxygen",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "氏",
        "pronunciation": "し",
        "back": "family name, lineage",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "詩",
        "pronunciation": "し",
        "back": "poem; poetry",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "幸せ",
        "pronunciation": "しあわせ",
        "back": "happiness, blessing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジーンズ",
        "pronunciation": "ジーンズ",
        "back": "jeans",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジェット機",
        "pronunciation": "ジェットき",
        "back": "jet plane",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "四角",
        "pronunciation": "しかく",
        "back": "square",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "直に",
        "pronunciation": "じかに",
        "back": "immediately, readily, directly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "しかも",
        "pronunciation": "しかも",
        "back": "moreover, furthermore, besides, plus",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "四季",
        "pronunciation": "しき",
        "back": "four seasons",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "直",
        "pronunciation": "じき",
        "back": "immediately, soon, shortly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "時期",
        "pronunciation": "じき",
        "back": "time, season, period",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "支給",
        "pronunciation": "しきゅう",
        "back": "payment, allowance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "至急",
        "pronunciation": "しきゅう",
        "back": "urgent, pressing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "しきりに",
        "pronunciation": "しきりに",
        "back": "frequently, repeatedly, eagerly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "刺激",
        "pronunciation": "しげき",
        "back": "stimulus, impetus, incentive",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "資源",
        "pronunciation": "しげん",
        "back": "resources",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "事件",
        "pronunciation": "じけん",
        "back": "event, affair, incident",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "時刻",
        "pronunciation": "じこく",
        "back": "time, hour",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "自殺",
        "pronunciation": "じさつ",
        "back": "suicide",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "事実",
        "pronunciation": "じじつ",
        "back": "fact, truth, reality",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "支出",
        "pronunciation": "ししゅつ",
        "back": "expenditure, expenses",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "事情",
        "pronunciation": "じじょう",
        "back": "circumstances, situation, reasons",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "詩人",
        "pronunciation": "しじん",
        "back": "poet",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "自身",
        "pronunciation": "じしん",
        "back": "oneself",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "沈む",
        "pronunciation": "しずむ",
        "back": "to sink; to feel depressed",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "自然",
        "pronunciation": "しぜん",
        "back": "nature, spontaneous",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "思想",
        "pronunciation": "しそう",
        "back": "thought, idea",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "舌",
        "pronunciation": "した",
        "back": "tongue",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "次第",
        "pronunciation": "しだい",
        "back": "order; circumstances; immediate(ly)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "従う",
        "pronunciation": "したがう",
        "back": "to abide (by the rules), to obey",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "したがって",
        "pronunciation": "したがって",
        "back": "therefore, consequently",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "親しい",
        "pronunciation": "したしい",
        "back": "intimate, close (e.g., friend)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "質",
        "pronunciation": "しつ",
        "back": "quality, nature (of person)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "失業",
        "pronunciation": "しつぎょう",
        "back": "unemployment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "湿気",
        "pronunciation": "しっけ",
        "back": "moisture, humidity, dampness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "実験",
        "pronunciation": "じっけん",
        "back": "lab work; experiment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "実現",
        "pronunciation": "じつげん",
        "back": "implementation, materialization, realization",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "実行",
        "pronunciation": "じっこう",
        "back": "practice, execution (e.g., program), realization",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "実際",
        "pronunciation": "じっさい",
        "back": "in fact; in actuality",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "実施",
        "pronunciation": "じっし",
        "back": "enforcement, carry out, operation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "湿度",
        "pronunciation": "しつど",
        "back": "humidity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "じっと",
        "pronunciation": "じっと",
        "back": "patiently, quietly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "実に",
        "pronunciation": "じつに",
        "back": "indeed, truly, surely",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "実は",
        "pronunciation": "じつは",
        "back": "actually; in fact",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "失望",
        "pronunciation": "しつぼう",
        "back": "disappointment, despair",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "実力",
        "pronunciation": "じつりょく",
        "back": "ability; force",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "支店",
        "pronunciation": "してん",
        "back": "branch store (office)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "指導",
        "pronunciation": "しどう",
        "back": "leadership, guidance, coaching",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "自動",
        "pronunciation": "じどう",
        "back": "automatic, self-motion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "児童",
        "pronunciation": "じどう",
        "back": "children, juvenile",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "品",
        "pronunciation": "しな",
        "back": "thing, article, goods",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "支配",
        "pronunciation": "しはい",
        "back": "rule, control, direction",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "芝居",
        "pronunciation": "しばい",
        "back": "play, drama",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "しばしば",
        "pronunciation": "しばしば",
        "back": "often, again and again, frequently",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "芝生",
        "pronunciation": "しばふ",
        "back": "lawn",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "支払",
        "pronunciation": "しはらい",
        "back": "payment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "支払う",
        "pronunciation": "しはらう",
        "back": "to pay",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "死亡",
        "pronunciation": "しぼう",
        "back": "death",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "資本",
        "pronunciation": "しほん",
        "back": "funds, capital",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "姉妹",
        "pronunciation": "しまい",
        "back": "sisters",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "しまった (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "しまった (かん)",
        "back": "Damn it!",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "自慢",
        "pronunciation": "じまん",
        "back": "pride, boast",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "地味",
        "pronunciation": "じみ",
        "back": "quiet, plain, conservative",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "示す",
        "pronunciation": "しめす",
        "back": "to show, to indicate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "占める",
        "pronunciation": "しめる",
        "back": "to take up; to account for",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "湿る",
        "pronunciation": "しめる",
        "back": "to be wet, to be damp",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "下",
        "pronunciation": "しも",
        "back": "under, below, beneath",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "霜",
        "pronunciation": "しも",
        "back": "frost",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "借金",
        "pronunciation": "しゃっきん",
        "back": "debt, loan, liabilities",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "しゃべる",
        "pronunciation": "しゃべる",
        "back": "to talk, to chat, to chatter (same as 話す (はなす))",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "週",
        "pronunciation": "しゅう",
        "back": "week",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "州",
        "pronunciation": "しゅう",
        "back": "state, province",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "銃",
        "pronunciation": "じゅう",
        "back": "gun",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "周囲",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうい",
        "back": "surroundings, circumference, environs",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "収穫",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうかく",
        "back": "harvest, crop, ingathering",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "宗教",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうきょう",
        "back": "religion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "重視",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうし",
        "back": "importance, stress",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "就職",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうしょく",
        "back": "finding employment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジュース",
        "pronunciation": "ジュース",
        "back": "juice, soft drink; deuce",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "修正",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうせい",
        "back": "amendment, correction",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "重体",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうたい",
        "back": "seriously ill, critical state",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "渋滞",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうたい",
        "back": "congestion (e.g., traffic), delay",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "重大",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうだい",
        "back": "serious, important",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "住宅",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうたく",
        "back": "resident, housing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "集団",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうだん",
        "back": "group, mass",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "集中",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうちゅう",
        "back": "concentration, focusing the mind",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "収入",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうにゅう",
        "back": "income, revenue",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "住民",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうみん",
        "back": "inhabitants, residents",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "重要",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうよう",
        "back": "important, essential",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "修理",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうり",
        "back": "repairing, mending",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "主義",
        "pronunciation": "しゅぎ",
        "back": "doctrine, cause, principle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "宿泊",
        "pronunciation": "しゅくはく",
        "back": "lodging",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "手術",
        "pronunciation": "しゅじゅつ",
        "back": "surgical operation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "首相",
        "pronunciation": "しゅしょう",
        "back": "Prime Minister",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "手段",
        "pronunciation": "しゅだん",
        "back": "means, way, measure",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "主張",
        "pronunciation": "しゅちょう",
        "back": "claim, insistence, assertion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "出場",
        "pronunciation": "しゅつじょう",
        "back": "participation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "出身",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっしん",
        "back": "come from",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "出版",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっぱん",
        "back": "publication",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "首都",
        "pronunciation": "しゅと",
        "back": "capital city",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "主婦",
        "pronunciation": "しゅふ",
        "back": "housewife",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "主要",
        "pronunciation": "しゅよう",
        "back": "chief, main",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "需要",
        "pronunciation": "じゅよう",
        "back": "demand",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "種類",
        "pronunciation": "しゅるい",
        "back": "variety, kind",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "順",
        "pronunciation": "じゅん",
        "back": "order, turn",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "瞬間",
        "pronunciation": "しゅんかん",
        "back": "moment, second",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "順調",
        "pronunciation": "じゅんちょう",
        "back": "doing well",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "順番",
        "pronunciation": "じゅんばん",
        "back": "turn (in line), order of things",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "使用",
        "pronunciation": "しよう",
        "back": "use (same as 使うこと (つかうこと)), application, employment, utilization",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "小",
        "pronunciation": "しょう",
        "back": "small",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "章",
        "pronunciation": "しょう",
        "back": "chapter, section; medal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "賞",
        "pronunciation": "しょう",
        "back": "prize, award",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "上",
        "pronunciation": "じょう",
        "back": "first volume; superior quality; governmental",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "障害",
        "pronunciation": "しょうがい",
        "back": "obstacle, impediment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "奨学金",
        "pronunciation": "しょうがくきん",
        "back": "scholarship",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "乗客",
        "pronunciation": "じょうきゃく",
        "back": "passenger",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "上京",
        "pronunciation": "じょうきょう",
        "back": "proceeding to the capital (Tokyo)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "状況",
        "pronunciation": "じょうきょう",
        "back": "state of affairs, situation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "条件",
        "pronunciation": "じょうけん",
        "back": "conditions, terms",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "正午",
        "pronunciation": "しょうご",
        "back": "noon, mid-day",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "正直",
        "pronunciation": "しょうじき",
        "back": "honesty, integrity, frankness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "常識",
        "pronunciation": "じょうしき",
        "back": "common sense",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "少女",
        "pronunciation": "しょうじょ",
        "back": "young girl",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "少々",
        "pronunciation": "しょうしょう",
        "back": "a little; short (time) (formal for 少し (すこし))",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "症状",
        "pronunciation": "しょうじょう",
        "back": "symptoms, condition",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生じる",
        "pronunciation": "しょうじる",
        "back": "to occur, to arise, to be generated",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "状態",
        "pronunciation": "じょうたい",
        "back": "condition, situation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "上達",
        "pronunciation": "じょうたつ",
        "back": "improvement, advance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "冗談",
        "pronunciation": "じょうだん",
        "back": "a joke",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "上等",
        "pronunciation": "じょうとう",
        "back": "first class, very good",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "衝突",
        "pronunciation": "しょうとつ",
        "back": "collision, conflict",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "商人",
        "pronunciation": "しょうにん",
        "back": "trader, shopkeeper, merchant",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "承認",
        "pronunciation": "しょうにん",
        "back": "recognition, approval",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "少年",
        "pronunciation": "しょうねん",
        "back": "boys, juveniles",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "商売",
        "pronunciation": "しょうばい",
        "back": "trade, business, commerce",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "消費",
        "pronunciation": "しょうひ",
        "back": "consumption, expenditure",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "商品",
        "pronunciation": "しょうひん",
        "back": "commodity, merchandise",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "賞品",
        "pronunciation": "しょうひん",
        "back": "prize, trophy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "消防",
        "pronunciation": "しょうぼう",
        "back": "fire fighting, fire department",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "情報",
        "pronunciation": "じょうほう",
        "back": "information, (military) intelligence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "証明",
        "pronunciation": "しょうめい",
        "back": "proof, verification",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "省略",
        "pronunciation": "しょうりゃく",
        "back": "omission, abbreviation, abridgment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "女王",
        "pronunciation": "じょおう",
        "back": "queen",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "職",
        "pronunciation": "しょく",
        "back": "employment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "職業",
        "pronunciation": "しょくぎょう",
        "back": "occupation, business",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "食卓",
        "pronunciation": "しょくたく",
        "back": "dining table",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "食品",
        "pronunciation": "しょくひん",
        "back": "foodstuff",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "植物",
        "pronunciation": "しょくぶつ",
        "back": "plant, vegetation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "食物",
        "pronunciation": "しょくもつ",
        "back": "food, foodstuff",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "食欲",
        "pronunciation": "しょくよく",
        "back": "appetite (for food)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "食料",
        "pronunciation": "しょくりょう",
        "back": "food",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "食糧",
        "pronunciation": "しょくりょう",
        "back": "provisions, rations",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "書斎",
        "pronunciation": "しょさい",
        "back": "study, den",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "女子",
        "pronunciation": "じょし",
        "back": "woman, girl",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "助手",
        "pronunciation": "じょしゅ",
        "back": "helper, assistant",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "徐々に",
        "pronunciation": "じょじょに",
        "back": "slowly, little by little",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "署名",
        "pronunciation": "しょめい",
        "back": "signature",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "書物",
        "pronunciation": "しょもつ",
        "back": "books",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "女優",
        "pronunciation": "じょゆう",
        "back": "actress",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "処理",
        "pronunciation": "しょり",
        "back": "processing, treatment, disposition",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "書類",
        "pronunciation": "しょるい",
        "back": "documents, official papers",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "知らせ",
        "pronunciation": "しらせ",
        "back": "notice",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "尻",
        "pronunciation": "しり",
        "back": "buttocks, bottom",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "知合い",
        "pronunciation": "しりあい",
        "back": "acquaintance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "印",
        "pronunciation": "しるし",
        "back": "mark; symbol; evidence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "城",
        "pronunciation": "しろ",
        "back": "castle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "進学",
        "pronunciation": "しんがく",
        "back": "going on to university",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "神経",
        "pronunciation": "しんけい",
        "back": "nerve, sensitivity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "真剣",
        "pronunciation": "しんけん",
        "back": "seriousness, earnestness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "信仰",
        "pronunciation": "しんこう",
        "back": "(religious) faith, belief",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "信号",
        "pronunciation": "しんごう",
        "back": "traffic lights, signal, semaphore",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "人工",
        "pronunciation": "じんこう",
        "back": "artificial, man made, human work,",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "深刻",
        "pronunciation": "しんこく",
        "back": "serious",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "診察",
        "pronunciation": "しんさつ",
        "back": "medical examination (of a patient)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "人種",
        "pronunciation": "じんしゅ",
        "back": "race (of people)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "信じる",
        "pronunciation": "しんじる",
        "back": "to believe",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "人生",
        "pronunciation": "じんせい",
        "back": "(human) life (e.g., conception to death)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "親戚",
        "pronunciation": "しんせき",
        "back": "relative(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "新鮮",
        "pronunciation": "しんせん",
        "back": "fresh",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "心臓",
        "pronunciation": "しんぞう",
        "back": "heart",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "身体",
        "pronunciation": "しんたい",
        "back": "the body",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "身長",
        "pronunciation": "しんちょう",
        "back": "height (of body), stature",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "慎重",
        "pronunciation": "しんちょう",
        "back": "careful, prudent, cautious",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "審判",
        "pronunciation": "しんぱん",
        "back": "umpire, referee, judgment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "人物",
        "pronunciation": "じんぶつ",
        "back": "character, personality, talented man",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "進歩",
        "pronunciation": "しんぽ",
        "back": "improvement, progress, development",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "親友",
        "pronunciation": "しんゆう",
        "back": "close friend, buddy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "信用",
        "pronunciation": "しんよう",
        "back": "confidence, dependence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "信頼",
        "pronunciation": "しんらい",
        "back": "reliance, trust, confidence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "心理",
        "pronunciation": "しんり",
        "back": "mentality",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "人類",
        "pronunciation": "じんるい",
        "back": "mankind, humanity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "巣",
        "pronunciation": "す",
        "back": "nest, breeding place",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "酢",
        "pronunciation": "す",
        "back": "vinegar",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "図",
        "pronunciation": "ず",
        "back": "figure, drawing, illustration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "水準",
        "pronunciation": "すいじゅん",
        "back": "level, standard",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "推薦",
        "pronunciation": "すいせん",
        "back": "recommendation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "スイッチ",
        "pronunciation": "スイッチ",
        "back": "switch",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "睡眠",
        "pronunciation": "すいみん",
        "back": "sleep",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "数",
        "pronunciation": "すう",
        "back": "number, figure",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "数字",
        "pronunciation": "すうじ",
        "back": "numeral, figure",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "スープ",
        "pronunciation": "スープ",
        "back": "(Western) soup",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "末",
        "pronunciation": "すえ",
        "back": "the end of, powder",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "姿",
        "pronunciation": "すがた",
        "back": "figure, shape, appearance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "スキー",
        "pronunciation": "スキー",
        "back": "ski",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "救う",
        "pronunciation": "すくう",
        "back": "to rescue from, to help out of",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "すくなくとも",
        "pronunciation": "すくなくとも",
        "back": "at least",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "優れる",
        "pronunciation": "すぐれる",
        "back": "to surpass, to outstrip, to excel",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "スケート",
        "pronunciation": "スケート",
        "back": "skate(s), skating",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "スケジュール",
        "pronunciation": "スケジュール",
        "back": "schedule",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "少しも",
        "pronunciation": "すこしも",
        "back": "anything of, not one bit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "過ごす",
        "pronunciation": "すごす",
        "back": "to pass, to spend (time)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "筋",
        "pronunciation": "すじ",
        "back": "muscle, string, line",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "進める",
        "pronunciation": "すすめる",
        "back": "to advance, to promote, to hasten",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "勧める",
        "pronunciation": "すすめる",
        "back": "to urge (someone) to do (something), to recommend",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "スター",
        "pronunciation": "スター",
        "back": "star",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "スタイル",
        "pronunciation": "スタイル",
        "back": "style",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "スタンド",
        "pronunciation": "スタンド",
        "back": "stand",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "頭痛",
        "pronunciation": "ずつう",
        "back": "headache",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ずっと",
        "pronunciation": "ずっと",
        "back": "for a long time; all the time; consecutively",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "すっぱい",
        "pronunciation": "すっぱい",
        "back": "sour, acid",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "すてき",
        "pronunciation": "すてき",
        "back": "lovely, great",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "既に",
        "pronunciation": "すでに",
        "back": "already (same as もう)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "すなわち",
        "pronunciation": "すなわち",
        "back": "that is, namely, e.g.",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "スピーチ",
        "pronunciation": "スピーチ",
        "back": "speech",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "全て",
        "pronunciation": "すべて",
        "back": "all, the whole, entirely",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "済ませる",
        "pronunciation": "すませる",
        "back": "to be finished",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "角",
        "pronunciation": "すみ",
        "back": "corner",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "墨",
        "pronunciation": "すみ",
        "back": "ink",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "すみません (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "すみません (かん)",
        "back": "sorry, excuse me",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "澄む",
        "pronunciation": "すむ",
        "back": "to clear (e.g., weather), to become transparent",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "清む",
        "pronunciation": "すむ",
        "back": "to clear (e.g., weather), to become transparent",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "刷る",
        "pronunciation": "する",
        "back": "to print",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "為る",
        "pronunciation": "する",
        "back": "to do, to attempt",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "鋭い",
        "pronunciation": "するどい",
        "back": "pointed, sharp",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "すれ違う",
        "pronunciation": "すれちがう",
        "back": "to pass by one another",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ずれる",
        "pronunciation": "ずれる",
        "back": "move, off the point",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "正",
        "pronunciation": "せい",
        "back": "(logical) true, regular",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生",
        "pronunciation": "せい",
        "back": "birth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "性",
        "pronunciation": "せい",
        "back": "sex, gender",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "姓",
        "pronunciation": "せい",
        "back": "surname, family name",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "所為",
        "pronunciation": "せい",
        "back": "cause, reason, fault",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "税",
        "pronunciation": "ぜい",
        "back": "tax",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "性格",
        "pronunciation": "せいかく",
        "back": "character, personality",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "正確",
        "pronunciation": "せいかく",
        "back": "accurate, punctuality, exact",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "世紀",
        "pronunciation": "せいき",
        "back": "century",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "請求",
        "pronunciation": "せいきゅう",
        "back": "claim, demand, request",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "税金",
        "pronunciation": "ぜいきん",
        "back": "tax, duty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "清潔",
        "pronunciation": "せいけつ",
        "back": "clean",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "制限",
        "pronunciation": "せいげん",
        "back": "restriction, restraint, limitation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "成功",
        "pronunciation": "せいこう",
        "back": "success, hit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "正式",
        "pronunciation": "せいしき",
        "back": "official, formal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "性質",
        "pronunciation": "せいしつ",
        "back": "nature, property, disposition",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "精神",
        "pronunciation": "せいしん",
        "back": "mind, soul, spirit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "成人",
        "pronunciation": "せいじん",
        "back": "adult",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "精々",
        "pronunciation": "せいぜい",
        "back": "at the most, at best",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "成績",
        "pronunciation": "せいせき",
        "back": "grade (i.e., on a test), academic record",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "製造",
        "pronunciation": "せいぞう",
        "back": "manufacture, production",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "贅沢",
        "pronunciation": "ぜいたく",
        "back": "luxury, extravagance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "成長",
        "pronunciation": "せいちょう",
        "back": "growth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生長",
        "pronunciation": "せいちょう",
        "back": "growth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "制度",
        "pronunciation": "せいど",
        "back": "system, institution",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "青年",
        "pronunciation": "せいねん",
        "back": "youth, young man",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生年月日",
        "pronunciation": "せいねんがっぴ",
        "back": "birth date",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "製品",
        "pronunciation": "せいひん",
        "back": "manufactured goods, finished goods",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "政府",
        "pronunciation": "せいふ",
        "back": "government, administration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生物",
        "pronunciation": "せいぶつ",
        "back": "living thing, organism",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生命",
        "pronunciation": "せいめい",
        "back": "life",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "整理",
        "pronunciation": "せいり",
        "back": "sorting, arrangement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "咳",
        "pronunciation": "せき",
        "back": "cough",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "石炭",
        "pronunciation": "せきたん",
        "back": "coal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "責任",
        "pronunciation": "せきにん",
        "back": "duty, responsibility",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "石油",
        "pronunciation": "せきゆ",
        "back": "oil, petroleum, kerosene",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "世間",
        "pronunciation": "せけん",
        "back": "world, society",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "説",
        "pronunciation": "せつ",
        "back": "theory",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "積極的",
        "pronunciation": "せっきょくてき",
        "back": "positive, active, proactive",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "設計",
        "pronunciation": "せっけい",
        "back": "plan, design",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "絶対",
        "pronunciation": "ぜったい",
        "back": "definitely, without fail, absoluteness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "セット",
        "pronunciation": "セット",
        "back": "set",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "愛",
        "pronunciation": "あい",
        "back": "love",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "相変わらず",
        "pronunciation": "あいかわらず",
        "back": "as ever, as usual",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "愛情",
        "pronunciation": "あいじょう",
        "back": "love, affection",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "合図",
        "pronunciation": "あいず",
        "back": "sign, signal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "アイスクリーム",
        "pronunciation": "アイスクリーム",
        "back": "ice cream",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "愛する",
        "pronunciation": "あいする",
        "back": "to love",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "相手",
        "pronunciation": "あいて",
        "back": "partner; addressee; the person you are talking to",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "あいにく",
        "pronunciation": "あいにく",
        "back": "unfortunately",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "遭う",
        "pronunciation": "あう",
        "back": "to meet, to encounter (undesirable nuance)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "アウト",
        "pronunciation": "アウト",
        "back": "out",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "明かり",
        "pronunciation": "あかり",
        "back": "lamplight, light (in general)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "空き",
        "pronunciation": "あき",
        "back": "vacancy, opening, space",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "明らか",
        "pronunciation": "あきらか",
        "back": "obvious, clear",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "諦める",
        "pronunciation": "あきらめる",
        "back": "to give up, to abandon",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "飽きる",
        "pronunciation": "あきる",
        "back": "to get tired of, to lose interest in",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "握手",
        "pronunciation": "あくしゅ",
        "back": "handshake",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "悪魔",
        "pronunciation": "あくま",
        "back": "devil, demon, evil spirit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "明ける",
        "pronunciation": "あける",
        "back": "to dawn, to become daylight",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "揚げる",
        "pronunciation": "あげる",
        "back": "to lift, to fry",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "挙げる",
        "pronunciation": "あげる",
        "back": "to raise; to list, to cite",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "預かる",
        "pronunciation": "あずかる",
        "back": "to keep (something) for (someone)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "預ける",
        "pronunciation": "あずける",
        "back": "to give into custody, to deposit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "汗",
        "pronunciation": "あせ",
        "back": "sweat, perspiration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "与える",
        "pronunciation": "あたえる",
        "back": "to give",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "温かい",
        "pronunciation": "あたたかい",
        "back": "warm",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "暖まる",
        "pronunciation": "あたたまる",
        "back": "to warm up",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "温まる",
        "pronunciation": "あたたまる",
        "back": "to warm oneself, to get warm",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "暖める",
        "pronunciation": "あたためる",
        "back": "to warm (up to someone/something), to heat (up to someone/something)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "温める",
        "pronunciation": "あたためる",
        "back": "to warm, to heat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "辺り",
        "pronunciation": "あたり",
        "back": "vicinity, nearby",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "当たり前",
        "pronunciation": "あたりまえ",
        "back": "usual, common, obvious",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "当たる",
        "pronunciation": "あたる",
        "back": "to be hit, to be successful",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "あちこち",
        "pronunciation": "あちこち",
        "back": "here and there",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "扱う",
        "pronunciation": "あつかう",
        "back": "to treat, to handle, to deal with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "集まり",
        "pronunciation": "あつまり",
        "back": "gathering, meeting, collection",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "当てる",
        "pronunciation": "あてる",
        "back": "to hit; to apply to",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "跡",
        "pronunciation": "あと",
        "back": "trace; remains; scar",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "穴",
        "pronunciation": "あな",
        "back": "hole",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "油",
        "pronunciation": "あぶら",
        "back": "oil",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "脂",
        "pronunciation": "あぶら",
        "back": "fat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "誤り",
        "pronunciation": "あやまり",
        "back": "error",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "粗",
        "pronunciation": "あら",
        "back": "defect, flaw, fault",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "嵐",
        "pronunciation": "あらし",
        "back": "storm",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "争う",
        "pronunciation": "あらそう",
        "back": "to dispute, to argue, to fight",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "新た",
        "pronunciation": "あらた",
        "back": "new, fresh",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "あらゆる",
        "pronunciation": "あらゆる",
        "back": "all, every",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "表す",
        "pronunciation": "あらわす",
        "back": "to express, to show",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "現す",
        "pronunciation": "あらわす",
        "back": "to show, to appear, to reveal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "著す",
        "pronunciation": "あらわす",
        "back": "to write, to publish",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "現れ",
        "pronunciation": "あらわれ",
        "back": "expression, indication, sign",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "現れる",
        "pronunciation": "あらわれる",
        "back": "to appear (v.i.), to become visible; to express",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ありがとう",
        "pronunciation": "ありがとう",
        "back": "Thank you",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "在る; 有る",
        "pronunciation": "ある",
        "back": "to live, to be, to exist",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "或",
        "pronunciation": "ある",
        "back": "a certain..., some...",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "あるいは",
        "pronunciation": "あるいは",
        "back": "or, perhaps",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "アルバム",
        "pronunciation": "アルバム",
        "back": "album",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "泡",
        "pronunciation": "あわ",
        "back": "bubble, foam",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "合わせる",
        "pronunciation": "あわせる",
        "back": "to combine",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "慌てる",
        "pronunciation": "あわてる",
        "back": "to become confused、to panic",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "哀れ",
        "pronunciation": "あわれ",
        "back": "helpless, pity, pathetic",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "案",
        "pronunciation": "あん",
        "back": "plan, scheme, proposal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "案外",
        "pronunciation": "あんがい",
        "back": "unexpectedly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "暗記",
        "pronunciation": "あんき",
        "back": "memorization, learning by heart",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "安定",
        "pronunciation": "あんてい",
        "back": "stability, equilibrium",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "あんなに",
        "pronunciation": "あんなに",
        "back": "to that extent, to that degree",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "あんまり",
        "pronunciation": "あんまり",
        "back": "not very, not much",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "胃",
        "pronunciation": "い",
        "back": "stomach",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "委員",
        "pronunciation": "いいん",
        "back": "committee member",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "意外",
        "pronunciation": "いがい",
        "back": "unexpected, surprising",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "行き",
        "pronunciation": "いき",
        "back": "going",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "行き",
        "pronunciation": "ゆき",
        "back": "going",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "息",
        "pronunciation": "いき",
        "back": "breath",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "勢い",
        "pronunciation": "いきおい",
        "back": "force, vigor, momentum",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生き物",
        "pronunciation": "いきもの",
        "back": "living thing, creature",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "いけない",
        "pronunciation": "いけない",
        "back": "must not do, bad, wrong",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "医師",
        "pronunciation": "いし",
        "back": "doctor, physician",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "意思",
        "pronunciation": "いし",
        "back": "intention, purpose",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "意志",
        "pronunciation": "いし",
        "back": "will, volition",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "維持",
        "pronunciation": "いじ",
        "back": "maintenance, preservation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "意識",
        "pronunciation": "いしき",
        "back": "consciousness, senses",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "異常",
        "pronunciation": "いじょう",
        "back": "strangeness, abnormality, disorder",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "意地悪",
        "pronunciation": "いじわる",
        "back": "malicious, mean, unkind",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "泉",
        "pronunciation": "いずみ",
        "back": "spring, fountain",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "いずれ",
        "pronunciation": "いずれ",
        "back": "where, which, who",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "以前",
        "pronunciation": "いぜん",
        "back": "in the past; before",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "板",
        "pronunciation": "いた",
        "back": "board, plank",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "偉大",
        "pronunciation": "いだい",
        "back": "greatness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "抱く",
        "pronunciation": "いだく",
        "back": "to hold (v.t.) (written expression), to embrace, to harbor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "いたずら",
        "pronunciation": "いたずら",
        "back": "trick, practical joke",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "いただきます",
        "pronunciation": "いただきます",
        "back": "expression of gratitude before meals",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "痛み",
        "pronunciation": "いたみ",
        "back": "pain, ache, sore",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "至る",
        "pronunciation": "いたる",
        "back": "to come, to arrive",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "市",
        "pronunciation": "いち",
        "back": "market, fair",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "位置",
        "pronunciation": "いち",
        "back": "place, position",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一時",
        "pronunciation": "いちじ",
        "back": "for a time, temporarily",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一度に",
        "pronunciation": "いちどに",
        "back": "all at once",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "市場",
        "pronunciation": "いちば",
        "back": "market, bazaar",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "いつか",
        "pronunciation": "いつか",
        "back": "sometime, one day",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一家",
        "pronunciation": "いっか",
        "back": "family, clan",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一種",
        "pronunciation": "いっしゅ",
        "back": "a species, a kind, a variety",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一瞬",
        "pronunciation": "いっしゅん",
        "back": "a moment, an instant",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一生",
        "pronunciation": "いっしょう",
        "back": "throughout (one's) life",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一層",
        "pronunciation": "いっそう",
        "back": "much more, still more",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一体",
        "pronunciation": "いったい",
        "back": "one object; body; what on earth?; generally",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一致",
        "pronunciation": "いっち",
        "back": "agreement; conformity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "いつでも",
        "pronunciation": "いつでも",
        "back": "(at) any time, always",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "いつのまにか",
        "pronunciation": "いつのまにか",
        "back": "before one knows",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一般",
        "pronunciation": "いっぱん",
        "back": "general, average",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一方",
        "pronunciation": "いっぽう",
        "back": "on the other hand; meanwhile",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "いつまでも",
        "pronunciation": "いつまでも",
        "back": "forever, for good, eternally",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "移動",
        "pronunciation": "いどう",
        "back": "migration, movement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "従兄弟",
        "pronunciation": "いとこ",
        "back": "cousin (male)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "従姉妹",
        "pronunciation": "いとこ",
        "back": "cousin (female)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "稲",
        "pronunciation": "いね",
        "back": "rice-plant",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "居眠り",
        "pronunciation": "いねむり",
        "back": "dozing, nodding off",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "命",
        "pronunciation": "いのち",
        "back": "life",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "違反",
        "pronunciation": "いはん",
        "back": "violation (of law), infringement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "衣服",
        "pronunciation": "いふく",
        "back": "clothes",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "居間",
        "pronunciation": "いま",
        "back": "living room",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "今に",
        "pronunciation": "いまに",
        "back": "before long, soon",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "今にも",
        "pronunciation": "いまにも",
        "back": "at any time, soon",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "イメージ",
        "pronunciation": "イメージ",
        "back": "one's image",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "否",
        "pronunciation": "いや",
        "back": "no, the noes",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "以来",
        "pronunciation": "いらい",
        "back": "since, henceforth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "依頼",
        "pronunciation": "いらい",
        "back": "request; dependence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "いらいら",
        "pronunciation": "いらいら",
        "back": "getting nervous, irritation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "いらっしゃい",
        "pronunciation": "いらっしゃい",
        "back": "welcome",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "医療",
        "pronunciation": "いりょう",
        "back": "medical care, medical treatment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "岩",
        "pronunciation": "いわ",
        "back": "rock",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "祝い",
        "pronunciation": "いわい",
        "back": "celebration, festival",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "祝う",
        "pronunciation": "いわう",
        "back": "to congratulate, to celebrate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "言わば",
        "pronunciation": "いわば",
        "back": "so to speak",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "いわゆる",
        "pronunciation": "いわゆる",
        "back": "the so-called, so-to-speak",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "インク",
        "pronunciation": "インク",
        "back": "ink",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "印刷",
        "pronunciation": "いんさつ",
        "back": "printing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "印象",
        "pronunciation": "いんしょう",
        "back": "impression",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "引退",
        "pronunciation": "いんたい",
        "back": "retirement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "インタビュー",
        "pronunciation": "インタビュー",
        "back": "interview",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "引用",
        "pronunciation": "いんよう",
        "back": "quotation, citation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ウイスキー",
        "pronunciation": "ウイスキー",
        "back": "whiskey",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "上",
        "pronunciation": "うわ",
        "back": "upper, outer, surface",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "魚",
        "pronunciation": "うお",
        "back": "fish",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "うがい",
        "pronunciation": "うがい",
        "back": "gargling",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "受け取る",
        "pronunciation": "うけとる",
        "back": "to receive, to get, to accept",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "動かす",
        "pronunciation": "うごかす",
        "back": "to move, to shift",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "兎",
        "pronunciation": "うさぎ",
        "back": "rabbit, hare",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "牛",
        "pronunciation": "うし",
        "back": "cattle, cow",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "失う",
        "pronunciation": "うしなう",
        "back": "to lose, to part with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "疑う",
        "pronunciation": "うたがう",
        "back": "to doubt, to distrust",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "宇宙",
        "pronunciation": "うちゅう",
        "back": "universe, cosmos, space",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "討つ",
        "pronunciation": "うつ",
        "back": "to attack, to avenge",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "撃つ",
        "pronunciation": "うつ",
        "back": "to attack, to shoot",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "うっかり",
        "pronunciation": "うっかり",
        "back": "carelessly; inadvertently",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "映す",
        "pronunciation": "うつす",
        "back": "to project, to reflect, to cast (shadow)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "訴える",
        "pronunciation": "うったえる",
        "back": "to complain, to appeal, to sue (a person)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "写る",
        "pronunciation": "うつる",
        "back": "to be photographed, to be projected",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "映る",
        "pronunciation": "うつる",
        "back": "to be reflected, to come out (photo)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "うなる",
        "pronunciation": "うなる",
        "back": "to groan, to moan",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "奪う",
        "pronunciation": "うばう",
        "back": "to rob, to deprive",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "馬",
        "pronunciation": "うま",
        "back": "horse; promoted bishop (in Japanese chess known as shogi)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生まれ",
        "pronunciation": "うまれ",
        "back": "birth, birth-place",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "有無",
        "pronunciation": "うむ",
        "back": "yes or no, presence or absence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "梅",
        "pronunciation": "うめ",
        "back": "plum, lowest (of a three-tier ranking system)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "埋める",
        "pronunciation": "うめる",
        "back": "to bury, to fill up, to fill (a seat, a vacant position)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "裏切る",
        "pronunciation": "うらぎる",
        "back": "to betray, to turn traitor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "羨ましい",
        "pronunciation": "うらやましい",
        "back": "envious, enviable",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "売れる",
        "pronunciation": "うれる",
        "back": "to be sold",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "噂",
        "pronunciation": "うわさ",
        "back": "rumor, gossip",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "運",
        "pronunciation": "うん",
        "back": "fortune, luck",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "運転",
        "pronunciation": "うんてん",
        "back": "operation, driving",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "柄",
        "pronunciation": "え",
        "back": "handle (of a sword, dagger, etc.), grip",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "永遠",
        "pronunciation": "えいえん",
        "back": "eternity, perpetuity, immortality",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "永久",
        "pronunciation": "えいきゅう",
        "back": "eternity, perpetuity, immortality",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "影響",
        "pronunciation": "えいきょう",
        "back": "influence, effect",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "営業",
        "pronunciation": "えいぎょう",
        "back": "business, trade, management",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "衛星",
        "pronunciation": "えいせい",
        "back": "satellite",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "栄養",
        "pronunciation": "えいよう",
        "back": "nutrition, nourishment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "笑顔",
        "pronunciation": "えがお",
        "back": "smile (on one's face)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "描く",
        "pronunciation": "えがく",
        "back": "to draw, to depict, to describe",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "餌",
        "pronunciation": "えさ",
        "back": "feed, bait",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "エネルギー",
        "pronunciation": "エネルギー",
        "back": "energy (GER: energie)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "得る",
        "pronunciation": "える",
        "back": "to get, to gain, to win, to learn",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "得る",
        "pronunciation": "うる",
        "back": "to get, to gain, to win",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "円",
        "pronunciation": "えん",
        "back": "circle, yen",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "延期",
        "pronunciation": "えんき",
        "back": "postponement, adjournment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "演技",
        "pronunciation": "えんぎ",
        "back": "acting, performance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "援助",
        "pronunciation": "えんじょ",
        "back": "assistance, aid, support",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "エンジン",
        "pronunciation": "エンジン",
        "back": "engine",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "演説",
        "pronunciation": "えんぜつ",
        "back": "speech, address",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "演奏",
        "pronunciation": "えんそう",
        "back": "musical performance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "老い",
        "pronunciation": "おい",
        "back": "old age, the aged",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "追い付く",
        "pronunciation": "おいつく",
        "back": "to overtake, to catch up (with)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "王",
        "pronunciation": "おう",
        "back": "king",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "追う",
        "pronunciation": "おう",
        "back": "to chase, to run after",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "応援",
        "pronunciation": "おうえん",
        "back": "aid, assistance, help",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "王様",
        "pronunciation": "おうさま",
        "back": "king",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "王子",
        "pronunciation": "おうじ",
        "back": "prince",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "応じる",
        "pronunciation": "おうじる",
        "back": "to adapt, to respond, to comply with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "横断",
        "pronunciation": "おうだん",
        "back": "crossing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "終える",
        "pronunciation": "おえる",
        "back": "to finish",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大いに",
        "pronunciation": "おおいに",
        "back": "much, considerably (same as 大変 (たいへん)), greatly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "覆う",
        "pronunciation": "おおう",
        "back": "to cover, to hide, to conceal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大家",
        "pronunciation": "おおや",
        "back": "landlord",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "丘",
        "pronunciation": "おか",
        "back": "hill, height",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "沖",
        "pronunciation": "おき",
        "back": "open sea",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "奥",
        "pronunciation": "おく",
        "back": "interior, inner part",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "贈る",
        "pronunciation": "おくる",
        "back": "to present, to give to, to award to",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "起こる",
        "pronunciation": "おこる",
        "back": "to occur, to happen",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "押える",
        "pronunciation": "おさえる",
        "back": "to stop, to restrain, to press down",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "幼い",
        "pronunciation": "おさない",
        "back": "very young, childish",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "収める",
        "pronunciation": "おさめる",
        "back": "to store to pay, to supply",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "納める",
        "pronunciation": "おさめる",
        "back": "to store to pay, to supply",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "治める",
        "pronunciation": "おさめる",
        "back": "to govern, to manage; to subdue",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "お辞儀",
        "pronunciation": "おじぎ",
        "back": "bow",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "お洒落",
        "pronunciation": "おしゃれ",
        "back": "smartly dressed, fashion-conscious",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "お喋り",
        "pronunciation": "おしゃべり",
        "back": "chattering, talk",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "汚染",
        "pronunciation": "おせん",
        "back": "pollution, contamination",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "恐らく",
        "pronunciation": "おそらく",
        "back": "perhaps",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "恐れる",
        "pronunciation": "おそれる",
        "back": "to fear, to be afraid of",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "恐ろしい",
        "pronunciation": "おそろしい",
        "back": "terrible, dreadful",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "教わる",
        "pronunciation": "おそわる",
        "back": "to be taught",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "お互い",
        "pronunciation": "おたがい",
        "back": "mutual, reciprocal, each other",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "穏やか",
        "pronunciation": "おだやか",
        "back": "calm, gentle, quiet",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "男の人",
        "pronunciation": "おとこのひと",
        "back": "man",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大人しい",
        "pronunciation": "おとなしい",
        "back": "obedient, docile, quiet",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "劣る",
        "pronunciation": "おとる",
        "back": "to fall behind, to be inferior to",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "鬼",
        "pronunciation": "おに",
        "back": "ogre, demon, 'it' (e.g.,in a game of tag)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "帯",
        "pronunciation": "おび",
        "back": "band, sash",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "お昼",
        "pronunciation": "おひる",
        "back": "lunch, noon",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "オフィス",
        "pronunciation": "オフィス",
        "back": "office",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "溺れる",
        "pronunciation": "おぼれる",
        "back": "to be drowned, to indulge in",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "お前",
        "pronunciation": "おまえ",
        "back": "you (sing), presence (of a high personage)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "おめでとう",
        "pronunciation": "おめでとう",
        "back": "Congratulations!, an auspicious occasion!",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "お目に掛かる",
        "pronunciation": "おめにかかる",
        "back": "meet ~, see ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "思い付く",
        "pronunciation": "おもいつく",
        "back": "to think of, to hit upon",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "思い出",
        "pronunciation": "おもいで",
        "back": "memories, recollections, reminiscence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "主に",
        "pronunciation": "おもに",
        "back": "mainly, primarily",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "思わず",
        "pronunciation": "おもわず",
        "back": "unintentional, spontaneous",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "泳ぎ",
        "pronunciation": "およぎ",
        "back": "swimming",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "およそ",
        "pronunciation": "およそ",
        "back": "about, roughly, approximately",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "及ぼす",
        "pronunciation": "およぼす",
        "back": "to exert, to cause, to exercise",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "下す",
        "pronunciation": "おろす",
        "back": "to lower, to let go down",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "降ろす",
        "pronunciation": "おろす",
        "back": "to take down, to launch, to drop",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "卸す",
        "pronunciation": "おろす",
        "back": "to sell wholesale, grated (vegetables)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "音",
        "pronunciation": "おん",
        "back": "sound, note",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "恩",
        "pronunciation": "おん",
        "back": "favor, obligation, debt of gratitude",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "温暖",
        "pronunciation": "おんだん",
        "back": "warmth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "温度",
        "pronunciation": "おんど",
        "back": "temperature",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "可",
        "pronunciation": "か",
        "back": "passable",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "蚊",
        "pronunciation": "か",
        "back": "mosquito",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "課",
        "pronunciation": "か",
        "back": "department, division",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "カー",
        "pronunciation": "カー",
        "back": "car",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "カード",
        "pronunciation": "カード",
        "back": "card, curd",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "貝",
        "pronunciation": "かい",
        "back": "shell, shellfish",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "害",
        "pronunciation": "がい",
        "back": "harm, damage",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "会員",
        "pronunciation": "かいいん",
        "back": "member, the membership",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "絵画",
        "pronunciation": "かいが",
        "back": "picture, painting",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "海外",
        "pronunciation": "かいがい",
        "back": "foreign, abroad, overseas",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "会計",
        "pronunciation": "かいけい",
        "back": "account, finance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "解決",
        "pronunciation": "かいけつ",
        "back": "settlement, solution, resolution",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "会合",
        "pronunciation": "かいごう",
        "back": "meeting, assembly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "外交",
        "pronunciation": "がいこう",
        "back": "diplomacy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "開始",
        "pronunciation": "かいし",
        "back": "start, commencement, beginning",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "解釈",
        "pronunciation": "かいしゃく",
        "back": "explanation, interpretation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "外出",
        "pronunciation": "がいしゅつ",
        "back": "outing, going out",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "改善",
        "pronunciation": "かいぜん",
        "back": "betterment, improvement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "快適",
        "pronunciation": "かいてき",
        "back": "pleasant, agreeable",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "回復",
        "pronunciation": "かいふく",
        "back": "recovery (from illness), rehabilitation, restoration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "飼う",
        "pronunciation": "かう",
        "back": "to keep; to own (a pet); to raise; to feed",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "帰す",
        "pronunciation": "かえす",
        "back": "to send back",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "代える",
        "pronunciation": "かえる",
        "back": "to exchange, to interchange, to substitute",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "替える",
        "pronunciation": "かえる",
        "back": "to exchange, to interchange, to substitute",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "換える",
        "pronunciation": "かえる",
        "back": "to exchange, to interchange, to substitute",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "反る",
        "pronunciation": "かえる",
        "back": "to warp, to be warped, to curve",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "香り",
        "pronunciation": "かおり",
        "back": "aroma, fragrance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "画家",
        "pronunciation": "がか",
        "back": "painter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "抱える",
        "pronunciation": "かかえる",
        "back": "to hold or carry under or in the arms",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "価格",
        "pronunciation": "かかく",
        "back": "price, value",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "化学",
        "pronunciation": "かがく",
        "back": "chemistry",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "輝く",
        "pronunciation": "かがやく",
        "back": "to shine, to glitter, to sparkle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "係",
        "pronunciation": "かかり",
        "back": "person in charge",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "罹る",
        "pronunciation": "かかる",
        "back": "to suffer from",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "限る",
        "pronunciation": "かぎる",
        "back": "to restrict, to limit, to confine",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "掻く",
        "pronunciation": "かく",
        "back": "to scratch",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "描く",
        "pronunciation": "かく",
        "back": "to draw, to depict, to describe",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "嗅ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "かぐ",
        "back": "to sniff, to smell",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "家具",
        "pronunciation": "かぐ",
        "back": "furniture",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "学",
        "pronunciation": "がく",
        "back": "learning, knowledge",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "額",
        "pronunciation": "がく",
        "back": "amount; frame",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "覚悟",
        "pronunciation": "かくご",
        "back": "resolution, resignation, readiness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "確実",
        "pronunciation": "かくじつ",
        "back": "certainty, reliability, soundness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "学者",
        "pronunciation": "がくしゃ",
        "back": "scholar",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "学習",
        "pronunciation": "がくしゅう",
        "back": "study, learning",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "隠す",
        "pronunciation": "かくす",
        "back": "to hide, to conceal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "拡大",
        "pronunciation": "かくだい",
        "back": "magnification, enlargement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "確認",
        "pronunciation": "かくにん",
        "back": "affirmation, confirmation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "学問",
        "pronunciation": "がくもん",
        "back": "scholarship, study, learning",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "隠れる",
        "pronunciation": "かくれる",
        "back": "to hide, to be hidden",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "影",
        "pronunciation": "かげ",
        "back": "shade, shadow, other side",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "陰",
        "pronunciation": "かげ",
        "back": "shade, shadow, other side",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "欠ける",
        "pronunciation": "かける",
        "back": "to be lacking",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "加減",
        "pronunciation": "かげん",
        "back": "adjustment; addition and subtraction",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "過去",
        "pronunciation": "かこ",
        "back": "past",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "籠",
        "pronunciation": "かご",
        "back": "basket, cage",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "囲む",
        "pronunciation": "かこむ",
        "back": "to surround, to encircle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "火災",
        "pronunciation": "かさい",
        "back": "conflagration, fire",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "重なる",
        "pronunciation": "かさなる",
        "back": "to be piled up, lie on top of one another",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "重ねる",
        "pronunciation": "かさねる",
        "back": "to pile up, to put something on another, to heap up",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "飾り",
        "pronunciation": "かざり",
        "back": "decoration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "貸し",
        "pronunciation": "かし",
        "back": "loan, lending",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "菓子",
        "pronunciation": "かし",
        "back": "confectionery, sweet",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "家事",
        "pronunciation": "かじ",
        "back": "household matters; housework (same as 家の仕事 (いえのしごと))",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "賢い",
        "pronunciation": "かしこい",
        "back": "wise, clever, smart",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "歌手",
        "pronunciation": "かしゅ",
        "back": "singer",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "数",
        "pronunciation": "かず",
        "back": "number, figure, amount",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "稼ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "かせぐ",
        "back": "to earn income, to labor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "数える",
        "pronunciation": "かぞえる",
        "back": "to count",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "型",
        "pronunciation": "かた",
        "back": "mold, model, style",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "肩",
        "pronunciation": "かた",
        "back": "shoulder",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "堅い",
        "pronunciation": "かたい",
        "back": "hard, firm, solid",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "硬い",
        "pronunciation": "かたい",
        "back": "hard, firm, solid",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "方々",
        "pronunciation": "かたがた",
        "back": "persons",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "片付く",
        "pronunciation": "かたづく",
        "back": "to put in order, to solve",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "刀",
        "pronunciation": "かたな",
        "back": "sword, saber",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "語る",
        "pronunciation": "かたる",
        "back": "to talk, to tell, to recite",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "勝ち",
        "pronunciation": "かち",
        "back": "win, victory",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "価値",
        "pronunciation": "かち",
        "back": "value, worth, merit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "がっかり",
        "pronunciation": "がっかり",
        "back": "feel disappointed, be dejected, lose heart",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "活気",
        "pronunciation": "かっき",
        "back": "vigor; liveliness; vitality; energy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "楽器",
        "pronunciation": "がっき",
        "back": "musical instrument",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "学期",
        "pronunciation": "がっき",
        "back": "term (school)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "活動",
        "pronunciation": "かつどう",
        "back": "action, activity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "活躍",
        "pronunciation": "かつやく",
        "back": "activity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "活用",
        "pronunciation": "かつよう",
        "back": "conjugation; practical use",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "仮定",
        "pronunciation": "かてい",
        "back": "assumption, supposition, hypothesis",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "過程",
        "pronunciation": "かてい",
        "back": "process",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "課程",
        "pronunciation": "かてい",
        "back": "course, curriculum",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "悲しむ",
        "pronunciation": "かなしむ",
        "back": "to be sad, to mourn for, to regret",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "必ずしも",
        "pronunciation": "かならずしも",
        "back": "(not) always, (not) necessarily",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "かなり",
        "pronunciation": "かなり",
        "back": "considerably, fairly, quite",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "金",
        "pronunciation": "かね",
        "back": "gold, metal; money",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "鐘",
        "pronunciation": "かね",
        "back": "bell, chime",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "可能",
        "pronunciation": "かのう",
        "back": "possible, practicable, feasible",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "株",
        "pronunciation": "かぶ",
        "back": "stock; stump (of tree)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "被る",
        "pronunciation": "かぶる",
        "back": "to wear; to be covered with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "我慢",
        "pronunciation": "がまん",
        "back": "patience, endurance, perseverance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "上",
        "pronunciation": "かみ",
        "back": "first volume; superior quality; governmental",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "神",
        "pronunciation": "かみ",
        "back": "god",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "雷",
        "pronunciation": "かみなり",
        "back": "thunder",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "髪の毛",
        "pronunciation": "かみのけ",
        "back": "hair (head)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "科目",
        "pronunciation": "かもく",
        "back": "(school) subject, curriculum, course",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "かもしれない",
        "pronunciation": "かもしれない",
        "back": "maybe, perhaps",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "かゆい",
        "pronunciation": "かゆい",
        "back": "itchy, itching",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "歌謡",
        "pronunciation": "かよう",
        "back": "song, ballad",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "空",
        "pronunciation": "から",
        "back": "empty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "殻",
        "pronunciation": "から",
        "back": "shell, husk, hull",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "柄",
        "pronunciation": "がら",
        "back": "pattern; build; character",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "刈る",
        "pronunciation": "かる",
        "back": "to cut (hair), to mow (grass), to harvest",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "河",
        "pronunciation": "かわ",
        "back": "river, stream",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "皮",
        "pronunciation": "かわ",
        "back": "skin, hide, leather",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "革",
        "pronunciation": "かわ",
        "back": "leather",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "可愛そう",
        "pronunciation": "かわいそう",
        "back": "poor, pitiable, pathetic",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "可愛らしい",
        "pronunciation": "かわいらしい",
        "back": "lovely, sweet",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "乾かす",
        "pronunciation": "かわかす",
        "back": "to dry",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "渇く",
        "pronunciation": "かわく",
        "back": "to be thirsty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "代る",
        "pronunciation": "かわる",
        "back": "to take the place of, to relieve, to be substituted for",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "缶",
        "pronunciation": "かん",
        "back": "can, tin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "勘",
        "pronunciation": "かん",
        "back": "perception, intuition, the sixth sense",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "考え",
        "pronunciation": "かんがえ",
        "back": "thinking, thought, ideas",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "感覚",
        "pronunciation": "かんかく",
        "back": "sense, sensation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "間隔",
        "pronunciation": "かんかく",
        "back": "space, interval, SPC",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "観客",
        "pronunciation": "かんきゃく",
        "back": "audience, spectator(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "環境",
        "pronunciation": "かんきょう",
        "back": "environment, circumstance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "歓迎",
        "pronunciation": "かんげい",
        "back": "welcome, reception",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "観光",
        "pronunciation": "かんこう",
        "back": "sightseeing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "観察",
        "pronunciation": "かんさつ",
        "back": "observation, survey",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "感じ",
        "pronunciation": "かんじ",
        "back": "feeling, sense, impression",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "感謝",
        "pronunciation": "かんしゃ",
        "back": "thanks, gratitude",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "患者",
        "pronunciation": "かんじゃ",
        "back": "patient",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "勘定",
        "pronunciation": "かんじょう",
        "back": "calculation, counting, consideration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "感情",
        "pronunciation": "かんじょう",
        "back": "emotion(s), feeling(s), sentiment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "感じる",
        "pronunciation": "かんじる",
        "back": "to feel, to sense",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "感心",
        "pronunciation": "かんしん",
        "back": "admiration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "関心",
        "pronunciation": "かんしん",
        "back": "concern, interest",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "関する",
        "pronunciation": "かんする",
        "back": "to concern, to be related",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "完成",
        "pronunciation": "かんせい",
        "back": "complete, completion; perfection",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "完全",
        "pronunciation": "かんぜん",
        "back": "perfection, completeness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "乾燥",
        "pronunciation": "かんそう",
        "back": "dry, arid, dehydrated",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "感想",
        "pronunciation": "かんそう",
        "back": "(one's) impressions, (one's) thoughts",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "感動",
        "pronunciation": "かんどう",
        "back": "being deeply moved, excitement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "監督",
        "pronunciation": "かんとく",
        "back": "supervision, control, (movie) director",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "管理",
        "pronunciation": "かんり",
        "back": "control, management (e.g., of a business)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "完了",
        "pronunciation": "かんりょう",
        "back": "completion, conclusion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "関連",
        "pronunciation": "かんれん",
        "back": "relation, connection, relevance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "議員",
        "pronunciation": "ぎいん",
        "back": "member of the Diet, congress, or parliament",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "記憶",
        "pronunciation": "きおく",
        "back": "memory, recollection, remembrance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "気温",
        "pronunciation": "きおん",
        "back": "temperature (weather - not used for things)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "機械",
        "pronunciation": "きかい",
        "back": "machine, machinery",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "器械",
        "pronunciation": "きかい",
        "back": "instrument",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "議会",
        "pronunciation": "ぎかい",
        "back": "Diet, congress, parliament",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "期間",
        "pronunciation": "きかん",
        "back": "period, term",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "機関",
        "pronunciation": "きかん",
        "back": "engine; institution, organization",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "企業",
        "pronunciation": "きぎょう",
        "back": "industry, business, undertaking",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "効く",
        "pronunciation": "きく",
        "back": "to be effective",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "期限",
        "pronunciation": "きげん",
        "back": "deadline, term",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "機嫌",
        "pronunciation": "きげん",
        "back": "humor, temper, mood",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "気候",
        "pronunciation": "きこう",
        "back": "climate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "岸",
        "pronunciation": "きし",
        "back": "bank, coast, shore",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生地",
        "pronunciation": "きじ",
        "back": "fabric; dough",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "記事",
        "pronunciation": "きじ",
        "back": "article, news story",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "技師",
        "pronunciation": "ぎし",
        "back": "engineer, technician",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "記者",
        "pronunciation": "きしゃ",
        "back": "reporter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "傷",
        "pronunciation": "きず",
        "back": "wound, injury, hurt",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "期待",
        "pronunciation": "きたい",
        "back": "expectation, anticipation, hope",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "気体",
        "pronunciation": "きたい",
        "back": "vapor, gas",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "帰宅",
        "pronunciation": "きたく",
        "back": "returning home",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "貴重",
        "pronunciation": "きちょう",
        "back": "precious, valuable",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "議長",
        "pronunciation": "ぎちょう",
        "back": "chairman",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "きちんと",
        "pronunciation": "きちんと",
        "back": "precisely, accurately",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "きつい",
        "pronunciation": "きつい",
        "back": "tight, close, intense",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "気付く",
        "pronunciation": "きづく",
        "back": "to notice, to recognize, to become aware of",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "気に入る",
        "pronunciation": "きにいる",
        "back": "to like, to be please",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "記入",
        "pronunciation": "きにゅう",
        "back": "entry, filling in of forms",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "記念",
        "pronunciation": "きねん",
        "back": "commemoration, memory",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "機能",
        "pronunciation": "きのう",
        "back": "function, faculty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "気の毒",
        "pronunciation": "きのどく",
        "back": "pitiful, a pity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "寄付",
        "pronunciation": "きふ",
        "back": "contribution, donation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "希望",
        "pronunciation": "きぼう",
        "back": "hope, wish, aspiration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "基本",
        "pronunciation": "きほん",
        "back": "basic, basis",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "決まり",
        "pronunciation": "きまり",
        "back": "settlement, conclusion, rule",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "気味",
        "pronunciation": "きみ",
        "back": "-like, -looking, -looked",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "奇妙",
        "pronunciation": "きみょう",
        "back": "strange, queer, curious",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "義務",
        "pronunciation": "ぎむ",
        "back": "duty, obligation, responsibility",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "疑問",
        "pronunciation": "ぎもん",
        "back": "question, problem, doubt",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "逆",
        "pronunciation": "ぎゃく",
        "back": "reverse, opposite",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "キャプテン",
        "pronunciation": "キャプテン",
        "back": "captain",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "キャンプ",
        "pronunciation": "キャンプ",
        "back": "camp",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "旧",
        "pronunciation": "きゅう",
        "back": "ex-",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "級",
        "pronunciation": "きゅう",
        "back": "class, grade, rank",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "球",
        "pronunciation": "きゅう",
        "back": "globe, sphere, ball",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "休暇",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうか",
        "back": "vacation, holiday, day off",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "休憩",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうけい",
        "back": "rest, break, intermission",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "急激",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうげき",
        "back": "sudden, precipitous, radical",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "吸収",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうしゅう",
        "back": "absorption, suction",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "救助",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうじょ",
        "back": "relief, aid, rescue",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "急速",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうそく",
        "back": "rapid (e.g., progress)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "休息",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうそく",
        "back": "rest, relief, relaxation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "急に",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうに",
        "back": "suddenly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "給料",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうりょう",
        "back": "salary, wages",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "器用",
        "pronunciation": "きよう",
        "back": "skillful, handy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "教科書",
        "pronunciation": "きょうかしょ",
        "back": "textbook",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "競技",
        "pronunciation": "きょうぎ",
        "back": "game, match, contest",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "行儀",
        "pronunciation": "ぎょうぎ",
        "back": "manners",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "供給",
        "pronunciation": "きょうきゅう",
        "back": "supply, provision",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "教授",
        "pronunciation": "きょうじゅ",
        "back": "teaching, instruction; professor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "強調",
        "pronunciation": "きょうちょう",
        "back": "emphasis, stress, stressed point",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "共通",
        "pronunciation": "きょうつう",
        "back": "commonness, mutual",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "共同",
        "pronunciation": "きょうどう",
        "back": "cooperation, association, collaboration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "恐怖",
        "pronunciation": "きょうふ",
        "back": "fear, terror",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "協力",
        "pronunciation": "きょうりょく",
        "back": "cooperation, collaboration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "強力",
        "pronunciation": "きょうりょく",
        "back": "powerful, strong",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "許可",
        "pronunciation": "きょか",
        "back": "permission, approval",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "局",
        "pronunciation": "きょく",
        "back": "office, bureau, station(TV, radio)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "巨大",
        "pronunciation": "きょだい",
        "back": "huge, gigantic, enormous",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "嫌う",
        "pronunciation": "きらう",
        "back": "to hate, to dislike, to loathe",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "霧",
        "pronunciation": "きり",
        "back": "fog, mist",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "切れ",
        "pronunciation": "きれ",
        "back": "cloth, piece, cut",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "切れる",
        "pronunciation": "きれる",
        "back": "to cut well, to be sharp; to break (off)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "記録",
        "pronunciation": "きろく",
        "back": "record, minutes, document",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "議論",
        "pronunciation": "ぎろん",
        "back": "argument, discussion, dispute",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "金",
        "pronunciation": "きん",
        "back": "gold, metal; money",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "銀",
        "pronunciation": "ぎん",
        "back": "silver",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "禁煙",
        "pronunciation": "きんえん",
        "back": "No Smoking",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "金額",
        "pronunciation": "きんがく",
        "back": "amount of money",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "金庫",
        "pronunciation": "きんこ",
        "back": "safe, vault",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "禁止",
        "pronunciation": "きんし",
        "back": "prohibition, ban",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "金銭",
        "pronunciation": "きんせん",
        "back": "money, cash",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "金属",
        "pronunciation": "きんぞく",
        "back": "metal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "近代",
        "pronunciation": "きんだい",
        "back": "modern times",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "緊張",
        "pronunciation": "きんちょう",
        "back": "tension, mental strain, nervousness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "筋肉",
        "pronunciation": "きんにく",
        "back": "muscle, sinews",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "金融",
        "pronunciation": "きんゆう",
        "back": "finance, money and banking",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "句",
        "pronunciation": "く",
        "back": "phrase",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "食う",
        "pronunciation": "くう",
        "back": "(male) (vulg.) to eat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "偶然",
        "pronunciation": "ぐうぜん",
        "back": "(by) chance, unexpectedly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "臭い",
        "pronunciation": "くさい",
        "back": "stinky, smelly, bad-smelling",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "鎖",
        "pronunciation": "くさり",
        "back": "chain",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "腐る",
        "pronunciation": "くさる",
        "back": "to rot, to go bad",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "癖",
        "pronunciation": "くせ",
        "back": "a habit (often a bad habit), peculiarity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "管",
        "pronunciation": "くだ",
        "back": "pipe, tube",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "具体",
        "pronunciation": "ぐたい",
        "back": "concrete, tangible, material",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "下り",
        "pronunciation": "くだり",
        "back": "down-train (going away from Tokyo)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "下る",
        "pronunciation": "くだる",
        "back": "to get down, to descend",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "苦痛",
        "pronunciation": "くつう",
        "back": "pain, agony",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぐっすり",
        "pronunciation": "ぐっすり",
        "back": "sound asleep, fast asleep",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "区別",
        "pronunciation": "くべつ",
        "back": "distinction, differentiation, classification",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "組",
        "pronunciation": "くみ",
        "back": "class, team, set",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "組合",
        "pronunciation": "くみあい",
        "back": "association, union",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "組む",
        "pronunciation": "くむ",
        "back": "to put together",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "汲む",
        "pronunciation": "くむ",
        "back": "to draw, to scoop, to pump",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "酌む",
        "pronunciation": "くむ",
        "back": "to serve sake",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "悔しい",
        "pronunciation": "くやしい",
        "back": "regrettable, mortifying, vexing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "位",
        "pronunciation": "くらい",
        "back": "grade, rank, about",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "暮らし",
        "pronunciation": "くらし",
        "back": "living; life style",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "クラシック",
        "pronunciation": "クラシック",
        "back": "classic(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "暮らす",
        "pronunciation": "くらす",
        "back": "to live, to get along",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "グラス",
        "pronunciation": "グラス",
        "back": "glass; grass",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "グランド",
        "pronunciation": "グランド",
        "back": "gland, grand, (electrical) ground",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "クリーム",
        "pronunciation": "クリーム",
        "back": "cream",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "繰り返す",
        "pronunciation": "くりかえす",
        "back": "to repeat, to do something over again",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "クリスマス",
        "pronunciation": "クリスマス",
        "back": "Christmas",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "狂う",
        "pronunciation": "くるう",
        "back": "to go mad, to get out of order",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "グループ",
        "pronunciation": "グループ",
        "back": "group",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "苦しい",
        "pronunciation": "くるしい",
        "back": "tough; physically strenuous",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "苦しむ",
        "pronunciation": "くるしむ",
        "back": "to suffer, to groan, to be worried",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "暮れ",
        "pronunciation": "くれ",
        "back": "year end,",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "苦労",
        "pronunciation": "くろう",
        "back": "hardship; suffering",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "加える",
        "pronunciation": "くわえる",
        "back": "to append, to sum up, to add (up)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "咥える",
        "pronunciation": "くわえる",
        "back": "to hold something in the mouth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "詳しい",
        "pronunciation": "くわしい",
        "back": "detailed; full; accurate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "加わる",
        "pronunciation": "くわわる",
        "back": "to join in, to accede to",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "訓",
        "pronunciation": "くん",
        "back": "native Japanese reading of a Chinese character",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "軍",
        "pronunciation": "ぐん",
        "back": "army, force, troops",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "郡",
        "pronunciation": "ぐん",
        "back": "country, district",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "軍隊",
        "pronunciation": "ぐんたい",
        "back": "army, troops",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "訓練",
        "pronunciation": "くんれん",
        "back": "practice, training",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "下",
        "pronunciation": "げ",
        "back": "under, below, beneath",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "計",
        "pronunciation": "けい",
        "back": "plan; sum, total",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "敬意",
        "pronunciation": "けいい",
        "back": "respect, honor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "経営",
        "pronunciation": "けいえい",
        "back": "management, administration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "景気",
        "pronunciation": "けいき",
        "back": "condition, state, business (condition)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "傾向",
        "pronunciation": "けいこう",
        "back": "tendency, trend, inclination",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "警告",
        "pronunciation": "けいこく",
        "back": "warning",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "計算",
        "pronunciation": "けいさん",
        "back": "calculation, reckoning",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "掲示",
        "pronunciation": "けいじ",
        "back": "notice, bulletin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "刑事",
        "pronunciation": "けいじ",
        "back": "criminal case, (police) detective",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "芸術",
        "pronunciation": "げいじゅつ",
        "back": "(fine) art, the arts",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "契約",
        "pronunciation": "けいやく",
        "back": "contract, compact, agreement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "経由",
        "pronunciation": "けいゆ",
        "back": "go by the way, via",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ケース",
        "pronunciation": "ケース",
        "back": "case",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ゲーム",
        "pronunciation": "ゲーム",
        "back": "game",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "劇",
        "pronunciation": "げき",
        "back": "drama, play",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "劇場",
        "pronunciation": "げきじょう",
        "back": "theater, playhouse",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "化粧",
        "pronunciation": "けしょう",
        "back": "make-up (cosmetic)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "けち",
        "pronunciation": "けち",
        "back": "stinginess, miser",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "血液",
        "pronunciation": "けつえき",
        "back": "blood",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "結果",
        "pronunciation": "けっか",
        "back": "result, consequence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "欠陥",
        "pronunciation": "けっかん",
        "back": "defect, fault, deficiency",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "結局",
        "pronunciation": "けっきょく",
        "back": "after all, eventually",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "決心",
        "pronunciation": "けっしん",
        "back": "determination, resolution",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "欠席",
        "pronunciation": "けっせき",
        "back": "absence, non-attendance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "決定",
        "pronunciation": "けってい",
        "back": "decision, determination",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "欠点",
        "pronunciation": "けってん",
        "back": "faults, defect, weakness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "結論",
        "pronunciation": "けつろん",
        "back": "conclusion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "煙",
        "pronunciation": "けむり",
        "back": "smoke, fumes",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "蹴る",
        "pronunciation": "ける",
        "back": "to kick",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "券",
        "pronunciation": "けん",
        "back": "ticket, certificate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "県",
        "pronunciation": "けん",
        "back": "prefecture",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "見解",
        "pronunciation": "けんかい",
        "back": "opinion, point of view",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "限界",
        "pronunciation": "げんかい",
        "back": "limit, bound",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "現金",
        "pronunciation": "げんきん",
        "back": "cash",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "言語",
        "pronunciation": "げんご",
        "back": "language",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "健康",
        "pronunciation": "けんこう",
        "back": "health(y)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "検査",
        "pronunciation": "けんさ",
        "back": "inspection, examination",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "現在",
        "pronunciation": "げんざい",
        "back": "now (same as 今 (いま)), present, current",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "現実",
        "pronunciation": "げんじつ",
        "back": "reality",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "現象",
        "pronunciation": "げんしょう",
        "back": "phenomenon",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "現状",
        "pronunciation": "げんじょう",
        "back": "present condition, status quo",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "建設",
        "pronunciation": "けんせつ",
        "back": "construction, foundation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "現代",
        "pronunciation": "げんだい",
        "back": "today, present-day",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "建築",
        "pronunciation": "けんちく",
        "back": "construction, architecture",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "見当",
        "pronunciation": "けんとう",
        "back": "estimate, guess",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "検討",
        "pronunciation": "けんとう",
        "back": "consideration, examination, investigation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "現場",
        "pronunciation": "げんば",
        "back": "actual spot, scene, field",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "憲法",
        "pronunciation": "けんぽう",
        "back": "constitution",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "権利",
        "pronunciation": "けんり",
        "back": "right, privilege",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "後",
        "pronunciation": "ご",
        "back": "afterwards, since then",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "碁",
        "pronunciation": "ご",
        "back": "Go (board game of capturing territory)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "恋",
        "pronunciation": "こい",
        "back": "love, tender passion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "濃い",
        "pronunciation": "こい",
        "back": "thick (as of color, liquid), dense, strong",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "恋人",
        "pronunciation": "こいびと",
        "back": "lover; sweetheart; girlfriend",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "幸運",
        "pronunciation": "こううん",
        "back": "good luck, fortune",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "講演",
        "pronunciation": "こうえん",
        "back": "lecture, talk",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "効果",
        "pronunciation": "こうか",
        "back": "effect, result",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "硬貨",
        "pronunciation": "こうか",
        "back": "coin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "高価",
        "pronunciation": "こうか",
        "back": "high price",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "豪華",
        "pronunciation": "ごうか",
        "back": "luxurious, gorgeous, extravagance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "合格",
        "pronunciation": "ごうかく",
        "back": "success, passing (e.g., exam)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "交換",
        "pronunciation": "こうかん",
        "back": "exchange, swap",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "航空",
        "pronunciation": "こうくう",
        "back": "aviation, flying",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "光景",
        "pronunciation": "こうけい",
        "back": "scene, spectacle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "合計",
        "pronunciation": "ごうけい",
        "back": "sum total, total amount",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "攻撃",
        "pronunciation": "こうげき",
        "back": "attack, strike, offensive",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "貢献",
        "pronunciation": "こうけん",
        "back": "contribution, services",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "広告",
        "pronunciation": "こうこく",
        "back": "advertisement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "交際",
        "pronunciation": "こうさい",
        "back": "friendship, association, acquaintance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "校舎",
        "pronunciation": "こうしゃ",
        "back": "school building",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "後者",
        "pronunciation": "こうしゃ",
        "back": "the latter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "工場",
        "pronunciation": "こうば",
        "back": "factory, plant",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "公正",
        "pronunciation": "こうせい",
        "back": "justice, fairness, impartiality",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "構成",
        "pronunciation": "こうせい",
        "back": "organization, composition",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "高速",
        "pronunciation": "こうそく",
        "back": "high speed, high gear",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "行動",
        "pronunciation": "こうどう",
        "back": "action, conduct, behavior",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "強盗",
        "pronunciation": "ごうとう",
        "back": "robbery, burglary",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "後輩",
        "pronunciation": "こうはい",
        "back": "junior members of a group",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "幸福",
        "pronunciation": "こうふく",
        "back": "happiness, blessedness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "公平",
        "pronunciation": "こうへい",
        "back": "fairness, impartial, justice",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "候補",
        "pronunciation": "こうほ",
        "back": "candidacy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "考慮",
        "pronunciation": "こうりょ",
        "back": "consideration, taking into account",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "越える",
        "pronunciation": "こえる",
        "back": "to exceed, to cross over, to cross",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "超える",
        "pronunciation": "こえる",
        "back": "to exceed, to cross over, to cross",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "コーチ",
        "pronunciation": "コーチ",
        "back": "coach",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "コード",
        "pronunciation": "コード",
        "back": "code; cord; chord",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "氷",
        "pronunciation": "こおり",
        "back": "ice, hail",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "凍る",
        "pronunciation": "こおる",
        "back": "to freeze, to be frozen over, to congeal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ゴール",
        "pronunciation": "ゴール",
        "back": "goal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "誤解",
        "pronunciation": "ごかい",
        "back": "misunderstanding",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "語学",
        "pronunciation": "ごがく",
        "back": "language study",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "呼吸",
        "pronunciation": "こきゅう",
        "back": "breath, respiration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "故郷",
        "pronunciation": "こきょう",
        "back": "hometown",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "極",
        "pronunciation": "ごく",
        "back": "quite, very",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "国語",
        "pronunciation": "こくご",
        "back": "national language",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "国籍",
        "pronunciation": "こくせき",
        "back": "nationality",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "黒板",
        "pronunciation": "こくばん",
        "back": "blackboard",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "克服",
        "pronunciation": "こくふく",
        "back": "conquest, overcome",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "国民",
        "pronunciation": "こくみん",
        "back": "national, people, citizen",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "穀物",
        "pronunciation": "こくもつ",
        "back": "grain, cereal, corn",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "腰",
        "pronunciation": "こし",
        "back": "hip, waist",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "胡椒",
        "pronunciation": "こしょう",
        "back": "pepper",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "個人",
        "pronunciation": "こじん",
        "back": "individual, private person",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "越す",
        "pronunciation": "こす",
        "back": "to go over (e.g., with audience)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "超す",
        "pronunciation": "こす",
        "back": "to cross, to pass, to tide over",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "国家",
        "pronunciation": "こっか",
        "back": "state, country, nation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "国会",
        "pronunciation": "こっかい",
        "back": "National Diet, parliament, congress",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "国境",
        "pronunciation": "こっきょう",
        "back": "national or state border",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "骨折",
        "pronunciation": "こっせつ",
        "back": "bone fracture",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "小包",
        "pronunciation": "こづつみ",
        "back": "parcel, package",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "琴",
        "pronunciation": "こと",
        "back": "Japanese harp",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "異なる",
        "pronunciation": "ことなる",
        "back": "to differ, to vary",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "諺",
        "pronunciation": "ことわざ",
        "back": "proverb, saying",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "断る",
        "pronunciation": "ことわる",
        "back": "to refuse, to decline, to dismiss",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "粉",
        "pronunciation": "こな",
        "back": "flour, powder",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "好み",
        "pronunciation": "このみ",
        "back": "liking, taste, choice",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "好む",
        "pronunciation": "このむ",
        "back": "to like, to prefer",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "こぼす",
        "pronunciation": "こぼす",
        "back": "to spill",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "こぼれる",
        "pronunciation": "こぼれる",
        "back": "to overflow, to spill",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "塵",
        "pronunciation": "ごみ",
        "back": "garbage, litter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "小麦",
        "pronunciation": "こむぎ",
        "back": "wheat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ごめんなさい",
        "pronunciation": "ごめんなさい",
        "back": "I beg your pardon, excuse me, I'm sorry",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "小屋",
        "pronunciation": "こや",
        "back": "hut, cabin, shed",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "これら",
        "pronunciation": "これら",
        "back": "these",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "殺す",
        "pronunciation": "ころす",
        "back": "to kill",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "転ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "ころぶ",
        "back": "to fall down, to fall over",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "今回",
        "pronunciation": "こんかい",
        "back": "now, this time, lately",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "今後",
        "pronunciation": "こんご",
        "back": "from now on, hereafter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "混雑",
        "pronunciation": "こんざつ",
        "back": "confusion, congestion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "こんなに",
        "pronunciation": "こんなに",
        "back": "so, like this, in this way",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "困難",
        "pronunciation": "こんなん",
        "back": "difficulty, distress",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "今日",
        "pronunciation": "こんにち",
        "back": "today, this day",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "こんにちは",
        "pronunciation": "こんにちは",
        "back": "hello, good day (daytime greeting)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "婚約",
        "pronunciation": "こんやく",
        "back": "engagement, betrothal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "混乱",
        "pronunciation": "こんらん",
        "back": "chaos, confusion, mayhem",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "差",
        "pronunciation": "さ",
        "back": "difference, variation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "サービス",
        "pronunciation": "サービス",
        "back": "service, support system; goods or services without charge",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "際",
        "pronunciation": "さい",
        "back": "on the occasion of, circumstances",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "最高",
        "pronunciation": "さいこう",
        "back": "highest, supreme, the most",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "財産",
        "pronunciation": "ざいさん",
        "back": "property, fortune, assets",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "最終",
        "pronunciation": "さいしゅう",
        "back": "last, closing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "最中",
        "pronunciation": "さいちゅう",
        "back": "in the middle of",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "最低",
        "pronunciation": "さいてい",
        "back": "least, lowest, worst",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "才能",
        "pronunciation": "さいのう",
        "back": "talent, ability",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "裁判",
        "pronunciation": "さいばん",
        "back": "trial, judgment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "材料",
        "pronunciation": "ざいりょう",
        "back": "ingredients, material",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "幸い",
        "pronunciation": "さいわい",
        "back": "fortunately; luckily",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "サイン",
        "pronunciation": "サイン",
        "back": "autograph; sign; sine",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "境",
        "pronunciation": "さかい",
        "back": "border, boundary, mental state",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "逆らう",
        "pronunciation": "さからう",
        "back": "to go against, to oppose, to disobey",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "盛り",
        "pronunciation": "さかり",
        "back": "helping, serving",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "作業",
        "pronunciation": "さぎょう",
        "back": "work, operation, manufacturing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "裂く",
        "pronunciation": "さく",
        "back": "to tear, to split",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "昨",
        "pronunciation": "さく",
        "back": "last (year), yesterday",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "作品",
        "pronunciation": "さくひん",
        "back": "work, opus, production",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "作物",
        "pronunciation": "さくもつ",
        "back": "produce (e.g., agricultural), crops",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "桜",
        "pronunciation": "さくら",
        "back": "cherry blossom, cherry tree",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "酒",
        "pronunciation": "さけ",
        "back": "alcohol, sake",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "叫ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "さけぶ",
        "back": "to shout, to cry",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "避ける",
        "pronunciation": "さける",
        "back": "to avoid (physical contact); to ward off, to avert",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "支える",
        "pronunciation": "ささえる",
        "back": "support, hold, sustain",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "刺さる",
        "pronunciation": "ささる",
        "back": "to stick, to be stuck",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "刺す",
        "pronunciation": "さす",
        "back": "to sting, to bite (e.g., bug), to prick, to stab",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "指す",
        "pronunciation": "さす",
        "back": "to point,",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "挿す",
        "pronunciation": "さす",
        "back": "to insert, to put in, to graft",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "注す",
        "pronunciation": "さす",
        "back": "to pour (drink), to serve (drinks)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "射す",
        "pronunciation": "さす",
        "back": "to shine, to strike",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "座席",
        "pronunciation": "ざせき",
        "back": "seat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "誘う",
        "pronunciation": "さそう",
        "back": "to invite (someone to do something with you); to tempt, to lure",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "札",
        "pronunciation": "さつ",
        "back": "bill, note",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "作家",
        "pronunciation": "さっか",
        "back": "author, writer, novelist",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "作曲",
        "pronunciation": "さっきょく",
        "back": "composition (of music)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ざっと",
        "pronunciation": "ざっと",
        "back": "roughly, in round numbers",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "さっぱり",
        "pronunciation": "さっぱり",
        "back": "feeling refreshed, neat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "さて",
        "pronunciation": "さて",
        "back": "well; now (typically used when switching to a new, usually more important topic)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "砂漠",
        "pronunciation": "さばく",
        "back": "desert",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "差別",
        "pronunciation": "さべつ",
        "back": "discrimination, differentiation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ママ",
        "pronunciation": "ママ",
        "back": "Mama",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "豆",
        "pronunciation": "まめ",
        "back": "beans, peas",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "守る",
        "pronunciation": "まもる",
        "back": "to protect; to abide (by the rules)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "迷う",
        "pronunciation": "まよう",
        "back": "to be puzzled, to be perplexed, to lose one's way",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "丸",
        "pronunciation": "まる",
        "back": "circle, full (month)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "円",
        "pronunciation": "まる",
        "back": "circle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "まるで",
        "pronunciation": "まるで",
        "back": "just like",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "万一",
        "pronunciation": "まんいち",
        "back": "by some chance, if by any chance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "満足",
        "pronunciation": "まんぞく",
        "back": "satisfaction",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "身",
        "pronunciation": "み",
        "back": "body, main part",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "実",
        "pronunciation": "み",
        "back": "fruit, seed, good result",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "見送り",
        "pronunciation": "みおくり",
        "back": "seeing one off",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "味方",
        "pronunciation": "みかた",
        "back": "ally, supporter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "見事",
        "pronunciation": "みごと",
        "back": "splendid, magnificent",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ミス",
        "pronunciation": "ミス",
        "back": "miss (mistake, error, failure), Miss",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "満ちる",
        "pronunciation": "みちる",
        "back": "to be full, to mature",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "密",
        "pronunciation": "みつ",
        "back": "thick, close",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "認める",
        "pronunciation": "みとめる",
        "back": "to recognize, to notice; to approve",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "見舞い",
        "pronunciation": "みまい",
        "back": "expression of sympathy, expression of concern",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "土産",
        "pronunciation": "みやげ",
        "back": "souvenir",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "都",
        "pronunciation": "みやこ",
        "back": "city; capital",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "妙",
        "pronunciation": "みょう",
        "back": "strange, unusual",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "明後日",
        "pronunciation": "みょうごにち",
        "back": "day after tomorrow",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "未来",
        "pronunciation": "みらい",
        "back": "future (life tense)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "魅力",
        "pronunciation": "みりょく",
        "back": "charm, fascination, appeal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "診る",
        "pronunciation": "みる",
        "back": "to examine (a patient)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ミルク",
        "pronunciation": "ミルク",
        "back": "milk",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "無",
        "pronunciation": "む",
        "back": "nothing, naught, zero",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "向かい",
        "pronunciation": "むかい",
        "back": "facing, opposite, across",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "迎え",
        "pronunciation": "むかえ",
        "back": "meeting, person sent to pick up an arrival",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "向く",
        "pronunciation": "むく",
        "back": "to face",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "剥く",
        "pronunciation": "むく",
        "back": "to peel, to skin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "向ける",
        "pronunciation": "むける",
        "back": "to turn towards, to point",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "無視",
        "pronunciation": "むし",
        "back": "disregard, ignore",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "蒸し暑い",
        "pronunciation": "むしあつい",
        "back": "humid, sultry",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "虫歯",
        "pronunciation": "むしば",
        "back": "cavity, tooth decay",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "寧ろ",
        "pronunciation": "むしろ",
        "back": "rather, better, instead",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "蒸す",
        "pronunciation": "むす",
        "back": "to steam, to poultice, to be sultry",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "結ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "むすぶ",
        "back": "to tie, to bind, to link",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "無駄",
        "pronunciation": "むだ",
        "back": "futility, uselessness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "夢中",
        "pronunciation": "むちゅう",
        "back": "crush, crazy, be hooked on",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "胸",
        "pronunciation": "むね",
        "back": "breast, chest",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "無料",
        "pronunciation": "むりょう",
        "back": "free, no charge",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "芽",
        "pronunciation": "め",
        "back": "sprout",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "明確",
        "pronunciation": "めいかく",
        "back": "clear, definite",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "名刺",
        "pronunciation": "めいし",
        "back": "(name) card; business card",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "名詞",
        "pronunciation": "めいし",
        "back": "noun",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "命じる",
        "pronunciation": "めいじる",
        "back": "to order, to command, to appoint",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "名人",
        "pronunciation": "めいじん",
        "back": "master, expert",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "命令",
        "pronunciation": "めいれい",
        "back": "order, command, decree",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "迷惑",
        "pronunciation": "めいわく",
        "back": "trouble, bother, annoyance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "目上",
        "pronunciation": "めうえ",
        "back": "person of higher status; one's senior",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "飯",
        "pronunciation": "めし",
        "back": "meals, food",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "滅多に",
        "pronunciation": "めったに",
        "back": "rarely (with neg. verb), seldom",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "メモ",
        "pronunciation": "メモ",
        "back": "memorandum, note",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "面",
        "pronunciation": "めん",
        "back": "face, mug, surface, side or facet, corner, page",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "綿",
        "pronunciation": "めん",
        "back": "cotton",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "免許",
        "pronunciation": "めんきょ",
        "back": "license, permit, certificate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "面接",
        "pronunciation": "めんせつ",
        "back": "interview",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "面倒",
        "pronunciation": "めんどう",
        "back": "trouble, attention",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "メンバー",
        "pronunciation": "メンバー",
        "back": "member",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "申し込む",
        "pronunciation": "もうしこむ",
        "back": "to apply for, to make an application",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "申し訳",
        "pronunciation": "もうしわけ",
        "back": "apology, excuse",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "毛布",
        "pronunciation": "もうふ",
        "back": "blanket",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "燃える",
        "pronunciation": "もえる",
        "back": "to burn",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "目的",
        "pronunciation": "もくてき",
        "back": "purpose, goal, aim",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "目標",
        "pronunciation": "もくひょう",
        "back": "mark, objective, target",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "文字",
        "pronunciation": "もじ",
        "back": "letter (of alphabet), character",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "文字",
        "pronunciation": "もんじ",
        "back": "letter (of alphabet), character",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "もしかすると",
        "pronunciation": "もしかすると",
        "back": "perhaps, maybe, by some chance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "もしも",
        "pronunciation": "もしも",
        "back": "if",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "持ち上げる",
        "pronunciation": "もちあげる",
        "back": "to raise, to lift up, to flatter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "用いる",
        "pronunciation": "もちいる",
        "back": "to use, to make use of",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "もったいない",
        "pronunciation": "もったいない",
        "back": "wasteful; more than one deserves, unworthy of",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "尤も",
        "pronunciation": "もっとも",
        "back": "quite right, plausible, natural",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "元",
        "pronunciation": "もと",
        "back": "origin, original; former",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "基",
        "pronunciation": "もと",
        "back": "basis",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "素",
        "pronunciation": "もと",
        "back": "prime",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "戻す",
        "pronunciation": "もどす",
        "back": "to restore, to put back, to return",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "基づく",
        "pronunciation": "もとづく",
        "back": "to be grounded on, to be based on",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "求める",
        "pronunciation": "もとめる",
        "back": "to request, to ask for; to seek, to search for",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "者",
        "pronunciation": "もの",
        "back": "person (same as 人 (ひと))",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "物音",
        "pronunciation": "ものおと",
        "back": "sounds",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "物語",
        "pronunciation": "ものがたり",
        "back": "tale, story, legend",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "物事",
        "pronunciation": "ものごと",
        "back": "things, everything",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "燃やす",
        "pronunciation": "もやす",
        "back": "to burn",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "模様",
        "pronunciation": "もよう",
        "back": "pattern, figure, design",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "文句",
        "pronunciation": "もんく",
        "back": "a complaint",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "やがて",
        "pronunciation": "やがて",
        "back": "before long, soon, at length",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "役",
        "pronunciation": "やく",
        "back": "role, position",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "約",
        "pronunciation": "やく",
        "back": "approximately, about, some",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "訳",
        "pronunciation": "やく",
        "back": "translation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "訳す",
        "pronunciation": "やくす",
        "back": "to translate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "役割",
        "pronunciation": "やくわり",
        "back": "assigning (allotment of) parts, role, duties",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "家賃",
        "pronunciation": "やちん",
        "back": "rent",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "厄介",
        "pronunciation": "やっかい",
        "back": "trouble, burden, care",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "宿",
        "pronunciation": "やど",
        "back": "inn, lodging",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "雇う",
        "pronunciation": "やとう",
        "back": "to employ, to hire",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "屋根",
        "pronunciation": "やね",
        "back": "roof",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "破る",
        "pronunciation": "やぶる",
        "back": "to tear; to violate; to defeat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "破れる",
        "pronunciation": "やぶれる",
        "back": "to get torn, to wear out",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "辞める",
        "pronunciation": "やめる",
        "back": "to retire",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "やや",
        "pronunciation": "やや",
        "back": "a little, partially, somewhat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "唯一",
        "pronunciation": "ゆいいつ",
        "back": "only, sole, unique",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "勇気",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうき",
        "back": "courage, bravery, boldness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "友好",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうこう",
        "back": "friendship",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "有効",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうこう",
        "back": "valid, effectual",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "優秀",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうしゅう",
        "back": "superiority, excellence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "優勝",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうしょう",
        "back": "overall victory, championship",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "友情",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうじょう",
        "back": "friendship, fellowship",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "友人",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうじん",
        "back": "friend (formal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "有能",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうのう",
        "back": "able, capable, efficient",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "郵便",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうびん",
        "back": "mail, postal service",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ユーモア",
        "pronunciation": "ユーモア",
        "back": "humor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "有利",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうり",
        "back": "advantageous, better",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "床",
        "pronunciation": "ゆか",
        "back": "floor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "愉快",
        "pronunciation": "ゆかい",
        "back": "pleasant, happy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "譲る",
        "pronunciation": "ゆずる",
        "back": "to turn over, to assign, to hand over",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "豊か",
        "pronunciation": "ゆたか",
        "back": "abundant, wealthy, plentiful, rich",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "茹でる",
        "pronunciation": "ゆでる",
        "back": "to boil",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "許す",
        "pronunciation": "ゆるす",
        "back": "to permit, to allow, to approve",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "夜",
        "pronunciation": "よ",
        "back": "evening, night",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "夜明け",
        "pronunciation": "よあけ",
        "back": "dawn, daybreak",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "酔う",
        "pronunciation": "よう",
        "back": "to get drunk",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "容易",
        "pronunciation": "ようい",
        "back": "easy, simple, plain",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "容器",
        "pronunciation": "ようき",
        "back": "container, vessel",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "陽気",
        "pronunciation": "ようき",
        "back": "season, weather, cheerfulness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "要求",
        "pronunciation": "ようきゅう",
        "back": "request, demand",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "用心",
        "pronunciation": "ようじん",
        "back": "care, precaution, caution",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "様子",
        "pronunciation": "ようす",
        "back": "aspect, state, appearance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "要するに",
        "pronunciation": "ようするに",
        "back": "in a word, after all, in short …",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "要素",
        "pronunciation": "ようそ",
        "back": "element",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "要点",
        "pronunciation": "ようてん",
        "back": "gist, main point",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "曜日",
        "pronunciation": "ようび",
        "back": "day of the week",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ヨーロッパ",
        "pronunciation": "ヨーロッパ",
        "back": "Europe",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "予期",
        "pronunciation": "よき",
        "back": "expectation, forecast",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "横切る",
        "pronunciation": "よこぎる",
        "back": "to cross (e.g., arms), to traverse",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "汚す",
        "pronunciation": "よごす",
        "back": "to pollute, to make dirty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "予算",
        "pronunciation": "よさん",
        "back": "estimate, budget",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "止す",
        "pronunciation": "よす",
        "back": "to cease, to give up",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "寄せる",
        "pronunciation": "よせる",
        "back": "to collect, to gather, to put aside",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "予測",
        "pronunciation": "よそく",
        "back": "prediction, estimation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ヨット",
        "pronunciation": "ヨット",
        "back": "yacht",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "夜中",
        "pronunciation": "よなか",
        "back": "midnight, dead of night",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "世の中",
        "pronunciation": "よのなか",
        "back": "society, the world",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "余分",
        "pronunciation": "よぶん",
        "back": "extra, excess, surplus",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "予報",
        "pronunciation": "よほう",
        "back": "forecast, prediction",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "予防",
        "pronunciation": "よぼう",
        "back": "prevention, protection against",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "読み",
        "pronunciation": "よみ",
        "back": "reading",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "嫁",
        "pronunciation": "よめ",
        "back": "bride, daughter-in-law",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "余裕",
        "pronunciation": "よゆう",
        "back": "excess; surplus",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "より",
        "pronunciation": "より",
        "back": "twist, ply",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "因る",
        "pronunciation": "よる",
        "back": "to come from",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "喜び",
        "pronunciation": "よろこび",
        "back": "joy, pleasure, rejoicing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "よろしく (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "よろしく (かん)",
        "back": "best regards, please remember me",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "四",
        "pronunciation": "よん",
        "back": "four",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "来",
        "pronunciation": "らい～",
        "back": "next ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ライター",
        "pronunciation": "ライター",
        "back": "lighter; writer",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "楽",
        "pronunciation": "らく",
        "back": "comfort, ease",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ラケット",
        "pronunciation": "ラケット",
        "back": "racket",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "利益",
        "pronunciation": "りえき",
        "back": "profits, gains",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "理解",
        "pronunciation": "りかい",
        "back": "understanding, comprehension",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "陸",
        "pronunciation": "りく",
        "back": "land, shore",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "利口",
        "pronunciation": "りこう",
        "back": "clever, shrewd, bright",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "離婚",
        "pronunciation": "りこん",
        "back": "divorce",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "理想",
        "pronunciation": "りそう",
        "back": "ideal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "率",
        "pronunciation": "りつ",
        "back": "rate, ratio, percentage",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "留学",
        "pronunciation": "りゅうがく",
        "back": "studying abroad",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "流行",
        "pronunciation": "りゅうこう",
        "back": "fashionable, fad, prevailing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "量",
        "pronunciation": "りょう",
        "back": "quantity, amount",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "寮",
        "pronunciation": "りょう",
        "back": "hostel, dormitory",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "両替",
        "pronunciation": "りょうがえ",
        "back": "change, money exchange",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "料金",
        "pronunciation": "りょうきん",
        "back": "fee, charge, fare",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "例",
        "pronunciation": "れい",
        "back": "instance, example, case",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "礼",
        "pronunciation": "れい",
        "back": "expression of gratitude; bow",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "例外",
        "pronunciation": "れいがい",
        "back": "exception",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "礼儀",
        "pronunciation": "れいぎ",
        "back": "manners, courtesy, etiquette",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷静",
        "pronunciation": "れいせい",
        "back": "calm, coolness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "列",
        "pronunciation": "れつ",
        "back": "queue, line, row",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "列車",
        "pronunciation": "れっしゃ",
        "back": "train (ordinary)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "レベル",
        "pronunciation": "レベル",
        "back": "level",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "連想",
        "pronunciation": "れんそう",
        "back": "association (of ideas), suggestion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "連続",
        "pronunciation": "れんぞく",
        "back": "consecutive, continuity, continuing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "老人",
        "pronunciation": "ろうじん",
        "back": "the aged, old person",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "労働",
        "pronunciation": "ろうどう",
        "back": "labor, work",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ロケット",
        "pronunciation": "ロケット",
        "back": "locket, rocket",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "論じる",
        "pronunciation": "ろんじる",
        "back": "to argue, to discuss",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "論争",
        "pronunciation": "ろんそう",
        "back": "controversy, dispute",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "論文",
        "pronunciation": "ろんぶん",
        "back": "thesis, paper",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "輪",
        "pronunciation": "わ",
        "back": "ring, hoop, circle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ワイン",
        "pronunciation": "ワイン",
        "back": "wine",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "わがまま",
        "pronunciation": "わがまま",
        "back": "selfishness, egoism, willfulness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "別れ",
        "pronunciation": "わかれ",
        "back": "parting, separation, farewell",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "分かれる",
        "pronunciation": "わかれる",
        "back": "to branch off, to diverge from",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "脇",
        "pronunciation": "わき",
        "back": "side",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "湧く",
        "pronunciation": "わく",
        "back": "to boil, to grow hot",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "分ける",
        "pronunciation": "わける",
        "back": "to divide, to separate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "わざと",
        "pronunciation": "わざと",
        "back": "on purpose",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "僅か",
        "pronunciation": "わずか",
        "back": "only, merely, a little",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "綿",
        "pronunciation": "わた",
        "back": "cotton",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "話題",
        "pronunciation": "わだい",
        "back": "topic, subject",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "笑い",
        "pronunciation": "わらい",
        "back": "laugh, laughter, smile",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "割る",
        "pronunciation": "わる",
        "back": "to divide, to break",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "悪口",
        "pronunciation": "わるくち",
        "back": "abuse, insult",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "我々",
        "pronunciation": "われわれ",
        "back": "we",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "湾",
        "pronunciation": "わん",
        "back": "bay, gulf, inlet",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "椀",
        "pronunciation": "わん",
        "back": "bowl",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "碗",
        "pronunciation": "わん",
        "back": "bowl",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "悪",
        "pronunciation": "あく",
        "back": "evil, vice",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "当り",
        "pronunciation": "あたり",
        "back": "hit, success, reaching the mark",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "アップ",
        "pronunciation": "アップ",
        "back": "up",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "宛てる",
        "pronunciation": "あてる",
        "back": "to address, to put",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "アンケート",
        "pronunciation": "アンケート",
        "back": "questionnaire (FRE: enquete), survey",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "異",
        "pronunciation": "い",
        "back": "difference (of opinion)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "意",
        "pronunciation": "い",
        "back": "will",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "医院",
        "pronunciation": "いいん",
        "back": "doctor's office (surgery), clinic",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "怒り",
        "pronunciation": "いかり",
        "back": "anger",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "粋",
        "pronunciation": "いき",
        "back": "chic, style, purity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "意地",
        "pronunciation": "いじ",
        "back": "disposition, spirit, obstinacy, appetite",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "依然",
        "pronunciation": "いぜん",
        "back": "still, as yet",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "傷める",
        "pronunciation": "いためる",
        "back": "to damage, to impair, to spoil",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "炒める",
        "pronunciation": "いためる",
        "back": "to stir-fry",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一帯",
        "pronunciation": "いったい",
        "back": "a region, the whole place",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "異動",
        "pronunciation": "いどう",
        "back": "a change, transfer",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "衣料",
        "pronunciation": "いりょう",
        "back": "clothing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "渦",
        "pronunciation": "うず",
        "back": "swirl",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "埋まる",
        "pronunciation": "うまる",
        "back": "to be buried, to be filled",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "産む",
        "pronunciation": "うむ",
        "back": "to give birth (v.t.), to deliver, to produce",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "縁",
        "pronunciation": "えん",
        "back": "chance, tie, relationship",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "尾",
        "pronunciation": "お",
        "back": "tail, ridge",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "負う",
        "pronunciation": "おう",
        "back": "to bear, to owe",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "遅れ",
        "pronunciation": "おくれ",
        "back": "delay, lag",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "教え",
        "pronunciation": "おしえ",
        "back": "teachings, doctrine",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "驚き",
        "pronunciation": "おどろき",
        "back": "surprise, astonishment, wonder",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "織る",
        "pronunciation": "おる",
        "back": "to weave",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "欠く",
        "pronunciation": "かく",
        "back": "to lack, to crack",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "角",
        "pronunciation": "かく",
        "back": "angle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "核",
        "pronunciation": "かく",
        "back": "nucleus, kernel",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "格",
        "pronunciation": "かく",
        "back": "status, character, case",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "学歴",
        "pronunciation": "がくれき",
        "back": "academic background",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "駆ける",
        "pronunciation": "かける",
        "back": "to run",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "賭ける",
        "pronunciation": "かける",
        "back": "to bet, to risk, to gamble",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "課題",
        "pronunciation": "かだい",
        "back": "subject, theme, task",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "片付け",
        "pronunciation": "かたづけ",
        "back": "tidying up, finishing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "加味",
        "pronunciation": "かみ",
        "back": "seasoning, flavoring",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "借り",
        "pronunciation": "かり",
        "back": "borrowing, debt, loan",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "狩り",
        "pronunciation": "かり",
        "back": "hunting",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "管",
        "pronunciation": "かん",
        "back": "pipe, tube",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "～観",
        "pronunciation": "かん",
        "back": "feeling, view",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "癌",
        "pronunciation": "がん",
        "back": "cancer",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "刊行",
        "pronunciation": "かんこう",
        "back": "publication, issue",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "慣行",
        "pronunciation": "かんこう",
        "back": "customary practice, habit, traditional event",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "歓声",
        "pronunciation": "かんせい",
        "back": "cheer, shout of joy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "官僚",
        "pronunciation": "かんりょう",
        "back": "bureaucrat, bureaucracy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "器官",
        "pronunciation": "きかん",
        "back": "organ (of body, instrument)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "季刊",
        "pronunciation": "きかん",
        "back": "quarterly (e.g., magazine)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "起源",
        "pronunciation": "きげん",
        "back": "origin, beginning, rise",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "機構",
        "pronunciation": "きこう",
        "back": "mechanism, organization",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "築く",
        "pronunciation": "きずく",
        "back": "to build, to establish",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "規制",
        "pronunciation": "きせい",
        "back": "regulation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "丘陵",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうりょう",
        "back": "hill",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "協議",
        "pronunciation": "きょうぎ",
        "back": "conference, discussion, negotiation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "享受",
        "pronunciation": "きょうじゅ",
        "back": "enjoyment, being given",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "協調",
        "pronunciation": "きょうちょう",
        "back": "co-operation, conciliation, harmony",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "切り",
        "pronunciation": "きり",
        "back": "limits, place to leave off",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "菌",
        "pronunciation": "きん",
        "back": "germ, bacterium",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "近視",
        "pronunciation": "きんし",
        "back": "nearsightedness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "苦",
        "pronunciation": "く",
        "back": "trouble, worry, difficulty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "群",
        "pronunciation": "ぐん",
        "back": "group",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "刑",
        "pronunciation": "けい",
        "back": "penalty, sentence, punishment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "経緯",
        "pronunciation": "けいい",
        "back": "sequence of events, course",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "計器",
        "pronunciation": "けいき",
        "back": "meter, gauge",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "契機",
        "pronunciation": "けいき",
        "back": "opportunity, chance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "携帯",
        "pronunciation": "けいたい",
        "back": "carrying something; mobile telephone",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "形態",
        "pronunciation": "けいたい",
        "back": "form, shape, figure",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "血管",
        "pronunciation": "けっかん",
        "back": "blood vessel",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "決行",
        "pronunciation": "けっこう",
        "back": "doing (with resolve), carrying out (e.g., a plan)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "件",
        "pronunciation": "けん",
        "back": "matter, case, item",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "減少",
        "pronunciation": "げんしょう",
        "back": "decrease, reduction, decline",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "公演",
        "pronunciation": "こうえん",
        "back": "public performance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "後悔",
        "pronunciation": "こうかい",
        "back": "regret, repentance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "航海",
        "pronunciation": "こうかい",
        "back": "sail, voyage",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "拘束",
        "pronunciation": "こうそく",
        "back": "restriction, restraint",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "荒廃",
        "pronunciation": "こうはい",
        "back": "ruin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "降伏",
        "pronunciation": "こうふく",
        "back": "capitulation, surrender, submission",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "興奮",
        "pronunciation": "こうふん",
        "back": "excitement, stimulation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "語句",
        "pronunciation": "ごく",
        "back": "words, phrases",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "個々",
        "pronunciation": "ここ",
        "back": "individual, one by one",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "故人",
        "pronunciation": "こじん",
        "back": "the deceased",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "小銭",
        "pronunciation": "こぜに",
        "back": "coins, small change",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ことによると",
        "pronunciation": "ことによると",
        "back": "(depending on the circumstances)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "コンテスト",
        "pronunciation": "コンテスト",
        "back": "contest",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "採集",
        "pronunciation": "さいしゅう",
        "back": "collecting, gathering",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "作",
        "pronunciation": "さく",
        "back": "a work, a harvest",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "策",
        "pronunciation": "さく",
        "back": "plan, policy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "設備",
        "pronunciation": "せつび",
        "back": "equipment, device, facilities",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "絶滅",
        "pronunciation": "ぜつめつ",
        "back": "destruction, extinction",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "節約",
        "pronunciation": "せつやく",
        "back": "economizing, saving",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "攻める",
        "pronunciation": "せめる",
        "back": "to attack, to assault",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "責める",
        "pronunciation": "せめる",
        "back": "to condemn, to blame, to criticize",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "善",
        "pronunciation": "ぜん",
        "back": "good, virtue",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "全",
        "pronunciation": "ぜん",
        "back": "all, whole, entire",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "全員",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんいん",
        "back": "all members",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "専攻",
        "pronunciation": "せんこう",
        "back": "major subject, special study",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "全国",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんこく",
        "back": "the entire nation, country-wide, nation-wide",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "洗剤",
        "pronunciation": "せんざい",
        "back": "detergent",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "先日",
        "pronunciation": "せんじつ",
        "back": "the other day, a few days ago",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "前者",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんしゃ",
        "back": "the former",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "選手",
        "pronunciation": "せんしゅ",
        "back": "player selected for a team (usually athletic)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "全身",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんしん",
        "back": "the whole body, full-length (portrait)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "前進",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんしん",
        "back": "advance, drive, progress",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "センター",
        "pronunciation": "センター",
        "back": "center",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "全体",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんたい",
        "back": "whole, entirety, whatever (is the matter)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "選択",
        "pronunciation": "せんたく",
        "back": "selection, choice",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "宣伝",
        "pronunciation": "せんでん",
        "back": "advertisement, publicity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "象",
        "pronunciation": "ぞう",
        "back": "elephant",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "騒音",
        "pronunciation": "そうおん",
        "back": "noise",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "増加",
        "pronunciation": "ぞうか",
        "back": "increase, addition",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "操作",
        "pronunciation": "そうさ",
        "back": "operation, management, processing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "想像",
        "pronunciation": "そうぞう",
        "back": "imagination, guess",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "相続",
        "pronunciation": "そうぞく",
        "back": "succession, inheritance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "装置",
        "pronunciation": "そうち",
        "back": "equipment, installation, apparatus",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "相当",
        "pronunciation": "そうとう",
        "back": "considerably, fairly; worth ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "速度",
        "pronunciation": "そくど",
        "back": "speed, velocity, rate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "底",
        "pronunciation": "そこ",
        "back": "bottom, sole",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "そこで",
        "pronunciation": "そこで",
        "back": "so (conj.), accordingly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "組織",
        "pronunciation": "そしき",
        "back": "organization; structure; tissue",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "そして",
        "pronunciation": "そして",
        "back": "and then",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "注ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "そそぐ",
        "back": "to pour (into)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "育つ",
        "pronunciation": "そだつ",
        "back": "to be brought up, to grow (up)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "そっくり",
        "pronunciation": "そっくり",
        "back": "the splitting image of; entirely",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "そっと",
        "pronunciation": "そっと",
        "back": "softly, gently",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "袖",
        "pronunciation": "そで",
        "back": "sleeve",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "備える",
        "pronunciation": "そなえる",
        "back": "to prepare, to furnish, to store",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "具える",
        "pronunciation": "そなえる",
        "back": "to be furnished with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "そのうえ",
        "pronunciation": "そのうえ",
        "back": "in addition, furthermore",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "そのうち",
        "pronunciation": "そのうち",
        "back": "before long, eventually, sooner or later",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "そのまま",
        "pronunciation": "そのまま",
        "back": "without change, as it is (e.g., now)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "蕎麦",
        "pronunciation": "そば",
        "back": "soba (buckwheat noodles)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ソファー",
        "pronunciation": "ソファー",
        "back": "sofa, couch",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "粗末",
        "pronunciation": "そまつ",
        "back": "humble, miserable, crude",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "それぞれ",
        "pronunciation": "それぞれ",
        "back": "each, every, respectively",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "それでも",
        "pronunciation": "それでも",
        "back": "but (still), and yet, nevertheless",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "それと",
        "pronunciation": "それと",
        "back": "and",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "それとも",
        "pronunciation": "それとも",
        "back": "or, or else",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "揃う",
        "pronunciation": "そろう",
        "back": "to become complete, to be equal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "揃える",
        "pronunciation": "そろえる",
        "back": "to put things in order, to arrange",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "損",
        "pronunciation": "そん",
        "back": "loss, disadvantage",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "損害",
        "pronunciation": "そんがい",
        "back": "damage, loss",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "尊敬",
        "pronunciation": "そんけい",
        "back": "respect, reverence, honor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "存在",
        "pronunciation": "そんざい",
        "back": "existence, being",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "尊重",
        "pronunciation": "そんちょう",
        "back": "respect, esteem, regard",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "田",
        "pronunciation": "た",
        "back": "rice field",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "他",
        "pronunciation": "た",
        "back": "other (esp. places and things)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "対",
        "pronunciation": "たい",
        "back": "pair, couple, set",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大",
        "pronunciation": "だい",
        "back": "big, great",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "題",
        "pronunciation": "だい",
        "back": "title, subject, theme",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "体育",
        "pronunciation": "たいいく",
        "back": "physical education, gymnastics, athletics",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "体温",
        "pronunciation": "たいおん",
        "back": "temperature (body)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大会",
        "pronunciation": "たいかい",
        "back": "convention, (big) tournament, mass meeting",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大気",
        "pronunciation": "たいき",
        "back": "atmosphere",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "代金",
        "pronunciation": "だいきん",
        "back": "price, cost",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "退屈",
        "pronunciation": "たいくつ",
        "back": "tedium, boring",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "滞在",
        "pronunciation": "たいざい",
        "back": "stay, sojourn",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大使",
        "pronunciation": "たいし",
        "back": "ambassador",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大した",
        "pronunciation": "たいした",
        "back": "significant, great, considerable",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "体重",
        "pronunciation": "たいじゅう",
        "back": "(body) weight",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "対象",
        "pronunciation": "たいしょう",
        "back": "target; object (of worship, study, etc.); subject (i.e., of taxation)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "対照",
        "pronunciation": "たいしょう",
        "back": "contrast, antithesis, comparison",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大臣",
        "pronunciation": "だいじん",
        "back": "cabinet minister",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "対する",
        "pronunciation": "たいする",
        "back": "to face, to confront, to oppose",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大戦",
        "pronunciation": "たいせん",
        "back": "great war, great battle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "態度",
        "pronunciation": "たいど",
        "back": "attitude, manner",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大統領",
        "pronunciation": "だいとうりょう",
        "back": "president",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大半",
        "pronunciation": "たいはん",
        "back": "most of, majority, mostly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "代表",
        "pronunciation": "だいひょう",
        "back": "representative, delegation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大部分",
        "pronunciation": "だいぶぶん",
        "back": "most part, majority",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "タイプライター",
        "pronunciation": "タイプライター",
        "back": "typewriter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "逮捕",
        "pronunciation": "たいほ",
        "back": "arrest, apprehension, capture",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "題名",
        "pronunciation": "だいめい",
        "back": "title",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ダイヤ",
        "pronunciation": "ダイヤ",
        "back": "(railway) schedule; diamond",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "太陽",
        "pronunciation": "たいよう",
        "back": "sun",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "平ら",
        "pronunciation": "たいら",
        "back": "flatness, level, smooth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "代理",
        "pronunciation": "だいり",
        "back": "representation, proxy, deputy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "大陸",
        "pronunciation": "たいりく",
        "back": "continent",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "倒す",
        "pronunciation": "たおす",
        "back": "to throw down, to beat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "タオル",
        "pronunciation": "タオル",
        "back": "(hand) towel",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "だが",
        "pronunciation": "だが",
        "back": "but, however",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "互い",
        "pronunciation": "たがい",
        "back": "mutual, each other",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "高める",
        "pronunciation": "たかめる",
        "back": "to raise, to lift, to boost",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "宝",
        "pronunciation": "たから",
        "back": "treasure",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "宅",
        "pronunciation": "たく",
        "back": "house, home",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "炊く",
        "pronunciation": "たく",
        "back": "to boil, to cook",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "焚く",
        "pronunciation": "たく",
        "back": "to burn, to kindle, to build a fire",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "抱く",
        "pronunciation": "だく",
        "back": "to embrace, to hug",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "だけど",
        "pronunciation": "だけど",
        "back": "however",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "たしか",
        "pronunciation": "たしか",
        "back": "certain, sure, if I remember correctly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "確かめる",
        "pronunciation": "たしかめる",
        "back": "to ascertain, to make sure",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "多少",
        "pronunciation": "たしょう",
        "back": "a little (same as 少し (すこし))",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "助かる",
        "pronunciation": "たすかる",
        "back": "to be saved; (something) helps (v.i.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "助ける",
        "pronunciation": "たすける",
        "back": "to help (v.t.), to save, to rescue",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ただ",
        "pronunciation": "ただ",
        "back": "free of charge; just (~); only (~)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "只",
        "pronunciation": "ただ",
        "back": "free of charge, mere, only",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "唯",
        "pronunciation": "ただ",
        "back": "mere, sole, plain",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "戦い",
        "pronunciation": "たたかい",
        "back": "battle, fight",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "戦う",
        "pronunciation": "たたかう",
        "back": "to fight, to compete, to battle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "叩く",
        "pronunciation": "たたく",
        "back": "to strike, to beat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "直ちに",
        "pronunciation": "ただちに",
        "back": "at once, immediately",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "畳む",
        "pronunciation": "たたむ",
        "back": "to fold (clothes)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "立ち上がる",
        "pronunciation": "たちあがる",
        "back": "to stand up",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "立場",
        "pronunciation": "たちば",
        "back": "standpoint, position, situation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "建つ",
        "pronunciation": "たつ",
        "back": "to stand; to be built (v.i.), to erect, to be erected",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "経つ",
        "pronunciation": "たつ",
        "back": "(time) passes",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "達する",
        "pronunciation": "たっする",
        "back": "to reach, to get to",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "唯",
        "pronunciation": "たった",
        "back": "only, just",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "だって",
        "pronunciation": "だって",
        "back": "but, because, even",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "たっぷり",
        "pronunciation": "たっぷり",
        "back": "full, in plenty, ample",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "たとえ",
        "pronunciation": "たとえ",
        "back": "even if, no matter, though",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "谷",
        "pronunciation": "たに",
        "back": "valley",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "他人",
        "pronunciation": "たにん",
        "back": "unrelated person, stranger",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "種",
        "pronunciation": "たね",
        "back": "seed; material; cause",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "束",
        "pronunciation": "たば",
        "back": "bunch, bundle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "足袋",
        "pronunciation": "たび",
        "back": "Japanese socks (with split toe)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "度",
        "pronunciation": "たび",
        "back": "counter for occurrences",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "旅",
        "pronunciation": "たび",
        "back": "travel, trip, journey",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "たびたび",
        "pronunciation": "たびたび",
        "back": "often, repeatedly, frequently",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "玉",
        "pronunciation": "たま",
        "back": "ball, sphere, coin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "球",
        "pronunciation": "たま",
        "back": "globe, sphere, ball",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "弾",
        "pronunciation": "たま",
        "back": "bullet, shot",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "偶",
        "pronunciation": "たま",
        "back": "even number, couple, friend",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "騙す",
        "pronunciation": "だます",
        "back": "to trick, to cheat, to deceive",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "偶々",
        "pronunciation": "たまたま",
        "back": "unexpectedly, accidentally, by chance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "たまらない",
        "pronunciation": "たまらない",
        "back": "intolerable, unbearable, unendurable",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "溜まる",
        "pronunciation": "たまる",
        "back": "to collect, to gather, to accumulate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "黙る",
        "pronunciation": "だまる",
        "back": "to be silent",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "試し",
        "pronunciation": "ためし",
        "back": "trial, test",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "試す",
        "pronunciation": "ためす",
        "back": "to attempt, to test",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "溜める",
        "pronunciation": "ためる",
        "back": "to accumulate, to collect",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "便り",
        "pronunciation": "たより",
        "back": "news, correspondence, letter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "頼る",
        "pronunciation": "たよる",
        "back": "to rely on, to have recourse to, to depend on",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "段",
        "pronunciation": "だん",
        "back": "step, stair, grade",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "単位",
        "pronunciation": "たんい",
        "back": "credit (for a course in school); unit, denomination",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "単語",
        "pronunciation": "たんご",
        "back": "word; vocabulary",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "男子",
        "pronunciation": "だんし",
        "back": "young man",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "単純",
        "pronunciation": "たんじゅん",
        "back": "simplicity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "誕生",
        "pronunciation": "たんじょう",
        "back": "birth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ダンス",
        "pronunciation": "ダンス",
        "back": "dance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "団体",
        "pronunciation": "だんたい",
        "back": "organization, association",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "担当",
        "pronunciation": "たんとう",
        "back": "(in) charge",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "単なる",
        "pronunciation": "たんなる",
        "back": "mere, simple, sheer",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "単に",
        "pronunciation": "たんに",
        "back": "simply, merely",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "地",
        "pronunciation": "ち",
        "back": "earth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "地位",
        "pronunciation": "ちい",
        "back": "(social) position, status",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "地域",
        "pronunciation": "ちいき",
        "back": "area, region",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "チーズ",
        "pronunciation": "チーズ",
        "back": "cheese",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "チーム",
        "pronunciation": "チーム",
        "back": "team",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "知恵",
        "pronunciation": "ちえ",
        "back": "wisdom, wit, intelligence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "地下",
        "pronunciation": "ちか",
        "back": "basement, underground",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "違い",
        "pronunciation": "ちがい",
        "back": "difference, discrepancy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "違いない",
        "pronunciation": "ちがいない",
        "back": "(phrase) sure, no mistaking it, for certain",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "近頃",
        "pronunciation": "ちかごろ",
        "back": "lately, recently, nowadays",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "地球",
        "pronunciation": "ちきゅう",
        "back": "the earth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "地区",
        "pronunciation": "ちく",
        "back": "district, section",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "遅刻",
        "pronunciation": "ちこく",
        "back": "lateness, late coming",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "知事",
        "pronunciation": "ちじ",
        "back": "prefectural governor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "知識",
        "pronunciation": "ちしき",
        "back": "knowledge, information",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "父親",
        "pronunciation": "ちちおや",
        "back": "father",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "知能",
        "pronunciation": "ちのう",
        "back": "intelligence, brains",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "地平線",
        "pronunciation": "ちへいせん",
        "back": "horizon",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "地方",
        "pronunciation": "ちほう",
        "back": "area, locality, region",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "茶",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃ",
        "back": "tea",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "チャンス",
        "pronunciation": "チャンス",
        "back": "chance, opportunity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちゃんと",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃんと",
        "back": "perfectly, properly, exactly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "中",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅう",
        "back": "inside, middle, among",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "注",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅう",
        "back": "annotation, explanatory note",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "中央",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうおう",
        "back": "central, center, middle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "中学",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうがく",
        "back": "middle school, junior high school",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "中古",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうこ",
        "back": "used, second-hand",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "中止",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうし",
        "back": "suspension, stoppage, discontinuance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "駐車",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうしゃ",
        "back": "parking (e.g., car)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "昼食",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうしょく",
        "back": "lunch (same as 昼ご飯 (ひるごはん))",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "中心",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうしん",
        "back": "center, core",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "注目",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうもく",
        "back": "notice, attention, observation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "注文",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうもん",
        "back": "order, request",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "長期",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうき",
        "back": "long time period",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "調査",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうさ",
        "back": "survey; investigation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "調子",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうし",
        "back": "condition, state, tune, tone",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "頂上",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうじょう",
        "back": "top, summit, peak",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちょうだい",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうだい",
        "back": "-- colloquial form of ください; typically used by children or women --",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "貯金",
        "pronunciation": "ちょきん",
        "back": "(bank) savings",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "直接",
        "pronunciation": "ちょくせつ",
        "back": "direct, immediate, firsthand",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "著者",
        "pronunciation": "ちょしゃ",
        "back": "author, writer",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "散らす",
        "pronunciation": "ちらす",
        "back": "to scatter, to disperse, to distribute",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "散る",
        "pronunciation": "ちる",
        "back": "to fall, to scatter (e.g., blossoms)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "遂に",
        "pronunciation": "ついに",
        "back": "finally, at last",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "通過",
        "pronunciation": "つうか",
        "back": "passage through, passing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "通貨",
        "pronunciation": "つうか",
        "back": "currency",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "通学",
        "pronunciation": "つうがく",
        "back": "commuting to school",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "通勤",
        "pronunciation": "つうきん",
        "back": "commuting to work",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "通行",
        "pronunciation": "つうこう",
        "back": "passage, passing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "通じる",
        "pronunciation": "つうじる",
        "back": "to run to, to lead to, to communicate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "通信",
        "pronunciation": "つうしん",
        "back": "correspondence, communications",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "通訳",
        "pronunciation": "つうやく",
        "back": "interpretation; interpreter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "捕まる",
        "pronunciation": "つかまる",
        "back": "to be arrested; to be caught",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "掴む",
        "pronunciation": "つかむ",
        "back": "to seize, to catch, to grasp",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "疲れ",
        "pronunciation": "つかれ",
        "back": "tiredness, fatigue",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "付き合い",
        "pronunciation": "つきあい",
        "back": "socialization; friendship; association",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "付合う",
        "pronunciation": "つきあう",
        "back": "to associate with, to keep company with, to get on with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "次々",
        "pronunciation": "つぎつぎ",
        "back": "in succession, one by one",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "付く",
        "pronunciation": "つく",
        "back": "to adjoin, to be attached, to adhere",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "就く",
        "pronunciation": "つく",
        "back": "to settle in (place), to take (seat position), to study (under teacher)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "突く",
        "pronunciation": "つく",
        "back": "to thrust, to strike; to poke",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "次ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "つぐ",
        "back": "to rank next to, to come after",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "注ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "つぐ",
        "back": "to pour (into)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "付ける",
        "pronunciation": "つける",
        "back": "to attach, to join, to add",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "着ける",
        "pronunciation": "つける",
        "back": "to put on, to wear; to draw up",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "伝わる",
        "pronunciation": "つたわる",
        "back": "to be handed down, to be transmitted",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "土",
        "pronunciation": "つち",
        "back": "earth, soil",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "続き",
        "pronunciation": "つづき",
        "back": "sequel, continuation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "包み",
        "pronunciation": "つつみ",
        "back": "bundle, package",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "勤め",
        "pronunciation": "つとめ",
        "back": "work, employment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "務め",
        "pronunciation": "つとめ",
        "back": "duty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "繋がる",
        "pronunciation": "つながる",
        "back": "to be connected to, to be related to",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "繋ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "つなぐ",
        "back": "to tie, to fasten, to connect",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "繋げる",
        "pronunciation": "つなげる",
        "back": "to connect",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "常に",
        "pronunciation": "つねに",
        "back": "always (same as いつも) (written expression)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "翼",
        "pronunciation": "つばさ",
        "back": "wings",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "つまり",
        "pronunciation": "つまり",
        "back": "namely; in other words; in short",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "罪",
        "pronunciation": "つみ",
        "back": "crime, fault, indiscretion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "積む",
        "pronunciation": "つむ",
        "back": "to pile up, to stack",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "詰める",
        "pronunciation": "つめる",
        "back": "to pack, to shorten, to work out (details)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "積もる",
        "pronunciation": "つもる",
        "back": "to pile up",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "梅雨",
        "pronunciation": "つゆ",
        "back": "rainy season",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "辛い",
        "pronunciation": "つらい",
        "back": "painful, heart-breaking",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "釣",
        "pronunciation": "つり",
        "back": "fishing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "連れ",
        "pronunciation": "つれ",
        "back": "companion, company",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "出",
        "pronunciation": "で",
        "back": "outflow, coming (going) out, graduate (of)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "出会い",
        "pronunciation": "であい",
        "back": "meeting, rendezvous, encounter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "出合い",
        "pronunciation": "であい",
        "back": "an encounter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "出会う",
        "pronunciation": "であう",
        "back": "to meet by chance, to come across, to happen to encounter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "提案",
        "pronunciation": "ていあん",
        "back": "proposal, proposition, suggestion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "定期",
        "pronunciation": "ていき",
        "back": "fixed term",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "抵抗",
        "pronunciation": "ていこう",
        "back": "resistance, opposition",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "提出",
        "pronunciation": "ていしゅつ",
        "back": "presentation, submission, filing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "停電",
        "pronunciation": "ていでん",
        "back": "failure of electricity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "程度",
        "pronunciation": "ていど",
        "back": "degree, amount, level",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "停留所",
        "pronunciation": "ていりゅうじょ",
        "back": "bus or tram stop",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "デート",
        "pronunciation": "デート",
        "back": "date (in the sense of 'social engagement' only)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "敵",
        "pronunciation": "てき",
        "back": "enemy, rival",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "出来事",
        "pronunciation": "できごと",
        "back": "incident happening, event",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "適する",
        "pronunciation": "てきする",
        "back": "to fit, to suit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "適切",
        "pronunciation": "てきせつ",
        "back": "appropriate, adequate, relevance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "適度",
        "pronunciation": "てきど",
        "back": "moderate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "適用",
        "pronunciation": "てきよう",
        "back": "applying",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "できれば",
        "pronunciation": "できれば",
        "back": "if possible…",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "手品",
        "pronunciation": "てじな",
        "back": "conjuring trick, magic",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ですから",
        "pronunciation": "ですから",
        "back": "therefore",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉄",
        "pronunciation": "てつ",
        "back": "iron",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "哲学",
        "pronunciation": "てつがく",
        "back": "philosophy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "手伝い",
        "pronunciation": "てつだい",
        "back": "help, helper, assistant",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "徹底",
        "pronunciation": "てってい",
        "back": "thoroughness, completeness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉄道",
        "pronunciation": "てつどう",
        "back": "railway; railroad",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "徹夜",
        "pronunciation": "てつや",
        "back": "staying up all night, sleepless night",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "手間",
        "pronunciation": "てま",
        "back": "time, labor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "デモ",
        "pronunciation": "デモ",
        "back": "demo, demonstration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "典型",
        "pronunciation": "てんけい",
        "back": "type, pattern, archetypal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "天候",
        "pronunciation": "てんこう",
        "back": "weather",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "電子",
        "pronunciation": "でんし",
        "back": "electron; electronic",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "テント",
        "pronunciation": "テント",
        "back": "tent",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "伝統",
        "pronunciation": "でんとう",
        "back": "tradition, convention",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "天然",
        "pronunciation": "てんねん",
        "back": "nature, spontaneity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "問い",
        "pronunciation": "とい",
        "back": "question, query",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "党",
        "pronunciation": "とう",
        "back": "party (political)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "塔",
        "pronunciation": "とう",
        "back": "tower, pagoda",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "答案",
        "pronunciation": "とうあん",
        "back": "examination paper, examination script",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "同一",
        "pronunciation": "どういつ",
        "back": "identity, sameness, similarity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "銅貨",
        "pronunciation": "どうか",
        "back": "copper coin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "当時",
        "pronunciation": "とうじ",
        "back": "at that time, in those days (same as そのころ)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "動詞",
        "pronunciation": "どうし",
        "back": "verb",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "同時",
        "pronunciation": "どうじ",
        "back": "simultaneous(ly), same time",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "どうしても",
        "pronunciation": "どうしても",
        "back": "at any cost, no matter what, no matter how hard one tries",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "どうぞよろしく",
        "pronunciation": "どうぞよろしく",
        "back": "pleased to meet you",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "到着",
        "pronunciation": "とうちゃく",
        "back": "arrival",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "道徳",
        "pronunciation": "どうとく",
        "back": "morals",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "投票",
        "pronunciation": "とうひょう",
        "back": "voting, poll",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "東洋",
        "pronunciation": "とうよう",
        "back": "Orient",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "同様",
        "pronunciation": "どうよう",
        "back": "identical, same (kind), like",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "童謡",
        "pronunciation": "どうよう",
        "back": "children's song, nursery rhyme",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "同僚",
        "pronunciation": "どうりょう",
        "back": "colleague; co-worker",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "道路",
        "pronunciation": "どうろ",
        "back": "road",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "通す",
        "pronunciation": "とおす",
        "back": "to let pass, to overlook, to continue",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "通り過ぎる",
        "pronunciation": "とおりすぎる",
        "back": "to pass, to pass through",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "都会",
        "pronunciation": "とかい",
        "back": "city",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "溶く",
        "pronunciation": "とく",
        "back": "to dissolve (paint)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "解く",
        "pronunciation": "とく",
        "back": "to unfasten; answer, solve",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "退く",
        "pronunciation": "どく",
        "back": "to retreat, to recede, to withdraw",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "毒",
        "pronunciation": "どく",
        "back": "poison, toxicant",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "得意",
        "pronunciation": "とくい",
        "back": "pride, triumph, prosperity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "読書",
        "pronunciation": "どくしょ",
        "back": "reading",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "独身",
        "pronunciation": "どくしん",
        "back": "single, unmarried",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "特徴",
        "pronunciation": "とくちょう",
        "back": "characteristic(s); feature(s); trait(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "特長",
        "pronunciation": "とくちょう",
        "back": "forte, merit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "独特",
        "pronunciation": "どくとく",
        "back": "peculiarity, uniqueness, characteristic",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "独立",
        "pronunciation": "どくりつ",
        "back": "independence (e.g., Ind. Day), self-support",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "溶ける",
        "pronunciation": "とける",
        "back": "to melt, to thaw, to dissolve",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "解ける",
        "pronunciation": "とける",
        "back": "to come untied, to come apart",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "どこか",
        "pronunciation": "どこか",
        "back": "somewhere, anywhere",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ところが",
        "pronunciation": "ところが",
        "back": "however, while, even if",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ところで",
        "pronunciation": "ところで",
        "back": "by the way; even if",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "登山",
        "pronunciation": "とざん",
        "back": "mountain-climbing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "都市",
        "pronunciation": "とし",
        "back": "town, city, urban",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "年月",
        "pronunciation": "としつき",
        "back": "months and years",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "図書",
        "pronunciation": "としょ",
        "back": "books",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "年寄",
        "pronunciation": "としより",
        "back": "old people, the aged",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "閉じる",
        "pronunciation": "とじる",
        "back": "to close (e.g., book, eyes), to shut",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "途端",
        "pronunciation": "とたん",
        "back": "just (now, at the moment, etc.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "土地",
        "pronunciation": "とち",
        "back": "plot of land, lot, soil",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "突然",
        "pronunciation": "とつぜん",
        "back": "abruptly, suddenly, unexpectedly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "トップ",
        "pronunciation": "トップ",
        "back": "top",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "届く",
        "pronunciation": "とどく",
        "back": "to reach",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "とにかく",
        "pronunciation": "とにかく",
        "back": "anyhow, at any rate, anyway",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "飛ばす",
        "pronunciation": "とばす",
        "back": "to skip over, to omit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "飛び出す",
        "pronunciation": "とびだす",
        "back": "to jump out, to rush out, to fly out",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "留める",
        "pronunciation": "とめる",
        "back": "to fasten, to turn off, to detain",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "泊める",
        "pronunciation": "とめる",
        "back": "to have someone stay (over night) (v.t.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "友",
        "pronunciation": "とも",
        "back": "friend, companion, pal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "共に",
        "pronunciation": "ともに",
        "back": "sharing with, participate in",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "虎",
        "pronunciation": "とら",
        "back": "tiger",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ドライブ",
        "pronunciation": "ドライブ",
        "back": "drive, driving",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "トラック",
        "pronunciation": "トラック",
        "back": "truck; (running) track",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ドラマ",
        "pronunciation": "ドラマ",
        "back": "drama",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "トランプ",
        "pronunciation": "トランプ",
        "back": "playing cards (lit: trump)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り上げる",
        "pronunciation": "とりあげる",
        "back": "to take up, to pick up; to confiscate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "努力",
        "pronunciation": "どりょく",
        "back": "great effort, exertion, endeavor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "トレーニング",
        "pronunciation": "トレーニング",
        "back": "training",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ドレス",
        "pronunciation": "ドレス",
        "back": "dress",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "取れる",
        "pronunciation": "とれる",
        "back": "to come off, to be taken off",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "泥",
        "pronunciation": "どろ",
        "back": "mud",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "トン",
        "pronunciation": "トン",
        "back": "ton (1000 lbs.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "とんでもない",
        "pronunciation": "とんでもない",
        "back": "outrageous, No way!",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "どんなに",
        "pronunciation": "どんなに",
        "back": "how, how much",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "トンネル",
        "pronunciation": "トンネル",
        "back": "tunnel",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "名",
        "pronunciation": "な",
        "back": "name, reputation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "内容",
        "pronunciation": "ないよう",
        "back": "subject, contents, detail",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "なお",
        "pronunciation": "なお",
        "back": "still, yet",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "仲",
        "pronunciation": "なか",
        "back": "relation, relationship",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "流す",
        "pronunciation": "ながす",
        "back": "to drain, to float, to shed (e.g., blood, tears)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "半ば",
        "pronunciation": "なかば",
        "back": "middle, halfway",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "仲間",
        "pronunciation": "なかま",
        "back": "company, fellow, colleague, associate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "中身",
        "pronunciation": "なかみ",
        "back": "content(s); substance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "中味",
        "pronunciation": "なかみ",
        "back": "contents, interior, filling",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "眺め",
        "pronunciation": "ながめ",
        "back": "scene; view; prospect; outlook",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "眺める",
        "pronunciation": "ながめる",
        "back": "to view, to gaze at",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "流れ",
        "pronunciation": "ながれ",
        "back": "stream, current",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "流れる",
        "pronunciation": "ながれる",
        "back": "to flow, to be washed away",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "亡くす",
        "pronunciation": "なくす",
        "back": "to lose someone",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "殴る",
        "pronunciation": "なぐる",
        "back": "to strike; to hit; to punch",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "無し",
        "pronunciation": "なし",
        "back": "without",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "なぜなら",
        "pronunciation": "なぜなら",
        "back": "because",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "謎",
        "pronunciation": "なぞ",
        "back": "riddle, puzzle, enigma",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "納得",
        "pronunciation": "なっとく",
        "back": "consent, assent, understanding",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "何か",
        "pronunciation": "なにか",
        "back": "something",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "なにも",
        "pronunciation": "なにも",
        "back": "nothing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "鍋",
        "pronunciation": "なべ",
        "back": "saucepan, pot",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生",
        "pronunciation": "なま",
        "back": "raw, unprocessed",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "怠ける",
        "pronunciation": "なまける",
        "back": "to be idle, to neglect",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "波",
        "pronunciation": "なみ",
        "back": "wave",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "涙",
        "pronunciation": "なみだ",
        "back": "tear",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "悩む",
        "pronunciation": "なやむ",
        "back": "to agonize, to be troubled",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "鳴らす",
        "pronunciation": "ならす",
        "back": "to ring, to sound",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "為る",
        "pronunciation": "なる",
        "back": "to change, to be of use, to reach to",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生る",
        "pronunciation": "なる",
        "back": "to bear fruit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "馴れる",
        "pronunciation": "なれる",
        "back": "to become domesticated, to become tame",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "縄",
        "pronunciation": "なわ",
        "back": "rope",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "何で",
        "pronunciation": "なんで",
        "back": "Why, What for",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "何でも",
        "pronunciation": "なんでも",
        "back": "by all means, everything",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "何とか",
        "pronunciation": "なんとか",
        "back": "somehow, anyhow, one way or another",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "似合う",
        "pronunciation": "にあう",
        "back": "to suit (a person), to match (clothing), (something) becomes (someone)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "煮える",
        "pronunciation": "にえる",
        "back": "to boil, to cook, to be cooked",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "苦手",
        "pronunciation": "にがて",
        "back": "poor (at), weak (in), dislike (of)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "握る",
        "pronunciation": "にぎる",
        "back": "to grasp, to seize, to mold sushi",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "日",
        "pronunciation": "にち",
        "back": "day",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "日常",
        "pronunciation": "にちじょう",
        "back": "ordinary, regular, everyday",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "日光",
        "pronunciation": "にっこう",
        "back": "sunlight",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "日中",
        "pronunciation": "にっちゅう",
        "back": "daytime, broad daylight",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "にっこり",
        "pronunciation": "にっこり",
        "back": "smile sweetly, smile, grin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "日本",
        "pronunciation": "にっぽん",
        "back": "Japan",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "日本",
        "pronunciation": "にほん",
        "back": "Japan",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "入場",
        "pronunciation": "にゅうじょう",
        "back": "entrance, admission, entering",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "煮る",
        "pronunciation": "にる",
        "back": "to boil, to cook",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "人気",
        "pronunciation": "にんき",
        "back": "popularity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "人間",
        "pronunciation": "にんげん",
        "back": "human being, person",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "抜く",
        "pronunciation": "ぬく",
        "back": "to extract, to omit, to unplug",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "抜ける",
        "pronunciation": "ぬける",
        "back": "to come out, to fall out, to be omitted",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "布",
        "pronunciation": "ぬの",
        "back": "cloth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "濡らす",
        "pronunciation": "ぬらす",
        "back": "to wet, to soak",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "根",
        "pronunciation": "ね",
        "back": "root",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "値",
        "pronunciation": "ね",
        "back": "value, price, cost",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "願い",
        "pronunciation": "ねがい",
        "back": "desire, wish, request",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "願う",
        "pronunciation": "ねがう",
        "back": "to desire, to wish, to request",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "鼠",
        "pronunciation": "ねずみ",
        "back": "mouse, rat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "熱帯",
        "pronunciation": "ねったい",
        "back": "tropics",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "熱中",
        "pronunciation": "ねっちゅう",
        "back": "enthusiasm, zeal, mania",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "年間",
        "pronunciation": "ねんかん",
        "back": "year",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "年月",
        "pronunciation": "ねんげつ",
        "back": "months and years",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "年中",
        "pronunciation": "ねんじゅう",
        "back": "whole year, always, everyday",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "年代",
        "pronunciation": "ねんだい",
        "back": "age, era, period",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "年齢",
        "pronunciation": "ねんれい",
        "back": "age, years",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "野",
        "pronunciation": "の",
        "back": "field",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "能",
        "pronunciation": "のう",
        "back": "being skilled in, nicely, properly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "農家",
        "pronunciation": "のうか",
        "back": "farmer, farm family",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "農業",
        "pronunciation": "のうぎょう",
        "back": "agriculture",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "農民",
        "pronunciation": "のうみん",
        "back": "farmers, peasants",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "能力",
        "pronunciation": "のうりょく",
        "back": "ability, faculty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ノー",
        "pronunciation": "ノー",
        "back": "no",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "軒",
        "pronunciation": "のき",
        "back": "eaves",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "残す",
        "pronunciation": "のこす",
        "back": "to leave (behind, over), to save, to reserve",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "残り",
        "pronunciation": "のこり",
        "back": "remaining, left-over",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "乗せる",
        "pronunciation": "のせる",
        "back": "to place on (something), to take on board",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "載せる",
        "pronunciation": "のせる",
        "back": "to place on (something); to publish",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "覗く",
        "pronunciation": "のぞく",
        "back": "to peek in, to look in",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "除く",
        "pronunciation": "のぞく",
        "back": "to remove, to exclude, to except",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "望み",
        "pronunciation": "のぞみ",
        "back": "wish, desire, (a) hope",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "望む",
        "pronunciation": "のぞむ",
        "back": "to desire, to wish for; to view",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "後",
        "pronunciation": "のち",
        "back": "afterwards, since then",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ノック",
        "pronunciation": "ノック",
        "back": "knock; fungo (baseball)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "伸ばす",
        "pronunciation": "のばす",
        "back": "to extend, to stretch, to reach out",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "延ばす",
        "pronunciation": "のばす",
        "back": "to extend, to stretch, to reach out",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "伸びる",
        "pronunciation": "のびる",
        "back": "to extend, to make progress, to grow",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "延びる",
        "pronunciation": "のびる",
        "back": "to be prolonged",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "述べる",
        "pronunciation": "のべる",
        "back": "to state, to express, to mention",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "上る",
        "pronunciation": "のぼる",
        "back": "to ascend, to go up, to climb",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "昇る",
        "pronunciation": "のぼる",
        "back": "to arise, to ascend, to go up",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "載る",
        "pronunciation": "のる",
        "back": "to appear (in print), to be recorded",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "のんびり",
        "pronunciation": "のんびり",
        "back": "carefree, at leisure",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "場",
        "pronunciation": "ば",
        "back": "place, field (physics)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "はあ (かん)",
        "pronunciation": "はあ (かん)",
        "back": "(sigh)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "パーセント",
        "pronunciation": "パーセント",
        "back": "percent",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "灰",
        "pronunciation": "はい",
        "back": "ash",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "梅雨",
        "pronunciation": "ばいう",
        "back": "rainy season",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "バイオリン",
        "pronunciation": "バイオリン",
        "back": "violin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ハイキング",
        "pronunciation": "ハイキング",
        "back": "hiking",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "配達",
        "pronunciation": "はいたつ",
        "back": "delivery, distribution",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "パイプ",
        "pronunciation": "パイプ",
        "back": "pipe; channels official or otherwise",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "俳優",
        "pronunciation": "はいゆう",
        "back": "actor, actress, performer",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "パイロット",
        "pronunciation": "パイロット",
        "back": "pilot",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生える",
        "pronunciation": "はえる",
        "back": "to grow, to spring up; to cut (teeth)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "墓",
        "pronunciation": "はか",
        "back": "grave, tomb",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "馬鹿",
        "pronunciation": "ばか",
        "back": "fool, idiot",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "博士",
        "pronunciation": "はかせ",
        "back": "doctorate, PhD., doctor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "計る",
        "pronunciation": "はかる",
        "back": "to measure, to weigh, to survey",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "量る",
        "pronunciation": "はかる",
        "back": "to measure, to weigh, to survey",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "測る",
        "pronunciation": "はかる",
        "back": "to measure, to weigh, to survey",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "掃く",
        "pronunciation": "はく",
        "back": "to sweep, to brush, to gather up",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "吐く",
        "pronunciation": "はく",
        "back": "to throw up, to vomit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "拍手",
        "pronunciation": "はくしゅ",
        "back": "clapping hands, applause",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "莫大",
        "pronunciation": "ばくだい",
        "back": "enormous, vast",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "爆発",
        "pronunciation": "ばくはつ",
        "back": "explosion, detonation, eruption",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "博物館",
        "pronunciation": "はくぶつかん",
        "back": "museum",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "激しい",
        "pronunciation": "はげしい",
        "back": "violent, vehement, intense",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "はさみ",
        "pronunciation": "はさみ",
        "back": "scissors",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "破産",
        "pronunciation": "はさん",
        "back": "(personal) bankruptcy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "端",
        "pronunciation": "はし",
        "back": "end (e.g., of street), edge, margin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "始まり",
        "pronunciation": "はじまり",
        "back": "origin, beginning",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "パス",
        "pronunciation": "パス",
        "back": "path, pass (in games)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "外す",
        "pronunciation": "はずす",
        "back": "to unfasten, to remove",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "パスポート",
        "pronunciation": "パスポート",
        "back": "passport",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "外れる",
        "pronunciation": "はずれる",
        "back": "to be disconnected, to be out (e.g., of gear)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "旗",
        "pronunciation": "はた",
        "back": "flag",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "肌",
        "pronunciation": "はだ",
        "back": "skin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "裸",
        "pronunciation": "はだか",
        "back": "naked, nude",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "畑",
        "pronunciation": "はたけ",
        "back": "field, patch",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "働き",
        "pronunciation": "はたらき",
        "back": "work, labor",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "バッグ",
        "pronunciation": "バッグ",
        "back": "bag",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "発見",
        "pronunciation": "はっけん",
        "back": "discovery, detection, finding",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "発行",
        "pronunciation": "はっこう",
        "back": "issue (publications)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "発車",
        "pronunciation": "はっしゃ",
        "back": "departure of a vehicle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "発射",
        "pronunciation": "はっしゃ",
        "back": "firing, shooting, discharge",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "罰する",
        "pronunciation": "ばっする",
        "back": "to punish, to penalize",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "発達",
        "pronunciation": "はったつ",
        "back": "development, growth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ばったり",
        "pronunciation": "ばったり",
        "back": "(to meet) by chance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "発展",
        "pronunciation": "はってん",
        "back": "development, growth, progress",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "発表",
        "pronunciation": "はっぴょう",
        "back": "announcement; publication; presentation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "発明",
        "pronunciation": "はつめい",
        "back": "invention",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "派手",
        "pronunciation": "はで",
        "back": "showy, flashy, gaudy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "話し合う",
        "pronunciation": "はなしあう",
        "back": "to discuss, to talk together",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "離す",
        "pronunciation": "はなす",
        "back": "to part, to separate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "放す",
        "pronunciation": "はなす",
        "back": "to separate, to set free",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "離れる",
        "pronunciation": "はなれる",
        "back": "(something, someone) separates; parts from; to be apart",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "放れる",
        "pronunciation": "はなれる",
        "back": "to leave, to get free, to cut oneself off",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "羽",
        "pronunciation": "はね",
        "back": "wing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "羽根",
        "pronunciation": "はね",
        "back": "feather",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "幅",
        "pronunciation": "はば",
        "back": "width, breadth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "母親",
        "pronunciation": "ははおや",
        "back": "mother",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "省く",
        "pronunciation": "はぶく",
        "back": "to omit, to eliminate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "場面",
        "pronunciation": "ばめん",
        "back": "scene, setting (e.g., of novel)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "流行る",
        "pronunciation": "はやる",
        "back": "to be popular, to come into fashion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "腹",
        "pronunciation": "はら",
        "back": "abdomen, belly, stomach",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "原",
        "pronunciation": "はら",
        "back": "field, plain",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "バランス",
        "pronunciation": "バランス",
        "back": "balance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "針",
        "pronunciation": "はり",
        "back": "needle, hand (e.g., clock)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "範囲",
        "pronunciation": "はんい",
        "back": "extent, scope, range",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "反抗",
        "pronunciation": "はんこう",
        "back": "opposition, resistance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "犯罪",
        "pronunciation": "はんざい",
        "back": "crime",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ハンサム",
        "pronunciation": "ハンサム",
        "back": "handsome",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "反省",
        "pronunciation": "はんせい",
        "back": "reflection, reconsideration, regret",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "判断",
        "pronunciation": "はんだん",
        "back": "judgment, decision",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "犯人",
        "pronunciation": "はんにん",
        "back": "offender, criminal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "販売",
        "pronunciation": "はんばい",
        "back": "sale, selling, marketing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "灯",
        "pronunciation": "ひ",
        "back": "light",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ビール",
        "pronunciation": "ビール",
        "back": "beer",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "被害",
        "pronunciation": "ひがい",
        "back": "damage",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "比較",
        "pronunciation": "ひかく",
        "back": "comparison",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ピクニック",
        "pronunciation": "ピクニック",
        "back": "picnic",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "悲劇",
        "pronunciation": "ひげき",
        "back": "tragedy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "飛行",
        "pronunciation": "ひこう",
        "back": "aviation, flight",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "膝",
        "pronunciation": "ひざ",
        "back": "knee, lap",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "非常",
        "pronunciation": "ひじょう",
        "back": "emergency, extraordinary, unusual",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "美人",
        "pronunciation": "びじん",
        "back": "beautiful person (woman)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "額",
        "pronunciation": "ひたい",
        "back": "forehead, brow",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "日付",
        "pronunciation": "ひづけ",
        "back": "date, dating",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "引越し",
        "pronunciation": "ひっこし",
        "back": "moving, changing residence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "必死",
        "pronunciation": "ひっし",
        "back": "desperation, frantic, inevitable result",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぴったり",
        "pronunciation": "ぴったり",
        "back": "exactly, neatly, sharp",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "引っ張る",
        "pronunciation": "ひっぱる",
        "back": "to pull, to stretch, to drag",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "否定",
        "pronunciation": "ひてい",
        "back": "negation, denial",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ビデオ",
        "pronunciation": "ビデオ",
        "back": "video tape; VCR",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一言",
        "pronunciation": "ひとこと",
        "back": "one word",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "人込み",
        "pronunciation": "ひとごみ",
        "back": "crowd of people",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "等しい",
        "pronunciation": "ひとしい",
        "back": "equal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "独り",
        "pronunciation": "ひとり",
        "back": "alone, unmarried",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "一人一人",
        "pronunciation": "ひとりひとり",
        "back": "one by one, each",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "批判",
        "pronunciation": "ひはん",
        "back": "criticism",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "批評",
        "pronunciation": "ひひょう",
        "back": "criticism, review, commentary",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "秘密",
        "pronunciation": "ひみつ",
        "back": "secret, secrecy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "微妙",
        "pronunciation": "びみょう",
        "back": "delicate, subtle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "紐",
        "pronunciation": "ひも",
        "back": "string, cord",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷やす",
        "pronunciation": "ひやす",
        "back": "to cool, to refrigerate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "費用",
        "pronunciation": "ひよう",
        "back": "cost, expense",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "表",
        "pronunciation": "ひょう",
        "back": "table (e.g., Tab 1), chart, list",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "秒",
        "pronunciation": "びょう",
        "back": "second (60th min)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "評価",
        "pronunciation": "ひょうか",
        "back": "assessment, evaluation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "表現",
        "pronunciation": "ひょうげん",
        "back": "expression, presentation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "表情",
        "pronunciation": "ひょうじょう",
        "back": "facial expression",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "平等",
        "pronunciation": "びょうどう",
        "back": "equality, impartiality, evenness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "評判",
        "pronunciation": "ひょうばん",
        "back": "fame, reputation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "表面",
        "pronunciation": "ひょうめん",
        "back": "surface, outside, face",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "広がる",
        "pronunciation": "ひろがる",
        "back": "to spread (out), to extend, to stretch, to reach to, to get around",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "広げる",
        "pronunciation": "ひろげる",
        "back": "to spread, to extend, to expand, to enlarge",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "広める",
        "pronunciation": "ひろめる",
        "back": "to broaden, to propagate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "品",
        "pronunciation": "ひん",
        "back": "goods; taste, elegance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "瓶",
        "pronunciation": "びん",
        "back": "bottle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "便",
        "pronunciation": "びん",
        "back": "way, means; flight",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ピン",
        "pronunciation": "ピン",
        "back": "pin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不",
        "pronunciation": "ふ",
        "back": "un(~), non(~), negative prefix",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不",
        "pronunciation": "ぶ",
        "back": "un(~), non(~), negative prefix",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "無",
        "pronunciation": "ぶ",
        "back": "nothing, naught, nil, zero",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "分",
        "pronunciation": "ぶ",
        "back": "dividing, part",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不安",
        "pronunciation": "ふあん",
        "back": "anxiety, uneasiness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "風景",
        "pronunciation": "ふうけい",
        "back": "scenery",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "夫婦",
        "pronunciation": "ふうふ",
        "back": "married couple, husband and wife",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "笛",
        "pronunciation": "ふえ",
        "back": "flute, whistle",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不可",
        "pronunciation": "ふか",
        "back": "wrong, bad, impossible",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "深まる",
        "pronunciation": "ふかまる",
        "back": "to deepen",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "武器",
        "pronunciation": "ぶき",
        "back": "weapon, arms",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "拭く",
        "pronunciation": "ふく",
        "back": "to wipe, to dry",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "服装",
        "pronunciation": "ふくそう",
        "back": "clothes, attire",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "含む",
        "pronunciation": "ふくむ",
        "back": "to contain, to include",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "含める",
        "pronunciation": "ふくめる",
        "back": "to include",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "袋",
        "pronunciation": "ふくろ",
        "back": "bag, sack",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不幸",
        "pronunciation": "ふこう",
        "back": "unhappiness, sorrow, misfortune",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "節",
        "pronunciation": "ふし",
        "back": "tune, tone, knob",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "無事",
        "pronunciation": "ぶじ",
        "back": "safety, peace",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不思議",
        "pronunciation": "ふしぎ",
        "back": "mystery, curiosity",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不自由",
        "pronunciation": "ふじゆう",
        "back": "discomfort, disability, inconvenience",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "夫人",
        "pronunciation": "ふじん",
        "back": "wife, Mrs, madam",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "婦人",
        "pronunciation": "ふじん",
        "back": "woman (same as 女性 (じょせい)、女の人 (おんなのひと))",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不正",
        "pronunciation": "ふせい",
        "back": "injustice, unfairness",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "防ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "ふせぐ",
        "back": "to defend (against), to protect, to prevent",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不足",
        "pronunciation": "ふそく",
        "back": "insufficiency, shortage",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "舞台",
        "pronunciation": "ぶたい",
        "back": "stage (theater)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "双子",
        "pronunciation": "ふたご",
        "back": "twins, a twin",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "再び",
        "pronunciation": "ふたたび",
        "back": "again, once more, a second time",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "普段",
        "pronunciation": "ふだん",
        "back": "in everyday situations, usually, ordinarily",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "縁",
        "pronunciation": "ふち",
        "back": "edge, rim",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "打つ",
        "pronunciation": "ぶつ",
        "back": "to hit, to strike",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不通",
        "pronunciation": "ふつう",
        "back": "blockade, interruption, stoppage",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "物価",
        "pronunciation": "ぶっか",
        "back": "(commodity/consumer) prices",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぶつかる",
        "pronunciation": "ぶつかる",
        "back": "to strike, to collide with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぶつける",
        "pronunciation": "ぶつける",
        "back": "to knock, to strike hard, to hit and attack",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "物質",
        "pronunciation": "ぶっしつ",
        "back": "material, substance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "物理",
        "pronunciation": "ぶつり",
        "back": "physics",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "筆",
        "pronunciation": "ふで",
        "back": "writing brush",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ふと",
        "pronunciation": "ふと",
        "back": "suddenly, accidentally, incidentally",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "部分",
        "pronunciation": "ぶぶん",
        "back": "portion, section, part",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不平",
        "pronunciation": "ふへい",
        "back": "complaint, discontent, dissatisfaction",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不満",
        "pronunciation": "ふまん",
        "back": "dissatisfaction, discontent, complaints",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "増やす",
        "pronunciation": "ふやす",
        "back": "to increase (v.t.), to add to",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "殖やす",
        "pronunciation": "ふやす",
        "back": "to increase, to add to",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "プラス",
        "pronunciation": "プラス",
        "back": "plus",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "プラスチック",
        "pronunciation": "プラスチック",
        "back": "plastic",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "プラン",
        "pronunciation": "プラン",
        "back": "plan",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "不利",
        "pronunciation": "ふり",
        "back": "disadvantage, drawback",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "振る",
        "pronunciation": "ふる",
        "back": "to wave, to shake; to sprinkle; to cast (actor)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "震える",
        "pronunciation": "ふるえる",
        "back": "to shiver, to shake, to quake",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ブレーキ",
        "pronunciation": "ブレーキ",
        "back": "a brake",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "触れる",
        "pronunciation": "ふれる",
        "back": "to touch, to feel, to violate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "プロ",
        "pronunciation": "プロ",
        "back": "professional",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "分",
        "pronunciation": "ぶん",
        "back": "dividing, part, segment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "文",
        "pronunciation": "ぶん",
        "back": "sentence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "雰囲気",
        "pronunciation": "ふんいき",
        "back": "atmosphere (e.g., musical), mood, ambiance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "分析",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんせき",
        "back": "analysis",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "文明",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんめい",
        "back": "civilization",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "分野",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんや",
        "back": "field, sphere",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "塀",
        "pronunciation": "へい",
        "back": "wall, fence",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "平均",
        "pronunciation": "へいきん",
        "back": "equilibrium, balance, average",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "平和",
        "pronunciation": "へいわ",
        "back": "peace",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "別に",
        "pronunciation": "べつに",
        "back": "(not) particularly, nothing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "減らす",
        "pronunciation": "へらす",
        "back": "to decrease, to diminish",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "減る",
        "pronunciation": "へる",
        "back": "to decrease (in size or number), to diminish",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ベルト",
        "pronunciation": "ベルト",
        "back": "Belt for western clothes",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "変化",
        "pronunciation": "へんか",
        "back": "change, variation, shift",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ペンキ",
        "pronunciation": "ペンキ",
        "back": "paint",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "変更",
        "pronunciation": "へんこう",
        "back": "change, modification, alteration",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ベンチ",
        "pronunciation": "ベンチ",
        "back": "bench",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "弁当",
        "pronunciation": "べんとう",
        "back": "box lunch",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "方",
        "pronunciation": "ほう",
        "back": "side",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "法",
        "pronunciation": "ほう",
        "back": "Act (law: the X Act)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "棒",
        "pronunciation": "ぼう",
        "back": "pole, rod, stick",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "冒険",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうけん",
        "back": "risk, venture, adventure",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "方向",
        "pronunciation": "ほうこう",
        "back": "direction, course, way",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "報告",
        "pronunciation": "ほうこく",
        "back": "report, information",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "宝石",
        "pronunciation": "ほうせき",
        "back": "gem, jewel",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "包装",
        "pronunciation": "ほうそう",
        "back": "packing, wrapping",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "豊富",
        "pronunciation": "ほうふ",
        "back": "abundance, plenty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "方法",
        "pronunciation": "ほうほう",
        "back": "method, means, technique",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "方々",
        "pronunciation": "ほうぼう",
        "back": "here and there, everywhere",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "訪問",
        "pronunciation": "ほうもん",
        "back": "call, visit",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "吠える",
        "pronunciation": "ほえる",
        "back": "to bark, to howl",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ボーイ",
        "pronunciation": "ボーイ",
        "back": "porter; boy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ボート",
        "pronunciation": "ボート",
        "back": "rowing boat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ホーム",
        "pronunciation": "ホーム",
        "back": "platform; home",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ボール",
        "pronunciation": "ボール",
        "back": "ball; bowl",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "他",
        "pronunciation": "ほか",
        "back": "other (esp. places and things)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "誇り",
        "pronunciation": "ほこり",
        "back": "pride",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "埃",
        "pronunciation": "ほこり",
        "back": "dust",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "保証",
        "pronunciation": "ほしょう",
        "back": "guarantee, assurance, warranty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "保存",
        "pronunciation": "ほぞん",
        "back": "preservation, conservation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "歩道",
        "pronunciation": "ほどう",
        "back": "walkway",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "仏",
        "pronunciation": "ほとけ",
        "back": "Buddha",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "骨",
        "pronunciation": "ほね",
        "back": "bone",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "炎",
        "pronunciation": "ほのお",
        "back": "flame",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "頬",
        "pronunciation": "ほほ",
        "back": "cheek (of face)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "頬",
        "pronunciation": "ほお",
        "back": "cheek (of face)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ほぼ",
        "pronunciation": "ほぼ",
        "back": "almost, roughly",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "微笑む",
        "pronunciation": "ほほえむ",
        "back": "to smile",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "堀",
        "pronunciation": "ほり",
        "back": "moat, canal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "濠",
        "pronunciation": "ほり",
        "back": "moat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "本当",
        "pronunciation": "ほんと",
        "back": "truth, reality",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "本人",
        "pronunciation": "ほんにん",
        "back": "the person himself",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "本物",
        "pronunciation": "ほんもの",
        "back": "genuine article",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぼんやり",
        "pronunciation": "ぼんやり",
        "back": "dim, faint, vague",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "間",
        "pronunciation": "ま",
        "back": "space, room, pause",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "まあ",
        "pronunciation": "まあ",
        "back": "well (used when making a modest or hesitant statement)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "マーケット",
        "pronunciation": "マーケット",
        "back": "market",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "マイク",
        "pronunciation": "マイク",
        "back": "mic",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "迷子",
        "pronunciation": "まいご",
        "back": "lost (stray) child",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "マイナス",
        "pronunciation": "マイナス",
        "back": "minus",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "任せる",
        "pronunciation": "まかせる",
        "back": "to entrust to another, to leave to",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "巻く",
        "pronunciation": "まく",
        "back": "to wind, to coil, to roll",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "蒔く",
        "pronunciation": "まく",
        "back": "to sow (seeds)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "撒く",
        "pronunciation": "まく",
        "back": "to scatter, to sprinkle, to sow",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "幕",
        "pronunciation": "まく",
        "back": "curtain, act (in play)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "負け",
        "pronunciation": "まけ",
        "back": "defeat, loss",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "孫",
        "pronunciation": "まご",
        "back": "grandchild",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "まさか",
        "pronunciation": "まさか",
        "back": "by no means",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "まさに",
        "pronunciation": "まさに",
        "back": "correctly, surely",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "混ざる",
        "pronunciation": "まざる",
        "back": "to be mixed, to mingle with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "交ざる",
        "pronunciation": "まざる",
        "back": "to be mixed, to mingle with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "混じる",
        "pronunciation": "まじる",
        "back": "to be mixed, to mingle with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "交じる",
        "pronunciation": "まじる",
        "back": "to be mixed, to mingle with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "増す",
        "pronunciation": "ます",
        "back": "to increase, to gain",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "貧しい",
        "pronunciation": "まずしい",
        "back": "poor, needy",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "マスター",
        "pronunciation": "マスター",
        "back": "bar owner, master (e.g., arts, science)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ますます",
        "pronunciation": "ますます",
        "back": "increasingly (same as もっと), more and more",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "混ぜる",
        "pronunciation": "まぜる",
        "back": "to mix, to stir",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "交ぜる",
        "pronunciation": "まぜる",
        "back": "to be mixed, to be blended with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "街",
        "pronunciation": "まち",
        "back": "town; street, road",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "間違い",
        "pronunciation": "まちがい",
        "back": "mistake",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "松",
        "pronunciation": "まつ",
        "back": "pine tree",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "真っ赤",
        "pronunciation": "まっか",
        "back": "deep red, flushed (of face)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "全く",
        "pronunciation": "まったく",
        "back": "really, completely",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "祭",
        "pronunciation": "まつり",
        "back": "festival, feast",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "まとまる",
        "pronunciation": "まとまる",
        "back": "to be collected, to be settled, to be in order",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "まとめる",
        "pronunciation": "まとめる",
        "back": "to put in order, to collect, to bring to a conclusion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "学ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "まなぶ",
        "back": "to learn; to study",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "真似",
        "pronunciation": "まね",
        "back": "mimicry, imitation, behavior",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "招く",
        "pronunciation": "まねく",
        "back": "to invite",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "まぶしい",
        "pronunciation": "まぶしい",
        "back": "dazzling, radiant",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "柵",
        "pronunciation": "さく",
        "back": "fence, paling",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "裂ける",
        "pronunciation": "さける",
        "back": "to split, to tear, to burst",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "裁く",
        "pronunciation": "さばく",
        "back": "to judge",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "酸化",
        "pronunciation": "さんか",
        "back": "oxidation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "死",
        "pronunciation": "し",
        "back": "death, decease",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "資格",
        "pronunciation": "しかく",
        "back": "qualifications, requirements, capabilities",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "視覚",
        "pronunciation": "しかく",
        "back": "sense of sight, vision",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "指揮",
        "pronunciation": "しき",
        "back": "command, direction",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "磁気",
        "pronunciation": "じき",
        "back": "magnetism",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "磁器",
        "pronunciation": "じき",
        "back": "porcelain, china",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "自己",
        "pronunciation": "じこ",
        "back": "self, oneself",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "字体",
        "pronunciation": "じたい",
        "back": "font, lettering",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "辞退",
        "pronunciation": "じたい",
        "back": "refusal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "視点",
        "pronunciation": "してん",
        "back": "opinion, point of view, visual point",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "脂肪",
        "pronunciation": "しぼう",
        "back": "fat, grease",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "志望",
        "pronunciation": "しぼう",
        "back": "wish, desire, ambition",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "衆",
        "pronunciation": "しゅう",
        "back": "masses, people",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "住",
        "pronunciation": "じゅう",
        "back": "dwelling, living",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "修飾",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうしょく",
        "back": "ornamentation; modification (gram)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "私用",
        "pronunciation": "しよう",
        "back": "personal use, private business",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕様",
        "pronunciation": "しよう",
        "back": "way, method, specification",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "情",
        "pronunciation": "じょう",
        "back": "feelings, emotion, passion",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生涯",
        "pronunciation": "しょうがい",
        "back": "one's lifetime",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "上司",
        "pronunciation": "じょうし",
        "back": "one's superior",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "正体",
        "pronunciation": "しょうたい",
        "back": "natural shape, one's true colors, true character",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "照明",
        "pronunciation": "しょうめい",
        "back": "illumination",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "女史",
        "pronunciation": "じょし",
        "back": "Ms.",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "助詞",
        "pronunciation": "じょし",
        "back": "(gram) particle(s), postposition",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ショック",
        "pronunciation": "ショック",
        "back": "shock",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "進行",
        "pronunciation": "しんこう",
        "back": "advance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "新興",
        "pronunciation": "しんこう",
        "back": "rising, developing, emergent",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "振興",
        "pronunciation": "しんこう",
        "back": "promotion, encouragement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "申告",
        "pronunciation": "しんこく",
        "back": "report, statement",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "真理",
        "pronunciation": "しんり",
        "back": "truth",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "水洗",
        "pronunciation": "すいせん",
        "back": "flushing",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ストレス",
        "pronunciation": "ストレス",
        "back": "stress",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "擦る",
        "pronunciation": "する",
        "back": "to rub, to chafe",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "正規",
        "pronunciation": "せいき",
        "back": "regular, legitimate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "精巧",
        "pronunciation": "せいこう",
        "back": "elaborate, delicate, exquisite",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "精算",
        "pronunciation": "せいさん",
        "back": "exact calculation, adjustment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "成年",
        "pronunciation": "せいねん",
        "back": "majority, adult age",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "声明",
        "pronunciation": "せいめい",
        "back": "declaration, statement, proclamation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "姓名",
        "pronunciation": "せいめい",
        "back": "full name",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生理",
        "pronunciation": "せいり",
        "back": "physiology, menses",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "節",
        "pronunciation": "せつ",
        "back": "when, if; section; clause",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "膳",
        "pronunciation": "ぜん",
        "back": "(small) table, tray, meal",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "禅",
        "pronunciation": "ぜん",
        "back": "Zen (Buddhism)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "選挙",
        "pronunciation": "せんきょ",
        "back": "election",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "先行",
        "pronunciation": "せんこう",
        "back": "preceding, going first",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "選考",
        "pronunciation": "せんこう",
        "back": "selection, screening",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "相",
        "pronunciation": "そう",
        "back": "aspect, phase, countenance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "沿う",
        "pronunciation": "そう",
        "back": "to run along, to follow",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "添う",
        "pronunciation": "そう",
        "back": "to accompany, to comply with",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "僧",
        "pronunciation": "そう",
        "back": "monk, priest",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "像",
        "pronunciation": "ぞう",
        "back": "statue, image",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "捜査",
        "pronunciation": "そうさ",
        "back": "search (esp. in criminal investigations, investigation)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "操縦",
        "pronunciation": "そうじゅう",
        "back": "management, control, manipulation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "創造",
        "pronunciation": "そうぞう",
        "back": "creation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "隊",
        "pronunciation": "たい",
        "back": "party, troops",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "退学",
        "pronunciation": "たいがく",
        "back": "dropping out of school",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "タイトル",
        "pronunciation": "タイトル",
        "back": "title",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ダウン",
        "pronunciation": "ダウン",
        "back": "down",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "高まる",
        "pronunciation": "たかまる",
        "back": "to rise; to grow; to mount (v.i.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "断つ",
        "pronunciation": "たつ",
        "back": "to sever, to cut off",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "盾",
        "pronunciation": "たて",
        "back": "shield",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "例え",
        "pronunciation": "たとえ",
        "back": "example; even though",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "チャイム",
        "pronunciation": "チャイム",
        "back": "chime",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "挑戦",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうせん",
        "back": "challenge, defiance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "治療",
        "pronunciation": "ちりょう",
        "back": "medical treatment",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "対",
        "pronunciation": "つい",
        "back": "pair, couple, set",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "接ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "つぐ",
        "back": "to join; to piece together; to set (bones); to graft (trees)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "継ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "つぐ",
        "back": "to succeed (someone in a business or inheritance",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "摘む",
        "pronunciation": "つむ",
        "back": "to pluck, to pick, to trim",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "露",
        "pronunciation": "つゆ",
        "back": "dew",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "強まる",
        "pronunciation": "つよまる",
        "back": "to get strong, to gain strength",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "強める",
        "pronunciation": "つよめる",
        "back": "to strengthen, to emphasize",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "データ",
        "pronunciation": "データ",
        "back": "data",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "デザイン",
        "pronunciation": "デザイン",
        "back": "design",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "デザート",
        "pronunciation": "デザート",
        "back": "dessert",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "転校",
        "pronunciation": "てんこう",
        "back": "change schools",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "伝言",
        "pronunciation": "でんごん",
        "back": "verbal message",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "と",
        "pronunciation": "と",
        "back": "and",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "問う",
        "pronunciation": "とう",
        "back": "to ask, to question",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "棟",
        "pronunciation": "とう",
        "back": "ridge (of roof",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "倒産",
        "pronunciation": "とうさん",
        "back": "(corporate) bankruptcy, insolvency",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "同士",
        "pronunciation": "どうし",
        "back": "one another, companion, comrade",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "同志",
        "pronunciation": "どうし",
        "back": "same mind, comrade, kindred soul",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "当然",
        "pronunciation": "とうぜん",
        "back": "obvious; natural",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "動揺",
        "pronunciation": "どうよう",
        "back": "disturbance, flutter shock",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "説く",
        "pronunciation": "とく",
        "back": "to explain, to advocate",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "綴じる",
        "pronunciation": "とじる",
        "back": "to bind, to file",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "供",
        "pronunciation": "とも",
        "back": "accompanying, attendant, companion, retinue",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "並",
        "pronunciation": "なみ",
        "back": "medium (e.g., food serving size, quality, price, etc.), ordinary",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "慣らす",
        "pronunciation": "ならす",
        "back": "to accustom",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "馴らす",
        "pronunciation": "ならす",
        "back": "to domesticate, to tame",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "難",
        "pronunciation": "なん",
        "back": "difficulty, hardships, defect",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "音",
        "pronunciation": "ね",
        "back": "sound, note",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "年鑑",
        "pronunciation": "ねんかん",
        "back": "yearbook",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "脳",
        "pronunciation": "のう",
        "back": "brain, memory",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "臨む",
        "pronunciation": "のぞむ",
        "back": "to look out on, to face, to attend (function)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "肺",
        "pronunciation": "はい",
        "back": "lung",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "～敗",
        "pronunciation": "はい",
        "back": "counter for loss, defeat",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "映える",
        "pronunciation": "はえる",
        "back": "to shine, to look attractive, to look pretty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "諮る",
        "pronunciation": "はかる",
        "back": "to consult with, to confer",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "図る",
        "pronunciation": "はかる",
        "back": "to plot, to attempt, to devise, to design, to refer A to B",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "生やす",
        "pronunciation": "はやす",
        "back": "to grow, to cultivate, to wear beard",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "班",
        "pronunciation": "はん",
        "back": "group, party, section (mil)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "判",
        "pronunciation": "はん",
        "back": "size (of paper or books)",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "版",
        "pronunciation": "はん",
        "back": "edition",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "碑",
        "pronunciation": "ひ",
        "back": "stone monument bearing an inscription",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "非行",
        "pronunciation": "ひこう",
        "back": "delinquency, misconduct",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "票",
        "pronunciation": "ひょう",
        "back": "label, ballot, sign",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "広まる",
        "pronunciation": "ひろまる",
        "back": "to spread, to be propagated",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "深める",
        "pronunciation": "ふかめる",
        "back": "to deepen, to heighten, to intensify",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "福",
        "pronunciation": "ふく",
        "back": "good fortune",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "振り",
        "pronunciation": "ふり",
        "back": "style, manner",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "経る",
        "pronunciation": "へる",
        "back": "to pass, to elapse, to experience",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "保護",
        "pronunciation": "ほご",
        "back": "care, protection, shelter",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "保障",
        "pronunciation": "ほしょう",
        "back": "guarantee, security, warranty",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "補償",
        "pronunciation": "ほしょう",
        "back": "compensation, reparation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ほっと",
        "pronunciation": "ほっと",
        "back": "feel relieved",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "前もって",
        "pronunciation": "まえもって",
        "back": "in advance, beforehand, previously",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "膜",
        "pronunciation": "まく",
        "back": "membrane, film",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "マスコミ",
        "pronunciation": "マスコミ",
        "back": "mass communication",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "股",
        "pronunciation": "また",
        "back": "thigh, crotch",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "末",
        "pronunciation": "まつ",
        "back": "the end of",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "マッサージ",
        "pronunciation": "マッサージ",
        "back": "massage",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "見掛ける",
        "pronunciation": "みかける",
        "back": "to (happen to see), to notice, to catch sight of",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "捲る",
        "pronunciation": "めくる",
        "back": "to turn over, to turn pages of a book",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "メッセージ",
        "pronunciation": "メッセージ",
        "back": "message",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "野党",
        "pronunciation": "やとう",
        "back": "opposition party",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "優",
        "pronunciation": "ゆう",
        "back": "superiority, high grade",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "有機",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうき",
        "back": "organic",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "世",
        "pronunciation": "よ",
        "back": "world, society, generation",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "良い",
        "pronunciation": "よい",
        "back": "good, nice",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "予想",
        "pronunciation": "よそう",
        "back": "expectation, anticipation, prediction",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "弱まる",
        "pronunciation": "よわまる",
        "back": "to weaken, to be emaciated, to be dejected",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "弱める",
        "pronunciation": "よわめる",
        "back": "to weaken",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ラベル",
        "pronunciation": "ラベル",
        "back": "label",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "ルール",
        "pronunciation": "ルール",
        "back": "rule",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "枠",
        "pronunciation": "わく",
        "back": "frame, slide",
        "JLPT Level": "N3",
        "collection_id": "9"
    },
    {
        "front": "踏む",
        "pronunciation": "ふむ",
        "back": "to step on, to tread on",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～区",
        "pronunciation": "～く",
        "back": "~ district, ~ ward, ~ borough",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "すっと",
        "pronunciation": "すっと",
        "back": "straight, quickly",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "盗む",
        "pronunciation": "ぬすむ",
        "back": "to steal; to rob",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "大抵",
        "pronunciation": "たいてい",
        "back": "generally, usually",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "とうとう",
        "pronunciation": "とうとう",
        "back": "finally, at last",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ガソリン",
        "pronunciation": "ガソリン",
        "back": "gasoline, petrol",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "鳴る",
        "pronunciation": "なる",
        "back": "to sound, to ring (v.i.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "しっかり",
        "pronunciation": "しっかり",
        "back": "firmly, steady",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "生きる",
        "pronunciation": "いきる",
        "back": "to live",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "苦い",
        "pronunciation": "にがい",
        "back": "bitter",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "沸く",
        "pronunciation": "わく",
        "back": "to boil, to grow hot",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "意見",
        "pronunciation": "いけん",
        "back": "opinion, view, idea",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "やはり; やっぱり",
        "pronunciation": "やはり; やっぱり",
        "back": "as I thought, absolutely",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "漫画",
        "pronunciation": "まんが",
        "back": "comic (book), cartoon",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ステレオ",
        "pronunciation": "ステレオ",
        "back": "stereo",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "医学",
        "pronunciation": "いがく",
        "back": "medical science",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "テキスト",
        "pronunciation": "テキスト",
        "back": "text; text book",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～月",
        "pronunciation": "～つき",
        "back": "month",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "折る",
        "pronunciation": "おる",
        "back": "to snap, to break; to bend",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～会",
        "pronunciation": "～かい",
        "back": "~ meeting",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "うかがう",
        "pronunciation": "うかがう",
        "back": "to ask",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "聞こえる",
        "pronunciation": "きこえる",
        "back": "to be heard, to be audible",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "僕",
        "pronunciation": "ぼく",
        "back": "I (used by men towards those of equal or lower status)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "必ず",
        "pronunciation": "かならず",
        "back": "surely, certainly",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "壊す",
        "pronunciation": "こわす",
        "back": "to break, to break down",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "怒る",
        "pronunciation": "おこる",
        "back": "to get angry; to scold angrily",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "床屋",
        "pronunciation": "とこや",
        "back": "barber's (shop)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "オートバイ",
        "pronunciation": "オートバイ",
        "back": "motorcycle (lit: auto-bi(ke))",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "運動",
        "pronunciation": "うんどうする",
        "back": "exercise",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "止む",
        "pronunciation": "やむ",
        "back": "to cease, to stop",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "もし",
        "pronunciation": "もし",
        "back": "if",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "表",
        "pronunciation": "おもて",
        "back": "surface; front; outside",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "大学生",
        "pronunciation": "だいがくせい",
        "back": "college student, university student",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "運転手",
        "pronunciation": "うんてんしゅ",
        "back": "driver (by occupation)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "予習",
        "pronunciation": "よしゅう",
        "back": "preparation of lessons (for class)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "心配",
        "pronunciation": "しんぱいする",
        "back": "worry, concern",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "別",
        "pronunciation": "べつ",
        "back": "distinction, different",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "非常に",
        "pronunciation": "ひじょうに",
        "back": "extremely; very",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "お宅",
        "pronunciation": "おたく",
        "back": "(someone else's) house; home -- polite word for 家 (いえ) --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "柔らかい",
        "pronunciation": "やわらかい",
        "back": "soft (in reference to texture), tender",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "拾う",
        "pronunciation": "ひろう",
        "back": "to pick up (something), to find",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～ございます",
        "pronunciation": "～ございます",
        "back": "to be (polite), to exist",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "気",
        "pronunciation": "き",
        "back": "spirit, mood",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "比べる",
        "pronunciation": "くらべる",
        "back": "to compare",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ほとんど",
        "pronunciation": "ほとんど",
        "back": "mostly, almost",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "つもり",
        "pronunciation": "つもり",
        "back": "intention, plan",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "郊外",
        "pronunciation": "こうがい",
        "back": "suburb, outskirts",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "だめ",
        "pronunciation": "だめ",
        "back": "useless, no good, hopeless",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "売り場",
        "pronunciation": "うりば",
        "back": "place where things are sold",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "正月",
        "pronunciation": "しょうがつ",
        "back": "New Year, New Year's Day",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "規則",
        "pronunciation": "きそく",
        "back": "rule, regulation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "うん",
        "pronunciation": "うん",
        "back": "yes (informal), all right (ok)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "発音",
        "pronunciation": "はつおん",
        "back": "pronunciation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "焼く",
        "pronunciation": "やく",
        "back": "to bake, to grill",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "屋上",
        "pronunciation": "おくじょう",
        "back": "rooftop",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "失礼",
        "pronunciation": "しつれい",
        "back": "discourtesy, impoliteness; Excuse me",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ごみ",
        "pronunciation": "ごみ",
        "back": "trash, garbage",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "アフリカ",
        "pronunciation": "アフリカ",
        "back": "Africa",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "点",
        "pronunciation": "てん",
        "back": "mark, score, grade; point, dot",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "一生懸命",
        "pronunciation": "いっしょうけんめい",
        "back": "very hard (as in \"to work hard\"), with utmost effort",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "今度",
        "pronunciation": "こんど",
        "back": "now, this time, near future, one of these days, next time",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "機会",
        "pronunciation": "きかい",
        "back": "chance, opportunity",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "建てる",
        "pronunciation": "たてる",
        "back": "to build",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "複雑",
        "pronunciation": "ふくざつ",
        "back": "complexity, complication",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "彼",
        "pronunciation": "かれ",
        "back": "he, boyfriend",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "いらっしゃる",
        "pronunciation": "いらっしゃる",
        "back": "-- honorific expression for いく, くる, and いる --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "布団",
        "pronunciation": "ふとん",
        "back": "futon",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "大事",
        "pronunciation": "だいじ",
        "back": "important, valuable, serious matter",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "贈り物",
        "pronunciation": "おくりもの",
        "back": "a gift; a present",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "泥棒",
        "pronunciation": "どろぼう",
        "back": "thief; burglar",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～製",
        "pronunciation": "～せい",
        "back": "made in ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "注意",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうい",
        "back": "caution, attention",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "台風",
        "pronunciation": "たいふう",
        "back": "typhoon",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "日",
        "pronunciation": "ひ",
        "back": "sun, sunshine, day",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～軒",
        "pronunciation": "～けん",
        "back": "counter for houses",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "そう",
        "pronunciation": "そう",
        "back": "really, (is that) so; yes, right",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "通る",
        "pronunciation": "とおる",
        "back": "to pass (by), to go through",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "過ぎる",
        "pronunciation": "すぎる",
        "back": "to exceed, to go beyond",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "レポート; リポート",
        "pronunciation": "レポート; リポート",
        "back": "report",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "葉",
        "pronunciation": "は",
        "back": "leaf",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "必要",
        "pronunciation": "ひつよう",
        "back": "necessary",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "課長",
        "pronunciation": "かちょう",
        "back": "section manager",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "地震",
        "pronunciation": "じしん",
        "back": "earthquake",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "すると",
        "pronunciation": "すると",
        "back": "and, then",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "止める",
        "pronunciation": "やめる",
        "back": "to end, to stop",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ガラス",
        "pronunciation": "ガラス",
        "back": "glass, pane",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～学部",
        "pronunciation": "～がくぶ",
        "back": "department of a university",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "厳しい",
        "pronunciation": "きびしい",
        "back": "hard; rigorous; strict",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "エスカレーター",
        "pronunciation": "エスカレーター",
        "back": "escalator",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "人口",
        "pronunciation": "じんこう",
        "back": "population",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "月",
        "pronunciation": "つき",
        "back": "moon",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "絹",
        "pronunciation": "きぬ",
        "back": "silk",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちっとも",
        "pronunciation": "ちっとも",
        "back": "not at all (neg. verb)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "深い",
        "pronunciation": "ふかい",
        "back": "deep, profound",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "壊れる",
        "pronunciation": "こわれる",
        "back": "to be broken, to break",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "揺れる",
        "pronunciation": "ゆれる",
        "back": "to shake, to sway",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "落る",
        "pronunciation": "おちる",
        "back": "to fall, to drop",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "できるだけ",
        "pronunciation": "できるだけ",
        "back": "if at all possible, as much as possible",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "悲しい",
        "pronunciation": "かなしい",
        "back": "sad, sorrowful",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "中学校",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうがっこう",
        "back": "junior high school pupil",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ガス",
        "pronunciation": "ガス",
        "back": "gas",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "祈る",
        "pronunciation": "いのる",
        "back": "to pray; to wish",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "盛ん",
        "pronunciation": "さかん",
        "back": "prosperous, active, thriving",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "アルバイト",
        "pronunciation": "アルバイト",
        "back": "part-time job",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "起こす",
        "pronunciation": "おこす",
        "back": "to wake (someone) up",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "致す",
        "pronunciation": "いたす",
        "back": "-- extra-modest expression for する --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "噛む",
        "pronunciation": "かむ",
        "back": "to bite, to chew",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "赤ちゃん",
        "pronunciation": "あかちゃん",
        "back": "baby, infant",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "浅い",
        "pronunciation": "あさい",
        "back": "shallow, superficial",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "嘘",
        "pronunciation": "うそ",
        "back": "lie",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "小説",
        "pronunciation": "しょうせつ",
        "back": "novel",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "親",
        "pronunciation": "おや",
        "back": "a parent",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "それに",
        "pronunciation": "それに",
        "back": "moreover; besides",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "西洋",
        "pronunciation": "せいよう",
        "back": "the West, Western countries",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "思う",
        "pronunciation": "おもう",
        "back": "to think, to feel",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "パート (タイム)",
        "pronunciation": "パート (タイム)",
        "back": "part time (esp. female part time employees)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "時代",
        "pronunciation": "じだい",
        "back": "age, period, epoch, era",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "申し上げる",
        "pronunciation": "もうしあげる",
        "back": "(humble)to say, to tell",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～式",
        "pronunciation": "～しき",
        "back": "~ ceremony; ~ style",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "出席",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっせきする",
        "back": "attendance",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～家",
        "pronunciation": "～か",
        "back": "person who is specialized in ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "迎える",
        "pronunciation": "むかえる",
        "back": "to welcome; to meet; to greet",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "触る",
        "pronunciation": "さわる",
        "back": "to touch, to feel",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "建て",
        "pronunciation": "～だて",
        "back": "~ storied, separate housing",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "社長",
        "pronunciation": "しゃちょう",
        "back": "president of a company",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "動物園",
        "pronunciation": "どうぶつえん",
        "back": "zoo",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "捕まえる",
        "pronunciation": "つかまえる",
        "back": "to catch, to arrest",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "季節",
        "pronunciation": "きせつ",
        "back": "season (in reference to weather)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "寄る",
        "pronunciation": "よる",
        "back": "to stop by",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "決まる",
        "pronunciation": "きまる",
        "back": "to be set; fixed (v.i.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "開く",
        "pronunciation": "ひらく",
        "back": "to open; to hold (an event)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "逃げる",
        "pronunciation": "にげる",
        "back": "to escape, to run away",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "だから",
        "pronunciation": "だから",
        "back": "so; therefore",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "残念",
        "pronunciation": "ざんねん",
        "back": "regret; regrettable",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "畳",
        "pronunciation": "たたみ",
        "back": "tatami mat (Japanese straw mat)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "丁寧",
        "pronunciation": "ていねい",
        "back": "polite, courteous, careful",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "地理",
        "pronunciation": "ちり",
        "back": "geography",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "さっき",
        "pronunciation": "さっき",
        "back": "a little while ago",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "怖い",
        "pronunciation": "こわい",
        "back": "scary, frightening",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "包む",
        "pronunciation": "つつむ",
        "back": "to wrap, to cover",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "なるべく",
        "pronunciation": "なるべく",
        "back": "if possible, as much as possible",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "無理",
        "pronunciation": "むり",
        "back": "unreasonable, impossible",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "サンドイッチ",
        "pronunciation": "サンドイッチ",
        "back": "sandwich",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "会議室",
        "pronunciation": "かいぎしつ",
        "back": "conference room",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "品物",
        "pronunciation": "しなもの",
        "back": "goods",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "人形",
        "pronunciation": "にんぎょう",
        "back": "doll, figure",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "利用",
        "pronunciation": "りよう",
        "back": "use, utilization",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "飾る",
        "pronunciation": "かざる",
        "back": "to decorate, to adorn",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "止める",
        "pronunciation": "とめる",
        "back": "to stop (something)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "恥ずかしい",
        "pronunciation": "はずかしい",
        "back": "ashamed, embarrassed",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "いくら～ても",
        "pronunciation": "いくら～ても",
        "back": "however much one may ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "用事",
        "pronunciation": "ようじ",
        "back": "business to take care of; tasks; errands",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ビル",
        "pronunciation": "ビル",
        "back": "(abbr.) building",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "けんかする",
        "pronunciation": "けんかする",
        "back": "quarrel",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "頑張る",
        "pronunciation": "がんばる",
        "back": "to try one's best, to try hard, to persist",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "投げる",
        "pronunciation": "なげる",
        "back": "to pitch, to cast away",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "故障",
        "pronunciation": "こしょうする",
        "back": "breakdown",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "力",
        "pronunciation": "ちから",
        "back": "strength, power",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "受ける",
        "pronunciation": "うける",
        "back": "to take (an examination, interview, etc.); to receive",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "気分",
        "pronunciation": "きぶん",
        "back": "feeling, mood",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "間違える",
        "pronunciation": "まちがえる",
        "back": "to make a mistake",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "そんな",
        "pronunciation": "そんな",
        "back": "such, like that, that sort of",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "星",
        "pronunciation": "ほし",
        "back": "star",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "場合",
        "pronunciation": "ばあい",
        "back": "case, situation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "やっと",
        "pronunciation": "やっと",
        "back": "at last, finally",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "足りる",
        "pronunciation": "たりる",
        "back": "to be sufficient; to be enough",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "行う",
        "pronunciation": "おこなう",
        "back": "to carry out; to conduct (typically used in written language)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぶどう",
        "pronunciation": "ぶどう",
        "back": "grapes",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "無くなる",
        "pronunciation": "なくなる",
        "back": "to disappear, to get lost",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "準備",
        "pronunciation": "じゅんびする",
        "back": "prepare",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "世界",
        "pronunciation": "せかい",
        "back": "world",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "住所",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうしょ",
        "back": "address; place of residence",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "再来月",
        "pronunciation": "さらいげつ",
        "back": "the month after next",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "林",
        "pronunciation": "はやし",
        "back": "woods, forest",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "倍",
        "pronunciation": "ばい",
        "back": "double",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "痩せる",
        "pronunciation": "やせる",
        "back": "to lose weight",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "線",
        "pronunciation": "せん",
        "back": "line, wire",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "戦争",
        "pronunciation": "せんそう",
        "back": "war",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "決める",
        "pronunciation": "きめる",
        "back": "to decide (v.t.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "調べる",
        "pronunciation": "しらべる",
        "back": "to check; to look up; to inquire; to search",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "寝坊",
        "pronunciation": "ねぼう",
        "back": "sleeping in late",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "パパ",
        "pronunciation": "パパ",
        "back": "papa, daddy",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "光る",
        "pronunciation": "ひかる",
        "back": "to shine, to glitter",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "夫",
        "pronunciation": "おっと",
        "back": "husband",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "雲",
        "pronunciation": "くも",
        "back": "cloud",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "坂",
        "pronunciation": "さか",
        "back": "slope, hill",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～(て) しまう",
        "pronunciation": "～(て) しまう",
        "back": "to end up ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "飛行場",
        "pronunciation": "ひこうじょう",
        "back": "airport",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "柔道",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうどう",
        "back": "judo",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "決して",
        "pronunciation": "けっして",
        "back": "never",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "事務所",
        "pronunciation": "じむしょ",
        "back": "office",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "連絡",
        "pronunciation": "れんらく",
        "back": "communication, contact, connection",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "小学校",
        "pronunciation": "しょうがっこう",
        "back": "elementary school",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "客",
        "pronunciation": "きゃく",
        "back": "guest, customer",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "昔",
        "pronunciation": "むかし",
        "back": "old days; past",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "美しい",
        "pronunciation": "うつくしい",
        "back": "beautiful, lovely",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "捨てる",
        "pronunciation": "すてる",
        "back": "throw away (trash), dump, discard",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "なさる",
        "pronunciation": "なさる",
        "back": "-- honorific expression for する --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "事",
        "pronunciation": "こと",
        "back": "thing(s), matter(s), fact",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "どんどん",
        "pronunciation": "どんどん",
        "back": "quickly and steadily; at a rapid pace",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "試合",
        "pronunciation": "しあい",
        "back": "match, game, competition",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "適当",
        "pronunciation": "てきとう",
        "back": "fitness, suitability",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "素晴らしい",
        "pronunciation": "すばらしい",
        "back": "wonderful; terrific",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "美術館",
        "pronunciation": "びじゅつかん",
        "back": "art gallery, art museum",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "文法",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんぽう",
        "back": "grammar",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "終わり",
        "pronunciation": "おわり",
        "back": "end",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "壁",
        "pronunciation": "かべ",
        "back": "wall",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "一度",
        "pronunciation": "いちど",
        "back": "once, one time",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "お礼",
        "pronunciation": "おれい",
        "back": "expression of gratitude; thanking; gift of appreciation; bow",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "親切",
        "pronunciation": "しんせつ",
        "back": "kindness",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "知らせる",
        "pronunciation": "しらせる",
        "back": "to notify",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "歯医者",
        "pronunciation": "はいしゃ",
        "back": "dentist",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "熱心",
        "pronunciation": "ねっしん",
        "back": "enthusiasm",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "始める",
        "pronunciation": "はじめる",
        "back": "to start, to begin",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "もらう",
        "pronunciation": "もらう",
        "back": "to receive",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "泣く",
        "pronunciation": "なく",
        "back": "to cry",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "治る",
        "pronunciation": "なおる",
        "back": "to get better; to recover from illness (v.i.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "熱",
        "pronunciation": "ねつ",
        "back": "fever, temperature",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "お祭り",
        "pronunciation": "おまつり",
        "back": "festival",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "水道",
        "pronunciation": "すいどう",
        "back": "water service, water line",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "匂い",
        "pronunciation": "におい",
        "back": "odor, smell",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ベル",
        "pronunciation": "ベル",
        "back": "bell",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "赤ん坊",
        "pronunciation": "あかんぼう",
        "back": "baby",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "おかしい",
        "pronunciation": "おかしい",
        "back": "strange; odd; funny",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "事故",
        "pronunciation": "じこ",
        "back": "accident",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "変",
        "pronunciation": "へん",
        "back": "strange, odd",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "辞典",
        "pronunciation": "じてん",
        "back": "encyclopedia, reference book",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "残る",
        "pronunciation": "のこる",
        "back": "to remain (v.i.), to be left",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "立てる",
        "pronunciation": "たてる",
        "back": "to stand (something) up, to erect (something)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "くれる",
        "pronunciation": "くれる",
        "back": "to give, to do for",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～員",
        "pronunciation": "～いん",
        "back": "member of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "原因",
        "pronunciation": "げんいん",
        "back": "cause, origin, source",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "驚く",
        "pronunciation": "おどろく",
        "back": "to be surprised, to be astonished",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "いただく",
        "pronunciation": "頂く",
        "back": "-- extra-modest expression for たべる and のむ; humble expression for もらう --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "祖母",
        "pronunciation": "そぼ",
        "back": "grandmother",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "場所",
        "pronunciation": "ばしょ",
        "back": "place, location",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "答",
        "pronunciation": "こたえ",
        "back": "answer, response",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "もちろん",
        "pronunciation": "もちろん",
        "back": "certainly, of course",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "漬ける",
        "pronunciation": "つける",
        "back": "to soak, to moisten, to pickle",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "受付",
        "pronunciation": "うけつけ",
        "back": "reception(ist) desk",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "内",
        "pronunciation": "うち",
        "back": "within, inside",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "スクリーン",
        "pronunciation": "スクリーン",
        "back": "screen",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "増える",
        "pronunciation": "ふえる",
        "back": "to increase, to multiply",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "または",
        "pronunciation": "または",
        "back": "or, otherwise",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "けがする",
        "pronunciation": "けがする",
        "back": "injury (to animate object), hurt",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "以下",
        "pronunciation": "いか",
        "back": "less than, below",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "選ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "えらぶ",
        "back": "to choose; to select",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～ばかり",
        "pronunciation": "～ばかり",
        "back": "just did ~, only",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "心",
        "pronunciation": "こころ",
        "back": "heart, mind",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～だす",
        "pronunciation": "～だす",
        "back": "to start doing ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "サラダ",
        "pronunciation": "サラダ",
        "back": "salad",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "届ける",
        "pronunciation": "とどける",
        "back": "to deliver (v.t.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "挨拶",
        "pronunciation": "あいさつする",
        "back": "greet(ing)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "景色",
        "pronunciation": "けしき",
        "back": "scenery, landscape",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "確か",
        "pronunciation": "たしか",
        "back": "if I remember correctly; certain, definite",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ステーキ",
        "pronunciation": "ステーキ",
        "back": "steak",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "食料品",
        "pronunciation": "しょくりょうひん",
        "back": "foodstuff, groceries",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "森",
        "pronunciation": "もり",
        "back": "forest",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "以内",
        "pronunciation": "いない",
        "back": "within, less (no more) than",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "予定",
        "pronunciation": "よてい",
        "back": "plans, arrangement, schedule",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "オーバー",
        "pronunciation": "オーバー",
        "back": "overcoat; over, exceeding, exaggeration",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "乾く",
        "pronunciation": "かわく",
        "back": "to get dry",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "石",
        "pronunciation": "いし",
        "back": "stone",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "思い出す",
        "pronunciation": "おもいだす",
        "back": "to recall, to remember",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "踊る",
        "pronunciation": "おどる",
        "back": "to dance",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "細かい",
        "pronunciation": "こまかい",
        "back": "small; fine, minute",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "塗る",
        "pronunciation": "ぬる",
        "back": "to paint, to plaster",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ご主人",
        "pronunciation": "ごしゅじん",
        "back": "(your, her) husband",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "珍しい",
        "pronunciation": "めずらしい",
        "back": "unusual, rare",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "用",
        "pronunciation": "よう",
        "back": "errand, task, business (to take care of)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "公務員",
        "pronunciation": "こうむいん",
        "back": "government worker, public servant",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "お嬢さん",
        "pronunciation": "おじょうさん",
        "back": "(someone's) daughter (polite)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "用意",
        "pronunciation": "ようい",
        "back": "preparation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "探す",
        "pronunciation": "さがす",
        "back": "to search, to seek, to look for",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "形",
        "pronunciation": "かたち",
        "back": "shape",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "運転",
        "pronunciation": "うんてんする",
        "back": "driving",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "すっかり",
        "pronunciation": "すっかり",
        "back": "all, completely",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "アナウンサー",
        "pronunciation": "アナウンサー",
        "back": "announcer",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "お土産",
        "pronunciation": "おみやげ",
        "back": "souvenir",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "消しゴム",
        "pronunciation": "けしゴム",
        "back": "eraser",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "旅館",
        "pronunciation": "りょかん",
        "back": "a Japanese inn",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "海岸",
        "pronunciation": "かいがん",
        "back": "coast, seashore",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "寂しい",
        "pronunciation": "さびしい",
        "back": "lonely, lonesome",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "火",
        "pronunciation": "ひ",
        "back": "fire",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "育てる",
        "pronunciation": "そだてる",
        "back": "to raise (v.t.); to bring up",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "味噌",
        "pronunciation": "みそ",
        "back": "miso, bean paste",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "お祝い",
        "pronunciation": "おいわい",
        "back": "congratulation, celebration",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "乗り物",
        "pronunciation": "のりもの",
        "back": "vehicle",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "案内",
        "pronunciation": "あんないする",
        "back": "information, guidance",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "通う",
        "pronunciation": "かよう",
        "back": "to go back and forth; to commute",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "連れる",
        "pronunciation": "つれる",
        "back": "to lead, to take (a person)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "技術",
        "pronunciation": "ぎじゅつ",
        "back": "technique, technology, skill",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "小鳥",
        "pronunciation": "ことり",
        "back": "small bird",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "下宿",
        "pronunciation": "げしゅく",
        "back": "lodging, boarding house",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ジャム",
        "pronunciation": "ジャム",
        "back": "jam",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "招待",
        "pronunciation": "しょうたいする",
        "back": "invitation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "鏡",
        "pronunciation": "かがみ",
        "back": "mirror",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "はず",
        "pronunciation": "はず",
        "back": "it should be so",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "法律",
        "pronunciation": "ほうりつ",
        "back": "law",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "進む",
        "pronunciation": "すすむ",
        "back": "to advance, to proceed",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "楽む",
        "pronunciation": "たのしむ",
        "back": "to enjoy",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "貿易",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうえき",
        "back": "trade",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "反対",
        "pronunciation": "はんたい",
        "back": "oppose, opposition, resistance",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "おる",
        "pronunciation": "おる",
        "back": "-- extra-modest expression for いる --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "申す",
        "pronunciation": "もうす",
        "back": "-- extra-modest (humble) expression for 言う (いう) --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "試験",
        "pronunciation": "しけん",
        "back": "an exam",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "真面目",
        "pronunciation": "まじめ",
        "back": "diligent, serious",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ごらんになる",
        "pronunciation": "",
        "back": "-- honorific expression for みる --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "店員",
        "pronunciation": "てんいん",
        "back": "clerk; shop-employee",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "泊まる",
        "pronunciation": "とまる",
        "back": "to stay (over night) (v.i.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "よろしい",
        "pronunciation": "よろしい",
        "back": "(hon.) good, OK, all right",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "今夜",
        "pronunciation": "こんや",
        "back": "this evening, tonight",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "おつり",
        "pronunciation": "おつり",
        "back": "change; balance of money returned to the purchaser",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "チェックする",
        "pronunciation": "チェックする",
        "back": "check",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "会話",
        "pronunciation": "かいわ",
        "back": "conversation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "空気",
        "pronunciation": "くうき",
        "back": "air, atmosphere",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "交通",
        "pronunciation": "こうつう",
        "back": "traffic, transportation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ワープロ",
        "pronunciation": "ワープロ",
        "back": "word processor",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "喜ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "よろこぶ",
        "back": "to rejoice, to be delighted, to be glad",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "急行",
        "pronunciation": "きゅうこう",
        "back": "express train or bus",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "皆",
        "pronunciation": "みな",
        "back": "everyone",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "味",
        "pronunciation": "あじ",
        "back": "flavor, taste",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "空港",
        "pronunciation": "くうこう",
        "back": "airport",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "手袋",
        "pronunciation": "てぶくろ",
        "back": "glove(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "校長",
        "pronunciation": "こうちょう",
        "back": "principal, headmaster",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ごちそう",
        "pronunciation": "ごちそう",
        "back": "feast, treating (someone)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "踊り",
        "pronunciation": "おどり",
        "back": "dance",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "興味",
        "pronunciation": "きょうみ",
        "back": "interest (in something)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "引っ越す",
        "pronunciation": "ひっこす",
        "back": "to move to a new place of residence",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷房",
        "pronunciation": "れいぼう",
        "back": "cooling, air conditioning",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "都合",
        "pronunciation": "つごう",
        "back": "circumstances, convenience",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "遠慮",
        "pronunciation": "えんりょする",
        "back": "restraint, reserve, hesitate",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "亡くなる",
        "pronunciation": "なくなる",
        "back": "to pass away",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "科学",
        "pronunciation": "かがく",
        "back": "science",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "はっきり",
        "pronunciation": "はっきり",
        "back": "clearly, distinctly",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "差し上げる",
        "pronunciation": "さしあげる",
        "back": "-- humble expression for あげる --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "気持ち",
        "pronunciation": "きもち",
        "back": "feeling, sensation, mood",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "祖父",
        "pronunciation": "そふ",
        "back": "grandfather",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "港",
        "pronunciation": "みなと",
        "back": "harbor, port",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "予約",
        "pronunciation": "よやく",
        "back": "reservation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "凄い",
        "pronunciation": "すごい",
        "back": "terrific, great",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "入学",
        "pronunciation": "にゅうがくする",
        "back": "entry to school or university",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "片付ける",
        "pronunciation": "かたづける",
        "back": "to (clean) tidy up (v.t.), to put away",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "写す",
        "pronunciation": "うつす",
        "back": "to copy (v.t.); to photograph",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "パソコン",
        "pronunciation": "パソコン",
        "back": "(personal) computer",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "部長",
        "pronunciation": "ぶちょう",
        "back": "department (division) manager",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "火事",
        "pronunciation": "かじ",
        "back": "fire",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "足す",
        "pronunciation": "たす",
        "back": "to add (numbers)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "教会",
        "pronunciation": "きょうかい",
        "back": "church",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "彼ら",
        "pronunciation": "かれら",
        "back": "they (usually male)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "一杯",
        "pronunciation": "いっぱい",
        "back": "full, to the utmost",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "アメリカ",
        "pronunciation": "アメリカ",
        "back": "America, U.S.A.",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "男性",
        "pronunciation": "だんせい",
        "back": "man; male",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "理由",
        "pronunciation": "りゆう",
        "back": "reason",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "生産",
        "pronunciation": "せいさんする",
        "back": "production; to produce",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "着物",
        "pronunciation": "きもの",
        "back": "kimono; Japanese traditional dress",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "おもちゃ",
        "pronunciation": "おもちゃ",
        "back": "a toy",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "暮れる",
        "pronunciation": "くれる",
        "back": "to get dark, to come to an end",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "釣る",
        "pronunciation": "つる",
        "back": "to fish",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～ちゃん",
        "pronunciation": "～ちゃん",
        "back": "suffix for familiar (female) person",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "打つ",
        "pronunciation": "うつ",
        "back": "to hit, to strike",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "あんな",
        "pronunciation": "あんな",
        "back": "such, like that",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "謝る",
        "pronunciation": "あやまる",
        "back": "to apologize",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "昼間",
        "pronunciation": "ひるま",
        "back": "daytime, during the day",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "教育",
        "pronunciation": "きょういく",
        "back": "education",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "女性",
        "pronunciation": "じょせい",
        "back": "woman",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "米",
        "pronunciation": "こめ",
        "back": "uncooked rice",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "邪魔",
        "pronunciation": "じゃま",
        "back": "hindrance, intrusion",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "国際",
        "pronunciation": "こくさい",
        "back": "international",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "隅",
        "pronunciation": "すみ",
        "back": "corner",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "伺う",
        "pronunciation": "うかがう",
        "back": "humble form of 行く (いく), 聞く (きく) and 来る (くる)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "再来週",
        "pronunciation": "さらいしゅう",
        "back": "the week after next",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "夢",
        "pronunciation": "ゆめ",
        "back": "a dream",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "喉",
        "pronunciation": "のど",
        "back": "throat",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "最近",
        "pronunciation": "さいきん",
        "back": "recently, nowadays, in recent years, most recent, latest",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "周り",
        "pronunciation": "まわり",
        "back": "surroundings",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "歴史",
        "pronunciation": "れきし",
        "back": "history",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "不便",
        "pronunciation": "ふべん",
        "back": "inconvenience",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "血",
        "pronunciation": "ち",
        "back": "blood",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～続ける",
        "pronunciation": "～つづける",
        "back": "to continue doing ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "毛",
        "pronunciation": "け",
        "back": "hair, fur",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ひどい",
        "pronunciation": "ひどい",
        "back": "terrible, awful, unfair, cruel",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "例えば",
        "pronunciation": "たとえば",
        "back": "for example, e.g.",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "中々",
        "pronunciation": "なかなか",
        "back": "very, considerably, quite",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "随分",
        "pronunciation": "ずいぶん",
        "back": "extremely",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～やすい",
        "pronunciation": "～やすい",
        "back": "easy to do ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "押し入れ",
        "pronunciation": "おしいれ",
        "back": "closet",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "電灯",
        "pronunciation": "でんとう",
        "back": "electric light",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "叱る",
        "pronunciation": "しかる",
        "back": "to scold",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "サンダル",
        "pronunciation": "サンダル",
        "back": "sandal",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "びっくりする",
        "pronunciation": "びっくりする",
        "back": "to be surprised",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "うまい",
        "pronunciation": "うまい",
        "back": "delicious; skillful; fortunate",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "変える",
        "pronunciation": "かえる",
        "back": "to change, to alter, to vary",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "講堂",
        "pronunciation": "こうどう",
        "back": "auditorium",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "子",
        "pronunciation": "こ",
        "back": "child",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "沸かす",
        "pronunciation": "わかす",
        "back": "to boil",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "レジ",
        "pronunciation": "レジ",
        "back": "register",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "しばらく",
        "pronunciation": "しばらく",
        "back": "little while",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "特に",
        "pronunciation": "とくに",
        "back": "particularly",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "空く",
        "pronunciation": "あく",
        "back": "to open, to become empty (vacant)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "計画",
        "pronunciation": "けいかくする",
        "back": "plan, project, schedule",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "通り",
        "pronunciation": "とおり",
        "back": "~ Street, ~ Avenue",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "下着",
        "pronunciation": "したぎ",
        "back": "underwear",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "経済",
        "pronunciation": "けいざい",
        "back": "economics, finance, economy",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "こう",
        "pronunciation": "こう",
        "back": "like this, this way",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "是非",
        "pronunciation": "ぜひ",
        "back": "certainly, by all means; without fail",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "裏",
        "pronunciation": "うら",
        "back": "reverse side, back",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "為",
        "pronunciation": "ため",
        "back": "good, advantage, in order to",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "おいでになる",
        "pronunciation": "おいでになる",
        "back": "(hon.) to be",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "変わる",
        "pronunciation": "かわる",
        "back": "to change (v.i.), to be transformed, to vary",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "以外",
        "pronunciation": "いがい",
        "back": "other than, with the exception of, excepting",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "済む",
        "pronunciation": "すむ",
        "back": "to finish, to end",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ハンバーグ",
        "pronunciation": "ハンバーグ",
        "back": "hamburger steak",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "市",
        "pronunciation": "し",
        "back": "city",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "引き出し",
        "pronunciation": "ひきだし",
        "back": "drawer",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "遊び",
        "pronunciation": "あそび",
        "back": "play",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "支度",
        "pronunciation": "したくする",
        "back": "preparation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～始める",
        "pronunciation": "～はじめる",
        "back": "to start doing ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "見える",
        "pronunciation": "みえる",
        "back": "to be visible; -- polite verb meaning 来る (くる) --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "十分",
        "pronunciation": "じゅうぶん",
        "back": "enough",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "音",
        "pronunciation": "おと",
        "back": "sound, note",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "きっと",
        "pronunciation": "きっと",
        "back": "surely, definitely, undoubtedly, certainly",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "まず",
        "pronunciation": "まず",
        "back": "first (of all), to start with",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "遠く",
        "pronunciation": "とおく",
        "back": "far away, distant",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "大体",
        "pronunciation": "だいたい",
        "back": "approximately; in most cases; in general; to begin with (same as もともと)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "折れる",
        "pronunciation": "おれる",
        "back": "to break, to be folded, to give in; to turn (a corner)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "正しい",
        "pronunciation": "ただしい",
        "back": "correct",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "輸入",
        "pronunciation": "ゆにゅう",
        "back": "import",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "返事",
        "pronunciation": "へんじ",
        "back": "reply, answer",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "都",
        "pronunciation": "と",
        "back": "metropolitan",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "産業",
        "pronunciation": "さんぎょう",
        "back": "industry",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "伝える",
        "pronunciation": "つたえる",
        "back": "to convey (a message); to tell, to report",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "お金持ち",
        "pronunciation": "かねもち; おかねもち",
        "back": "rich person",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "説明",
        "pronunciation": "せつめい",
        "back": "explanation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "島",
        "pronunciation": "しま",
        "back": "island",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "道具",
        "pronunciation": "どうぐ",
        "back": "tool",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "滑る",
        "pronunciation": "すべる",
        "back": "to slide, to slip",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "それほど",
        "pronunciation": "それほど",
        "back": "to that degree; extent",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "以上",
        "pronunciation": "いじょう",
        "back": "more than; this is all",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～まま",
        "pronunciation": "～まま",
        "back": "as it is",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "特急",
        "pronunciation": "とっきゅう",
        "back": "limited express (train faster than an express)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "プレゼント",
        "pronunciation": "プレゼント",
        "back": "present, gift",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～(に) よると",
        "pronunciation": "～(に) よると",
        "back": "according to ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "妻",
        "pronunciation": "つま",
        "back": "wife (humble)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "帰り",
        "pronunciation": "かえり",
        "back": "return, coming back",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "具合",
        "pronunciation": "ぐあい",
        "back": "condition, state, health",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "堅; 硬; 固い",
        "pronunciation": "かたい",
        "back": "solid, hard, firm",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "駐車場",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうしゃじょう",
        "back": "parking lot",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "スーツ",
        "pronunciation": "スーツ",
        "back": "suit",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "危険",
        "pronunciation": "きけん",
        "back": "danger, risk, hazard",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "髪",
        "pronunciation": "かみ",
        "back": "hair",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "天気予報",
        "pronunciation": "てんきよほう",
        "back": "weather forecast",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "彼女",
        "pronunciation": "かのじょ",
        "back": "girlfriend; she",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "間",
        "pronunciation": "あいだ",
        "back": "space, interval",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "卒業",
        "pronunciation": "そつぎょう",
        "back": "graduation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "それで",
        "pronunciation": "それで",
        "back": "and (conj.), thereupon, because of that",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "枝",
        "pronunciation": "えだ",
        "back": "branch, twig",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "専門",
        "pronunciation": "せんもん",
        "back": "major; speciality",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "そろそろ",
        "pronunciation": "そろそろ",
        "back": "gradually, soon",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "送る",
        "pronunciation": "おくる",
        "back": "to send, to dispatch",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "あげる",
        "pronunciation": "あげる",
        "back": "to give",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "騒ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "さわぐ",
        "back": "to make noise, to clamor",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "尋ねる",
        "pronunciation": "たずねる",
        "back": "to inquire (same as 質問する)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "放送",
        "pronunciation": "ほうそうする",
        "back": "broadcasting",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "政治",
        "pronunciation": "せいじ",
        "back": "politics",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "市民",
        "pronunciation": "しみん",
        "back": "citizen",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ファックス",
        "pronunciation": "ファックス",
        "back": "fax",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "負ける",
        "pronunciation": "まける",
        "back": "to lose (a game) (v.i.), to be defeated",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "指輪",
        "pronunciation": "ゆびわ",
        "back": "(finger) ring",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "田舎",
        "pronunciation": "いなか",
        "back": "rural, countryside",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "見つける",
        "pronunciation": "みつける",
        "back": "to discover, to find (v.t.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "高校生",
        "pronunciation": "こうこうせい",
        "back": "high school student",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "講義",
        "pronunciation": "こうぎ",
        "back": "a lecture",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "そんなに",
        "pronunciation": "そんなに",
        "back": "so much, like that",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "昼休み",
        "pronunciation": "ひるやすみ",
        "back": "lunch break, noon recess",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "忘れ物",
        "pronunciation": "わすれもの",
        "back": "lost article, something forgotten",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "下りる",
        "pronunciation": "おりる",
        "back": "to get down, to go; come down",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "腕",
        "pronunciation": "うで",
        "back": "arm (in reference to body)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "訳",
        "pronunciation": "わけ",
        "back": "reason; explanation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "承知",
        "pronunciation": "しょうちする",
        "back": "consent, acceptance",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "日記",
        "pronunciation": "にっき",
        "back": "diary, journal",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "高校; 高等学校",
        "pronunciation": "こうこう; こうとうがっこう",
        "back": "high school; senior high school",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "似る",
        "pronunciation": "にる",
        "back": "to resemble, to be similar",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～おわる",
        "pronunciation": "～おわる",
        "back": "to finish doing ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "暖房",
        "pronunciation": "だんぼう",
        "back": "heating",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "留守",
        "pronunciation": "るす",
        "back": "absence; not at home",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "割合",
        "pronunciation": "わりあい",
        "back": "rate, ratio, percentage",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "寺",
        "pronunciation": "てら",
        "back": "Buddhist temple",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "慣れる",
        "pronunciation": "なれる",
        "back": "to grow accustomed to",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "普通",
        "pronunciation": "ふつう",
        "back": "common; usual",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "手伝う",
        "pronunciation": "てつだう",
        "back": "to help",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "なるほど",
        "pronunciation": "なるほど",
        "back": "I see; I now understand",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "くださる",
        "pronunciation": "くださる",
        "back": "(hon.) to give, to confer",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "息子",
        "pronunciation": "むすこ",
        "back": "(humble) son",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "お子さん",
        "pronunciation": "おこさん",
        "back": "(someone else's) child (polite)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "会場",
        "pronunciation": "かいじょう",
        "back": "venue, meeting place",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "笑う",
        "pronunciation": "わらう",
        "back": "to laugh, to smile",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "運ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "はこぶ",
        "back": "to transport, to carry",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "文学",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんがく",
        "back": "literature",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "光",
        "pronunciation": "ひかり",
        "back": "light",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "お見舞い",
        "pronunciation": "おみまい",
        "back": "calling on someone who is ill, visit",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "席",
        "pronunciation": "せき",
        "back": "a seat",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～様",
        "pronunciation": "～さま",
        "back": "Mr., Mrs., Ms.",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ご存じ",
        "pronunciation": "ごぞんじ",
        "back": "knowing, acquaintance",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "下る",
        "pronunciation": "さがる",
        "back": "to descend, to drop, to fall",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "字",
        "pronunciation": "じ",
        "back": "letter; character",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "アジア",
        "pronunciation": "アジア",
        "back": "Asia",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "褒める",
        "pronunciation": "ほめる",
        "back": "to praise; to say nice things",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "空く",
        "pronunciation": "すく",
        "back": "to be empty (in reference to people), to be less crowded",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "あ",
        "pronunciation": "あ",
        "back": "Ah",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "最も",
        "pronunciation": "もっとも",
        "back": "most",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "合う",
        "pronunciation": "あう",
        "back": "to fit, to match",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～代",
        "pronunciation": "～だい",
        "back": "~ age; period",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "最後",
        "pronunciation": "さいご",
        "back": "last, end",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "値段",
        "pronunciation": "ねだん",
        "back": "price",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "退院",
        "pronunciation": "たいいんする",
        "back": "leaving hospital",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "展覧会",
        "pronunciation": "てんらんかい",
        "back": "exhibition",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "久しぶり",
        "pronunciation": "ひさしぶり",
        "back": "it has been a long time; for the first time in a long time",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "カーテン",
        "pronunciation": "カーテン",
        "back": "curtain",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "汽車",
        "pronunciation": "きしゃ",
        "back": "train (steam)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "遅れる",
        "pronunciation": "おくれる",
        "back": "to (be) become late",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "見つかる",
        "pronunciation": "みつかる",
        "back": "to be found (v.i.), to be discovered",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "召し上がる",
        "pronunciation": "めしあがる",
        "back": "-- honorific form of 食べる (たべる) and 飲む (のむ) --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "太る",
        "pronunciation": "ふとる",
        "back": "to gain weight",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "注射",
        "pronunciation": "ちゅうしゃ",
        "back": "injection",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "様",
        "pronunciation": "よう",
        "back": "way, manner, kind",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～おき",
        "pronunciation": "～おき",
        "back": "after every ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "最初",
        "pronunciation": "さいしょ",
        "back": "beginning, first",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "御～",
        "pronunciation": "ご～",
        "back": "honorable ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "安心",
        "pronunciation": "あんしん",
        "back": "peace of mind, relief",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "直る",
        "pronunciation": "なおる",
        "back": "to be fixed",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "集める",
        "pronunciation": "あつめる",
        "back": "to collect, to gather (v.t.), to assemble",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "直す",
        "pronunciation": "なおす",
        "back": "to correct (v.t.); to fix",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "続く",
        "pronunciation": "つづく",
        "back": "to be continued",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "先輩",
        "pronunciation": "せんぱい",
        "back": "senior members of a group",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "約束",
        "pronunciation": "やくそく",
        "back": "arrangement, appointment, promise",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "世話",
        "pronunciation": "せわする",
        "back": "looking after; to look after",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "近所",
        "pronunciation": "きんじょ",
        "back": "neighborhood",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "将来",
        "pronunciation": "しょうらい",
        "back": "(in the) future; prospects",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "億",
        "pronunciation": "おく",
        "back": "hundred million",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "数学",
        "pronunciation": "すうがく",
        "back": "mathematics",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "文化",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんか",
        "back": "culture",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "払う",
        "pronunciation": "はらう",
        "back": "to pay",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "習慣",
        "pronunciation": "しゅうかん",
        "back": "custom (in reference to culture)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "焼ける",
        "pronunciation": "やける",
        "back": "to burn, to be roasted",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "君",
        "pronunciation": "きみ",
        "back": "you (informal for men)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷える",
        "pronunciation": "ひえる",
        "back": "to grow cold, to cool down",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "点く",
        "pronunciation": "つく",
        "back": "to be started, to be switched on",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "この間",
        "pronunciation": "このあいだ",
        "back": "the other day, recently",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "格好",
        "pronunciation": "かっこう",
        "back": "appearance, manner, shape, form, posture",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "かまう",
        "pronunciation": "",
        "back": "to mind, to care about, to be concerned about",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "続ける",
        "pronunciation": "つづける",
        "back": "to continue, to keep up",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "落す",
        "pronunciation": "おとす",
        "back": "to drop, to lose",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "明日",
        "pronunciation": "あす",
        "back": "tomorrow",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "出発",
        "pronunciation": "しゅっぱつする",
        "back": "departure",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "拝見",
        "pronunciation": "はいけんする",
        "back": "(humble) (polite) seeing, look at",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "割れる",
        "pronunciation": "われる",
        "back": "to break",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "背中",
        "pronunciation": "せなか",
        "back": "back (of body)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "新聞社",
        "pronunciation": "しんぶんしゃ",
        "back": "newspaper company",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "いじめる",
        "pronunciation": "いじめる",
        "back": "to bully, to torment",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "回る、回す",
        "pronunciation": "まわる、まわす",
        "back": "to go around, to revolve",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～君",
        "pronunciation": "～くん",
        "back": "Mr. (junior) ~, master ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "おっしゃる",
        "pronunciation": "おっしゃる",
        "back": "-- honorific expression for いう --",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "眠い",
        "pronunciation": "ねむい",
        "back": "sleepy, drowsy",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "濡れる",
        "pronunciation": "ぬれる",
        "back": "to get wet",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "倒れる",
        "pronunciation": "たおれる",
        "back": "to collapse, to break down",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "スーパー (マーケット)",
        "pronunciation": "スーパー (マーケット)",
        "back": "supermarket",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "アクセサリー",
        "pronunciation": "アクセサリー",
        "back": "accessory",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "考える",
        "pronunciation": "かんがえる",
        "back": "to think (about); to consider",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "向かう",
        "pronunciation": "むかう",
        "back": "to face, to go towards",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "自由",
        "pronunciation": "じゆう",
        "back": "freedom",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕方",
        "pronunciation": "しかた",
        "back": "way (of doing something)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "首",
        "pronunciation": "くび",
        "back": "neck",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "程",
        "pronunciation": "ほど",
        "back": "degree, extent",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "代わり",
        "pronunciation": "かわり",
        "back": "substitute, replacement",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "失敗",
        "pronunciation": "しっぱい",
        "back": "failure, mistake",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "工業",
        "pronunciation": "こうぎょう",
        "back": "(manufacturing) industry",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "移る",
        "pronunciation": "うつる",
        "back": "to move (from a house); to transfer (from a department); to shift",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "スーツケース",
        "pronunciation": "スーツケース",
        "back": "suitcase",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ひげ",
        "pronunciation": "ひげ",
        "back": "beard",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "研究室",
        "pronunciation": "けんきゅうしつ",
        "back": "the professor's office; laboratory",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "工場",
        "pronunciation": "こうじょう",
        "back": "factory",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "紹介",
        "pronunciation": "しょうかい",
        "back": "an introduction",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "けれど; けれども",
        "pronunciation": "けれど; けれども",
        "back": "but, although",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "舟",
        "pronunciation": "ふね",
        "back": "ship, boat",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "動く",
        "pronunciation": "うごく",
        "back": "to move",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～(に) ついて",
        "pronunciation": "～(に) ついて",
        "back": "about, concerning",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "コンサート",
        "pronunciation": "コンサート",
        "back": "concert",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "虫",
        "pronunciation": "むし",
        "back": "insect",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "優しい",
        "pronunciation": "やさしい",
        "back": "kind (person), gentle (person), easy (problem)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "コンピュータ; コンピューター",
        "pronunciation": "コンピュータ; コンピューター",
        "back": "computer",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "植える",
        "pronunciation": "うえる",
        "back": "to plant",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "両方",
        "pronunciation": "りょうほう",
        "back": "both sides, both parties",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "汚れる",
        "pronunciation": "よごれる",
        "back": "to become dirty",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "水泳",
        "pronunciation": "すいえい",
        "back": "swimming",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "経験",
        "pronunciation": "けいけんする",
        "back": "experience",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "勝つ",
        "pronunciation": "かつ",
        "back": "to win",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "砂",
        "pronunciation": "すな",
        "back": "sand",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "警察",
        "pronunciation": "けいさつ",
        "back": "police; police station",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "取り替える",
        "pronunciation": "とりかえる",
        "back": "to exchange, to replace",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "急ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "いそぐ",
        "back": "to hurry, to be in a hurry, to rush",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "簡単",
        "pronunciation": "かんたん",
        "back": "simple",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "参る",
        "pronunciation": "まいる",
        "back": "humble expression for 行く and 来る",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "全然",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんぜん",
        "back": "not at all; wholly, entirely",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "特別",
        "pronunciation": "とくべつ",
        "back": "special",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "復習",
        "pronunciation": "ふくしゅう",
        "back": "review (of lessons), revision",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "間に合う",
        "pronunciation": "まにあう",
        "back": "to be in time for",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "役に立つ",
        "pronunciation": "やくにたつ",
        "back": "to be helpful, to be useful",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "もうすぐ",
        "pronunciation": "もうすぐ",
        "back": "very soon; in a few moments; days",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "真中",
        "pronunciation": "まんなか",
        "back": "middle, center",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "戻る",
        "pronunciation": "もどる",
        "back": "to return (v.i.); to come back",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "研究",
        "pronunciation": "けんきゅう",
        "back": "study, research, investigation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ケーキ",
        "pronunciation": "ケーキ",
        "back": "cake",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "草",
        "pronunciation": "くさ",
        "back": "grass",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "込む",
        "pronunciation": "こむ",
        "back": "to be crowded",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "この頃",
        "pronunciation": "このごろ",
        "back": "these days, nowadays",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "訪ねる",
        "pronunciation": "たずねる",
        "back": "to visit",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "下げる",
        "pronunciation": "さげる",
        "back": "to lower (v.t.); to hang",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "花見",
        "pronunciation": "はなみ",
        "back": "cherry-blossom viewing",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "途中",
        "pronunciation": "とちゅう",
        "back": "on the way, midway",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "入院",
        "pronunciation": "にゅういんする",
        "back": "hospitalization",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "乗り換える",
        "pronunciation": "のりかえる",
        "back": "to transfer (trains), to change (bus, train, etc.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "別れる",
        "pronunciation": "わかれる",
        "back": "to part from, to separate",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～町",
        "pronunciation": "～ちょう",
        "back": "the town of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "安全",
        "pronunciation": "あんぜん",
        "back": "safety, security",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "看護婦",
        "pronunciation": "かんごふ",
        "back": "(female) nurse",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "見物",
        "pronunciation": "けんぶつ",
        "back": "sightseeing",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "相談",
        "pronunciation": "そうだんする",
        "back": "consultation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ガソリンスタンド",
        "pronunciation": "ガソリンスタンド",
        "back": "gas station, service station",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "テニス",
        "pronunciation": "テニス",
        "back": "tennis",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "眠る",
        "pronunciation": "ねむる",
        "back": "to sleep",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "上がる",
        "pronunciation": "あがる",
        "back": "to rise, to go up",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "翻訳",
        "pronunciation": "ほんやく",
        "back": "translation",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "食事",
        "pronunciation": "しょくじする",
        "back": "meal",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "お陰",
        "pronunciation": "おかげ",
        "back": "thanks or owing to",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "娘",
        "pronunciation": "むすめ",
        "back": "daughter (humble)",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "湯",
        "pronunciation": "ゆ",
        "back": "hot water",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "競争",
        "pronunciation": "きょうそう",
        "back": "competition, contest",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "会議",
        "pronunciation": "かいぎ",
        "back": "business meeting; conference",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "湖",
        "pronunciation": "みずうみ",
        "back": "lake",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "集まる",
        "pronunciation": "あつまる",
        "back": "to gather (v.i.), to collect",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～にくい",
        "pronunciation": "～にくい",
        "back": "difficult to do ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "生活",
        "pronunciation": "せいかつする",
        "back": "living, life; to live",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "糸",
        "pronunciation": "いと",
        "back": "thread",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "関係",
        "pronunciation": "かんけい",
        "back": "relation(ship), connection",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ピアノ",
        "pronunciation": "ピアノ",
        "back": "piano",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "～目",
        "pronunciation": "～め",
        "back": "number ~ sequence, ~nd; ~th",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "番組",
        "pronunciation": "ばんぐみ",
        "back": "broadcast program",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "急",
        "pronunciation": "きゅう",
        "back": "urgent, sudden; steep",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "棚",
        "pronunciation": "たな",
        "back": "shelves, rack",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "木綿",
        "pronunciation": "もめん",
        "back": "cotton",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "輸出",
        "pronunciation": "ゆしゅつする",
        "back": "export",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "タイプ",
        "pronunciation": "タイプ",
        "back": "type, style",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "すり",
        "pronunciation": "すり",
        "back": "pickpocket",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "嬉しい",
        "pronunciation": "うれしい",
        "back": "to be happy; to be glad",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "アルコール",
        "pronunciation": "アルコール",
        "back": "alcohol",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ソフト",
        "pronunciation": "ソフト",
        "back": "soft; soft hat; software",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "神社",
        "pronunciation": "じんじゃ",
        "back": "Shinto shrine",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "大分",
        "pronunciation": "だいぶ",
        "back": "fairly well, to a large extent, considerably, pretty much",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "楽しみ",
        "pronunciation": "たのしみ",
        "back": "pleasure, joy",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "趣味",
        "pronunciation": "しゅみ",
        "back": "hobby; pastime",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "電報",
        "pronunciation": "でんぽう",
        "back": "telegram",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "家内",
        "pronunciation": "かない",
        "back": "(one's own) wife",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "指",
        "pronunciation": "ゆび",
        "back": "finger",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "これから",
        "pronunciation": "これから",
        "back": "from now on, after this",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "たまに",
        "pronunciation": "たまに",
        "back": "occasionally",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "社会",
        "pronunciation": "しゃかい",
        "back": "society",
        "JLPT Level": "N4",
        "collection_id": "8"
    },
    {
        "front": "ああ",
        "pronunciation": "ああ",
        "back": "Ah!, Oh!",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "会う",
        "pronunciation": "あう",
        "back": "to meet, to see",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "青",
        "pronunciation": "あお",
        "back": "blue",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "青い",
        "pronunciation": "あおい",
        "back": "blue",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "赤",
        "pronunciation": "あか",
        "back": "red",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "赤い",
        "pronunciation": "あかい",
        "back": "red",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "明るい",
        "pronunciation": "あかるい",
        "back": "bright (in reference to personality or weather); cheerful",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "秋",
        "pronunciation": "あき",
        "back": "fall (season)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "開く",
        "pronunciation": "あく",
        "back": "to open, to become open",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "開ける",
        "pronunciation": "あける",
        "back": "to open (v.t.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "上げる",
        "pronunciation": "あげる",
        "back": "to raise, to lift",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "朝",
        "pronunciation": "あさ",
        "back": "morning",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "朝御飯",
        "pronunciation": "あさごはん",
        "back": "breakfast",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "明後日",
        "pronunciation": "あさって",
        "back": "day after tomorrow",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "足; 脚",
        "pronunciation": "あし",
        "back": "foot; leg",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "明日",
        "pronunciation": "あした",
        "back": "tomorrow",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "あそこ",
        "pronunciation": "あそこ",
        "back": "there, over there, that place",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "遊ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "あそぶ",
        "back": "to play; to spend time pleasantly; to hang out",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "暖かい",
        "pronunciation": "あたたかい",
        "back": "warm",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "頭",
        "pronunciation": "あたま",
        "back": "head",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "新しい",
        "pronunciation": "あたらしい",
        "back": "new",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "あちら",
        "pronunciation": "あちら",
        "back": "this way (polite)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "暑い",
        "pronunciation": "あつい",
        "back": "hot (in reference to weather), warm",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "熱い",
        "pronunciation": "あつい",
        "back": "hot (objects)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "厚い",
        "pronunciation": "あつい",
        "back": "kind, warm(hearted), thick, deep",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "あっち",
        "pronunciation": "あっち",
        "back": "over there",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "後",
        "pronunciation": "あと",
        "back": "afterwards (later); in the future; the rest; since then",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "あなた",
        "pronunciation": "あなた",
        "back": "you",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "兄",
        "pronunciation": "あに",
        "back": "(my) older brother (humble)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "姉",
        "pronunciation": "あね",
        "back": "(my) older sister (humble)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "アパート",
        "pronunciation": "アパート",
        "back": "apartment (abbr.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "あの",
        "pronunciation": "あの",
        "back": "that over there; like that, that way; um...",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "浴びる",
        "pronunciation": "あびる",
        "back": "to bathe, to shower",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "危ない",
        "pronunciation": "あぶない",
        "back": "dangerous, critical",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "甘い",
        "pronunciation": "あまい",
        "back": "generous, sweet",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "余り",
        "pronunciation": "あまり",
        "back": "not very; surplus",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "雨",
        "pronunciation": "あめ",
        "back": "rain",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "飴",
        "pronunciation": "あめ",
        "back": "(hard) candy",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "洗う",
        "pronunciation": "あらう",
        "back": "to wash",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "在る",
        "pronunciation": "ある",
        "back": "to be, to have",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "有る",
        "pronunciation": "ある",
        "back": "to be, to have",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "歩く",
        "pronunciation": "あるく",
        "back": "to walk",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "あれ",
        "pronunciation": "あれ",
        "back": "that one (over there)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "いい; よい",
        "pronunciation": "いい; よい",
        "back": "good",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "いいえ",
        "pronunciation": "いいえ",
        "back": "no, not at all",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "言う",
        "pronunciation": "いう",
        "back": "to say",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "家",
        "pronunciation": "いえ",
        "back": "house, home",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "いかが",
        "pronunciation": "いかが",
        "back": "how, in what way",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "行く",
        "pronunciation": "いく; ゆく",
        "back": "to go",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "いくつ",
        "pronunciation": "いくつ",
        "back": "how many, how old",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "いくら",
        "pronunciation": "いくら",
        "back": "how much, how many",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "池",
        "pronunciation": "いけ",
        "back": "pond",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "医者",
        "pronunciation": "いしゃ",
        "back": "doctor; physician",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "椅子",
        "pronunciation": "いす",
        "back": "chair",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "忙しい",
        "pronunciation": "いそがしい",
        "back": "busy (people, days)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "痛い",
        "pronunciation": "いたい",
        "back": "hurt; painful; sore",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "一",
        "pronunciation": "いち",
        "back": "one",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "一日",
        "pronunciation": "いちにち",
        "back": "one day (duration)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "一番",
        "pronunciation": "いちばん",
        "back": "best (most), first, number one",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "いつ",
        "pronunciation": "いつ",
        "back": "when",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "五日",
        "pronunciation": "いつか",
        "back": "five days; fifth day of the month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "一緒",
        "pronunciation": "いっしょ",
        "back": "together",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "五つ",
        "pronunciation": "いつつ",
        "back": "five things",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "いつも",
        "pronunciation": "いつも",
        "back": "always, usually, every time, never (with neg. verb)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "犬",
        "pronunciation": "いぬ",
        "back": "dog",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "今",
        "pronunciation": "いま",
        "back": "now",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "意味",
        "pronunciation": "いみ",
        "back": "meaning, significance",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "妹",
        "pronunciation": "いもうと",
        "back": "younger sister (humble)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "嫌",
        "pronunciation": "いや",
        "back": "disagreeable, detestable, unpleasant",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "入口",
        "pronunciation": "いりぐち",
        "back": "entrance",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "居る",
        "pronunciation": "いる",
        "back": "(humble) to be (animate), to exist",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "要る",
        "pronunciation": "いる",
        "back": "to need",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "入れる",
        "pronunciation": "いれる",
        "back": "to put in",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "色",
        "pronunciation": "いろ",
        "back": "color",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "色々",
        "pronunciation": "いろいろ",
        "back": "various",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "上",
        "pronunciation": "うえ",
        "back": "above (up, top, etc.), over, on top of",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "後ろ",
        "pronunciation": "うしろ",
        "back": "back, behind, rear",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "薄い",
        "pronunciation": "うすい",
        "back": "thin, weak",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "歌",
        "pronunciation": "うた",
        "back": "a song",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "歌う",
        "pronunciation": "うたう",
        "back": "to sing",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "うち",
        "pronunciation": "うち",
        "back": "home; house; my place",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "生まれる",
        "pronunciation": "うまれる",
        "back": "to be born",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "海",
        "pronunciation": "うみ",
        "back": "sea, beach",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "売る",
        "pronunciation": "うる",
        "back": "to sell (v.t.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "うるさい",
        "pronunciation": "うるさい",
        "back": "noisy; annoying",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "上着",
        "pronunciation": "うわぎ",
        "back": "coat, jacket",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "絵",
        "pronunciation": "え",
        "back": "a painting; a picture; a drawing",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "映画",
        "pronunciation": "えいが",
        "back": "movie, film",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "映画館",
        "pronunciation": "えいがかん",
        "back": "movie theater, cinema",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "英語",
        "pronunciation": "えいご",
        "back": "English (language)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ええ",
        "pronunciation": "ええ",
        "back": "yes",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "駅",
        "pronunciation": "えき",
        "back": "station",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "エレベーター",
        "pronunciation": "エレベーター",
        "back": "elevator",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～円",
        "pronunciation": "～えん",
        "back": "Yen",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "鉛筆",
        "pronunciation": "えんぴつ",
        "back": "pencil",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お～",
        "pronunciation": "お～",
        "back": "honorable ~ (honorific)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "美味しい",
        "pronunciation": "おいしい",
        "back": "delicious, tasty",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "多い",
        "pronunciation": "おおい",
        "back": "many; there are a lot",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "大きい",
        "pronunciation": "おおきい",
        "back": "big, large",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "大きな",
        "pronunciation": "おおきな",
        "back": "big",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "大勢",
        "pronunciation": "おおぜい",
        "back": "great number of people",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お母さん",
        "pronunciation": "おかあさん",
        "back": "mother (formal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お菓子",
        "pronunciation": "おかし",
        "back": "confections, sweets, snack",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お金",
        "pronunciation": "おかね",
        "back": "money",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "起きる",
        "pronunciation": "おきる",
        "back": "to get up (e.g., from sleeping); to happen",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "置く",
        "pronunciation": "おく",
        "back": "to put; to lay; to place",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "奥さん",
        "pronunciation": "おくさん",
        "back": "(someone else's) wife (hon.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お酒",
        "pronunciation": "おさけ",
        "back": "sake; alcohol",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お皿",
        "pronunciation": "おさら",
        "back": "plate, dish",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "伯父; 叔父さん",
        "pronunciation": "おじさん",
        "back": "uncle, middle-aged man",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "おじいさん",
        "pronunciation": "おじいさん",
        "back": "grandfather, male senior citizen",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "教える",
        "pronunciation": "おしえる",
        "back": "to teach, to inform, to instruct",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "押す",
        "pronunciation": "おす",
        "back": "to push, to press, to stamp (e.g., a passport)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "遅い",
        "pronunciation": "おそい",
        "back": "slow; (to be) late",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お茶",
        "pronunciation": "おちゃ",
        "back": "(green) tea",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お手洗い",
        "pronunciation": "おてあらい",
        "back": "toilet, restroom, bathroom (lit., a place to wash one's hands)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お父さん",
        "pronunciation": "おとうさん",
        "back": "father (formal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "弟",
        "pronunciation": "おとうと",
        "back": "younger brother",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "男",
        "pronunciation": "おとこ",
        "back": "man, male",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "男の子",
        "pronunciation": "おとこのこ",
        "back": "boy",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "一昨日",
        "pronunciation": "おととい",
        "back": "the day before yesterday",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "おととし",
        "pronunciation": "おととし",
        "back": "year before last",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "大人",
        "pronunciation": "おとな",
        "back": "adult",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お腹",
        "pronunciation": "おなか",
        "back": "stomach",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "同じ",
        "pronunciation": "おなじ",
        "back": "same, identical",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お兄さん",
        "pronunciation": "おにいさん",
        "back": "(someone else's) older brother (formal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お姉さん",
        "pronunciation": "おねえさん",
        "back": "older sister (formal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "伯母さん; 叔母さん",
        "pronunciation": "おばさん",
        "back": "aunt",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "おばあさん",
        "pronunciation": "おばあさん",
        "back": "grandmother, female senior-citizen",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お風呂",
        "pronunciation": "おふろ",
        "back": "a bath",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "お弁当",
        "pronunciation": "おべんとう",
        "back": "a boxed lunch",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "覚える",
        "pronunciation": "おぼえる",
        "back": "to learn, to commit to memory, to remember, to memorize",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "おまわりさん",
        "pronunciation": "おまわりさん",
        "back": "policeman (friendly term)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "重い",
        "pronunciation": "おもい",
        "back": "heavy; serious",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "面白い",
        "pronunciation": "おもしろい",
        "back": "interesting, amusing",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "泳ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "およぐ",
        "back": "to swim",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "降りる",
        "pronunciation": "おりる",
        "back": "to get off",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "終る",
        "pronunciation": "おわる",
        "back": "to finish, to close",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "音楽",
        "pronunciation": "おんがく",
        "back": "Music",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "女",
        "pronunciation": "おんな",
        "back": "woman, female",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "女の子",
        "pronunciation": "おんなのこ",
        "back": "girl",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～回",
        "pronunciation": "～かい",
        "back": "counter for occurrences (~ times)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～階",
        "pronunciation": "～かい",
        "back": "counter for stories (floors) of a building",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "外国",
        "pronunciation": "がいこく",
        "back": "foreign country; abroad",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "外国人",
        "pronunciation": "がいこくじん",
        "back": "foreigner",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "会社",
        "pronunciation": "かいしゃ",
        "back": "company, corporation",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "階段",
        "pronunciation": "かいだん",
        "back": "stairs",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "買い物",
        "pronunciation": "かいもの",
        "back": "shopping",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "買う",
        "pronunciation": "かう",
        "back": "to buy",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "返す",
        "pronunciation": "かえす",
        "back": "to return something",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "帰る",
        "pronunciation": "かえる",
        "back": "to go back, to go home, to return",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "顔",
        "pronunciation": "かお",
        "back": "face (body part)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "かかる",
        "pronunciation": "かかる",
        "back": "it takes (amount of time, money) (v.i.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "鍵",
        "pronunciation": "かぎ",
        "back": "a lock; a key",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "書く",
        "pronunciation": "かく",
        "back": "to write",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "学生",
        "pronunciation": "がくせい",
        "back": "student",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～か月",
        "pronunciation": "～かげつ",
        "back": "(number of) months",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "掛ける",
        "pronunciation": "かける",
        "back": "to put on (e.g., glasses); to hang (e.g., on a wall)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "かける",
        "pronunciation": "かける",
        "back": "to dial/call (e.g., phone); to sit down",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "傘",
        "pronunciation": "かさ",
        "back": "umbrella, parasol",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "貸す",
        "pronunciation": "かす",
        "back": "to lend",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "風",
        "pronunciation": "かぜ",
        "back": "wind, breeze",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "風邪",
        "pronunciation": "かぜ",
        "back": "cold, flu",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "方",
        "pronunciation": "かた",
        "back": "-- honorific form for 人 (ひと) --; way of doing",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "家族",
        "pronunciation": "かぞく",
        "back": "family, members of a family",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "片仮名",
        "pronunciation": "かたかな",
        "back": "katakana",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～月",
        "pronunciation": "～がつ",
        "back": "month of year",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "学校",
        "pronunciation": "がっこう",
        "back": "a school",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "カップ",
        "pronunciation": "カップ",
        "back": "cup",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "家庭",
        "pronunciation": "かてい",
        "back": "home; family",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "角",
        "pronunciation": "かど",
        "back": "corner (e.g., desk, pavement)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "かばん",
        "pronunciation": "かばん",
        "back": "bag, basket",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "花瓶",
        "pronunciation": "かびん",
        "back": "(flower) vase",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "かぶる",
        "pronunciation": "かぶる",
        "back": "to wear, to put on (e.g., a hat on the head)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "紙",
        "pronunciation": "かみ",
        "back": "paper",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "カメラ",
        "pronunciation": "カメラ",
        "back": "camera",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "火曜日",
        "pronunciation": "かようび",
        "back": "Tuesday",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "辛い",
        "pronunciation": "からい",
        "back": "hot and spicy; salty",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "体",
        "pronunciation": "からだ",
        "back": "body; health",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "借りる",
        "pronunciation": "かりる",
        "back": "to borrow, to owe",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～がる",
        "pronunciation": "～がる",
        "back": "feel",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "軽い",
        "pronunciation": "かるい",
        "back": "light, non-serious, minor",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "カレー",
        "pronunciation": "カレー",
        "back": "curry (abbr. for curry and rice)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "カレンダー",
        "pronunciation": "カレンダー",
        "back": "calendar",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "川; 河",
        "pronunciation": "かわ",
        "back": "river",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～側",
        "pronunciation": "～がわ",
        "back": "~ side",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "可愛い",
        "pronunciation": "かわいい",
        "back": "cute, adorable",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "漢字",
        "pronunciation": "かんじ",
        "back": "kanji; Chinese character",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "木",
        "pronunciation": "き",
        "back": "tree, wood, timber",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "黄色",
        "pronunciation": "きいろ",
        "back": "yellow",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "黄色い",
        "pronunciation": "きいろい",
        "back": "yellow",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "消える",
        "pronunciation": "きえる",
        "back": "to vanish, to disappear",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "聞く",
        "pronunciation": "きく",
        "back": "to hear, to listen, to ask",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "北",
        "pronunciation": "きた",
        "back": "north",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ギター",
        "pronunciation": "ギター",
        "back": "guitar",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "汚い",
        "pronunciation": "きたない",
        "back": "dirty, unclean, filthy",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "喫茶店",
        "pronunciation": "きっさてん",
        "back": "café",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "切手",
        "pronunciation": "きって",
        "back": "postal (postage) stamps",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "切符",
        "pronunciation": "きっぷ",
        "back": "a ticket",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "昨日",
        "pronunciation": "きのう",
        "back": "yesterday",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "九",
        "pronunciation": "きゅう",
        "back": "nine",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "牛肉",
        "pronunciation": "ぎゅうにく",
        "back": "beef",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "牛乳",
        "pronunciation": "ぎゅうにゅう",
        "back": "milk",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "今日",
        "pronunciation": "きょう",
        "back": "today, this day",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "教室",
        "pronunciation": "きょうしつ",
        "back": "classroom",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "兄弟",
        "pronunciation": "きょうだい",
        "back": "siblings (humble), brothers and sisters",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "去年",
        "pronunciation": "きょねん",
        "back": "last year",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "嫌い",
        "pronunciation": "きらい",
        "back": "dislike",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "切る",
        "pronunciation": "きる",
        "back": "to cut; to hang up (a phone)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "着る",
        "pronunciation": "きる",
        "back": "to put on (clothes above your waist); to wear",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "綺麗",
        "pronunciation": "きれい",
        "back": "pretty, clean, tidy",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "キロ; キログラム",
        "pronunciation": "キロ; キログラム",
        "back": "(abbr.) kilo (kilogram)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "キロ; キロメートル",
        "pronunciation": "キロ; キロメートル",
        "back": "(abbr.) kilo (kilometer)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "銀行",
        "pronunciation": "ぎんこう",
        "back": "bank",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "金曜日",
        "pronunciation": "きんようび",
        "back": "Friday",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "九",
        "pronunciation": "く",
        "back": "nine",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "薬",
        "pronunciation": "くすり",
        "back": "medicine",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "下さい",
        "pronunciation": "ください",
        "back": "(with te-form verb) please do for me",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "果物",
        "pronunciation": "くだもの",
        "back": "fruit",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "口",
        "pronunciation": "くち",
        "back": "job opening; mouth",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "靴",
        "pronunciation": "くつ",
        "back": "shoes, footwear",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "靴下",
        "pronunciation": "くつした",
        "back": "socks",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "国",
        "pronunciation": "くに",
        "back": "country; place of origin",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "曇り",
        "pronunciation": "くもり",
        "back": "cloudiness, cloudy weather",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "曇る",
        "pronunciation": "くもる",
        "back": "to become cloudy, to become dim",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "暗い",
        "pronunciation": "くらい",
        "back": "dark, gloomy",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～くらい; ぐらい",
        "pronunciation": "～くらい; ぐらい",
        "back": "approximate (quantity)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "クラス",
        "pronunciation": "クラス",
        "back": "a class",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "グラム",
        "pronunciation": "グラム",
        "back": "gram",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "来る",
        "pronunciation": "くる",
        "back": "to come",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "車",
        "pronunciation": "くるま",
        "back": "car, vehicle",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "黒",
        "pronunciation": "くろ",
        "back": "black",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "黒い",
        "pronunciation": "くろい",
        "back": "black; dark",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "警官",
        "pronunciation": "けいかん",
        "back": "police officer",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "今朝",
        "pronunciation": "けさ",
        "back": "this morning",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "消す",
        "pronunciation": "けす",
        "back": "to erase, to delete, to turn off power",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "結構",
        "pronunciation": "けっこう",
        "back": "splendid; enough, tolerably",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "結婚",
        "pronunciation": "けっこん (する)",
        "back": "marriage (get married)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "月曜日",
        "pronunciation": "げつようび",
        "back": "Monday",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "玄関",
        "pronunciation": "げんかん",
        "back": "entrance (to a house or a building)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "元気",
        "pronunciation": "げんき",
        "back": "health(y), energetic",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～個",
        "pronunciation": "～こ",
        "back": "counter for small items (e.g., fruits, cups)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "五",
        "pronunciation": "ご",
        "back": "five",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～語",
        "pronunciation": "～ご",
        "back": "word, language",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "公園",
        "pronunciation": "こうえん",
        "back": "a park",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "交差点",
        "pronunciation": "こうさてん",
        "back": "intersection",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "紅茶",
        "pronunciation": "こうちゃ",
        "back": "black tea",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "交番",
        "pronunciation": "こうばん",
        "back": "police box",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "声",
        "pronunciation": "こえ",
        "back": "voice",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "コート",
        "pronunciation": "コート",
        "back": "coat; court (e.g., tennis)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "コーヒー",
        "pronunciation": "コーヒー",
        "back": "coffee",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ここ",
        "pronunciation": "ここ",
        "back": "here, this place",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "午後",
        "pronunciation": "ごご",
        "back": "afternoon, P.M.",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "九日",
        "pronunciation": "ここのか",
        "back": "nine days; ninth day of the month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "九つ",
        "pronunciation": "ここのつ",
        "back": "nine things",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "午前",
        "pronunciation": "ごぜん",
        "back": "morning, A.M.",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "答える",
        "pronunciation": "こたえる",
        "back": "to answer, to reply",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "こちら",
        "pronunciation": "こちら",
        "back": "this person (polite); this way (polite)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "こっち",
        "pronunciation": "こっち",
        "back": "this person; this direction; this side",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "コップ",
        "pronunciation": "コップ",
        "back": "a tumbler; a glass",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "今年",
        "pronunciation": "ことし",
        "back": "this year",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "言葉",
        "pronunciation": "ことば",
        "back": "language; word(s); expression(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "子供",
        "pronunciation": "こども",
        "back": "child(ren)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "この",
        "pronunciation": "この",
        "back": "this",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "御飯",
        "pronunciation": "ごはん",
        "back": "rice (cooked); meal",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "コピーする",
        "pronunciation": "コピーする",
        "back": "to copy",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "困る",
        "pronunciation": "こまる",
        "back": "to be bothered, to have difficulty",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "これ",
        "pronunciation": "これ",
        "back": "this one",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～ころ; ～ごろ",
        "pronunciation": "～ころ; ～ごろ",
        "back": "about, toward, approximately (time)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "今月",
        "pronunciation": "こんげつ",
        "back": "this month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "今週",
        "pronunciation": "こんしゅう",
        "back": "this week",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "こんな",
        "pronunciation": "こんな",
        "back": "such, like this",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "今晩",
        "pronunciation": "こんばん",
        "back": "tonight, this evening",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "さあ",
        "pronunciation": "さあ",
        "back": "come now, well",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～歳",
        "pronunciation": "～さい",
        "back": "~ years old",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "財布",
        "pronunciation": "さいふ",
        "back": "wallet",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "魚",
        "pronunciation": "さかな",
        "back": "fish",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "先",
        "pronunciation": "さき",
        "back": "future; recent, previous",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "咲く",
        "pronunciation": "さく",
        "back": "to bloom",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "作文",
        "pronunciation": "さくぶん",
        "back": "essay; composition",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "差す",
        "pronunciation": "さす",
        "back": "to raise (stretch out) hands, to raise (e.g., umbrella)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～冊",
        "pronunciation": "～さつ",
        "back": "counter for books",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "雑誌",
        "pronunciation": "ざっし",
        "back": "magazine, journal",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "砂糖",
        "pronunciation": "さとう",
        "back": "sugar",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "寒い",
        "pronunciation": "さむい",
        "back": "cold (in reference to weather)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "さ来年",
        "pronunciation": "さらいねん",
        "back": "year after next",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～さん",
        "pronunciation": "～さん",
        "back": "Mr. ~, Ms. ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "三",
        "pronunciation": "さん",
        "back": "three",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "散歩",
        "pronunciation": "さんぽ (する)",
        "back": "walk, stroll",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "四",
        "pronunciation": "し",
        "back": "four",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～時",
        "pronunciation": "～じ",
        "back": "~ o'clock (time)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "塩",
        "pronunciation": "しお",
        "back": "salt",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "しかし",
        "pronunciation": "しかし",
        "back": "however; but",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "時間",
        "pronunciation": "じかん",
        "back": "time",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～時間",
        "pronunciation": "～じかん",
        "back": "~ hours",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "仕事",
        "pronunciation": "しごと",
        "back": "work, job, occupation, employment",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "辞書",
        "pronunciation": "じしょ",
        "back": "dictionary",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "静か",
        "pronunciation": "しずか",
        "back": "quiet, calm",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "下",
        "pronunciation": "した",
        "back": "under, below, beneath",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "七",
        "pronunciation": "しち",
        "back": "seven",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "質問",
        "pronunciation": "しつもん",
        "back": "question, inquiry",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "自転車",
        "pronunciation": "じてんしゃ",
        "back": "bicycle",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "自動車",
        "pronunciation": "じどうしゃ",
        "back": "automobile",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "死ぬ",
        "pronunciation": "しぬ",
        "back": "to die",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "字引",
        "pronunciation": "じびき",
        "back": "dictionary",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "自分",
        "pronunciation": "じぶん",
        "back": "myself, oneself",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "閉まる",
        "pronunciation": "しまる",
        "back": "to close, to be closed",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "閉める",
        "pronunciation": "しめる",
        "back": "to close, to shut",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "締める",
        "pronunciation": "しめる",
        "back": "to tie, to fasten, to tighten",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "じゃ; じゃあ",
        "pronunciation": "じゃ; じゃあ",
        "back": "well, well then",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "写真",
        "pronunciation": "しゃしん",
        "back": "a picture; a photograph",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "シャツ",
        "pronunciation": "シャツ",
        "back": "shirt",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "シャワー",
        "pronunciation": "シャワー",
        "back": "shower",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "十",
        "pronunciation": "じゅう",
        "back": "ten",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～中",
        "pronunciation": "～じゅう",
        "back": "during, while",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～週間",
        "pronunciation": "～しゅうかん",
        "back": "~ weeks",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "授業",
        "pronunciation": "じゅぎょう",
        "back": "a class (of school)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "宿題",
        "pronunciation": "しゅくだい",
        "back": "homework",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "上手",
        "pronunciation": "じょうず",
        "back": "be good at, skillful",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "丈夫",
        "pronunciation": "じょうぶ",
        "back": "strong, solid, durable",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "醤油",
        "pronunciation": "しょうゆ",
        "back": "soy sauce",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "食堂",
        "pronunciation": "しょくどう",
        "back": "cafeteria, dining hall",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "知る",
        "pronunciation": "しる",
        "back": "to know, to understand",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "白",
        "pronunciation": "しろ",
        "back": "white",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "白い",
        "pronunciation": "しろい",
        "back": "white",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～人",
        "pronunciation": "～じん",
        "back": "counter for people",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "新聞",
        "pronunciation": "しんぶん",
        "back": "newspaper",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "水曜日",
        "pronunciation": "すいようび",
        "back": "Wednesday",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "吸う",
        "pronunciation": "すう",
        "back": "to breathe in, to suck",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "スカート",
        "pronunciation": "スカート",
        "back": "skirt",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "好き",
        "pronunciation": "すき",
        "back": "liking, fondness, love",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～すぎ",
        "pronunciation": "～すぎ",
        "back": "past; to exceed, ~ too much",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "少ない",
        "pronunciation": "すくない",
        "back": "a little; a few",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "すぐに",
        "pronunciation": "すぐに",
        "back": "immediately, soon",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "少し",
        "pronunciation": "すこし",
        "back": "little, few",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "涼しい",
        "pronunciation": "すずしい",
        "back": "cool, refreshing (in reference to weather)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～ずつ",
        "pronunciation": "～ずつ",
        "back": "at a time",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ストーブ",
        "pronunciation": "ストーブ",
        "back": "heater (lit: stove)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "スプーン",
        "pronunciation": "スプーン",
        "back": "spoon",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "スポーツ",
        "pronunciation": "スポーツ",
        "back": "sport(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ズボン",
        "pronunciation": "ズボン",
        "back": "trousers",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "住む",
        "pronunciation": "すむ",
        "back": "to reside, to live in",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "する",
        "pronunciation": "する",
        "back": "to do, to try; to wear small items (e.g., necktie, watch, etc.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "座る",
        "pronunciation": "すわる",
        "back": "to sit",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "背",
        "pronunciation": "せい",
        "back": "(one's) height, stature",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "生徒",
        "pronunciation": "せいと",
        "back": "student; pupil",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "セーター",
        "pronunciation": "セーター",
        "back": "sweater",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "石鹸",
        "pronunciation": "せっけん",
        "back": "soap",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "背広",
        "pronunciation": "せびろ",
        "back": "men's suit",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "狭い",
        "pronunciation": "せまい",
        "back": "narrow; not spacious",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ゼロ",
        "pronunciation": "ゼロ",
        "back": "zero",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "千",
        "pronunciation": "せん",
        "back": "thousand",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "先月",
        "pronunciation": "せんげつ",
        "back": "last month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "先週",
        "pronunciation": "せんしゅう",
        "back": "last week",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "先生",
        "pronunciation": "せんせい",
        "back": "teacher, professor; master; doctor",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "洗濯",
        "pronunciation": "せんたく",
        "back": "washing, laundry",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "全部",
        "pronunciation": "ぜんぶ",
        "back": "all, entire, whole",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "そう; そうです",
        "pronunciation": "そう; そうです",
        "back": "yes; appears, to be the case",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "掃除",
        "pronunciation": "そうじ (する)",
        "back": "cleaning, sweeping",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "そうして; そして",
        "pronunciation": "そうして; そして",
        "back": "and, like that",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "そこ",
        "pronunciation": "そこ",
        "back": "that place, there; bottom, sole",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "そちら",
        "pronunciation": "そちら",
        "back": "over there",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "そっち",
        "pronunciation": "そっち",
        "back": "over there",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "外",
        "pronunciation": "そと",
        "back": "outside, exterior",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "その",
        "pronunciation": "その",
        "back": "that",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "そば",
        "pronunciation": "そば",
        "back": "near, close, beside; Japanese traditional buckwheat noodle",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "空",
        "pronunciation": "そら",
        "back": "sky",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "それ",
        "pronunciation": "それ",
        "back": "that one",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "それから",
        "pronunciation": "それから",
        "back": "and then, after that",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "それでは",
        "pronunciation": "それでは",
        "back": "in that situation, well then...",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～台",
        "pronunciation": "～だい",
        "back": "counter for vehicles; machines",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "大学",
        "pronunciation": "だいがく",
        "back": "college; university",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "大使館",
        "pronunciation": "たいしかん",
        "back": "embassy",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "大丈夫",
        "pronunciation": "だいじょうぶ",
        "back": "It's ok (all right); No need to worry; Everything is under control",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "大好き",
        "pronunciation": "だいすき",
        "back": "very like-able, like very much",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "大切",
        "pronunciation": "たいせつ",
        "back": "important",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "台所",
        "pronunciation": "だいどころ",
        "back": "kitchen",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "大変",
        "pronunciation": "たいへん",
        "back": "very; difficult, hard",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "高い",
        "pronunciation": "たかい",
        "back": "tall, high; expensive",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～だけ",
        "pronunciation": "～だけ",
        "back": "only ~, just ~, as ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "沢山",
        "pronunciation": "たくさん",
        "back": "many, much",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "タクシー",
        "pronunciation": "タクシー",
        "back": "taxi",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "出す",
        "pronunciation": "だす",
        "back": "to take (something) out; to hand in (something)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～たち",
        "pronunciation": "～たち",
        "back": "plural suffix",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "立つ",
        "pronunciation": "たつ",
        "back": "to stand up",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "たて",
        "pronunciation": "たて",
        "back": "length, height",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "建物",
        "pronunciation": "たてもの",
        "back": "building",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "楽しい",
        "pronunciation": "たのしい",
        "back": "enjoyable, fun",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "頼む",
        "pronunciation": "たのむ",
        "back": "to request, to ask (a favor)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "たばこ",
        "pronunciation": "たばこ",
        "back": "tobacco, cigarettes",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "多分",
        "pronunciation": "たぶん",
        "back": "perhaps, probably, maybe",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "食べ物",
        "pronunciation": "たべもの",
        "back": "food",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "食べる",
        "pronunciation": "たべる",
        "back": "to eat",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "卵",
        "pronunciation": "たまご",
        "back": "egg",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "誰",
        "pronunciation": "だれ",
        "back": "who",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "誰か",
        "pronunciation": "だれか",
        "back": "someone",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "誕生日",
        "pronunciation": "たんじょうび",
        "back": "birthday",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "段々",
        "pronunciation": "だんだん",
        "back": "gradually, by degrees",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "小さい",
        "pronunciation": "ちいさい",
        "back": "small, little",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "小さな",
        "pronunciation": "ちいさな",
        "back": "small, little",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "近い",
        "pronunciation": "ちかい",
        "back": "near, close by, short",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "違う",
        "pronunciation": "ちがう",
        "back": "to be different; to differ; wrong",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "近く",
        "pronunciation": "ちかく",
        "back": "nearby; in the neighborhood",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "地下鉄",
        "pronunciation": "ちかてつ",
        "back": "underground train, subway",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "地図",
        "pronunciation": "ちず",
        "back": "a map",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "父",
        "pronunciation": "ちち",
        "back": "(my) father",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "茶色",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃいろ",
        "back": "brown",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "茶碗",
        "pronunciation": "ちゃわん",
        "back": "rice bowl",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～中",
        "pronunciation": "～ちゅう",
        "back": "during, while ~ing",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "丁度",
        "pronunciation": "ちょうど",
        "back": "just, right, exactly",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちょっと",
        "pronunciation": "ちょっと",
        "back": "a little, somewhat; just a little, somewhat",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "一日",
        "pronunciation": "ついたち",
        "back": "one day; first day of the month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "使う",
        "pronunciation": "つかう",
        "back": "to use",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "疲れる",
        "pronunciation": "つかれる",
        "back": "to get (become) tired; to become fatigued",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "次",
        "pronunciation": "つぎ",
        "back": "next",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "着く",
        "pronunciation": "つく",
        "back": "to arrive at, to reach",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "机",
        "pronunciation": "つくえ",
        "back": "desk",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "作る",
        "pronunciation": "つくる",
        "back": "to make, to create",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "つける",
        "pronunciation": "つける",
        "back": "to turn on (e.g., a light); to take",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "勤める",
        "pronunciation": "つとめる",
        "back": "to work (for)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "つまらない",
        "pronunciation": "つまらない",
        "back": "boring, dull; insignificant",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷たい",
        "pronunciation": "つめたい",
        "back": "cold (things, people)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "強い",
        "pronunciation": "つよい",
        "back": "strong, powerful",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "手",
        "pronunciation": "て",
        "back": "hand",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "テープ",
        "pronunciation": "テープ",
        "back": "tape",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "テープレコーダー",
        "pronunciation": "テープレコーダー",
        "back": "tape recorder",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "テーブル",
        "pronunciation": "テーブル",
        "back": "table",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "出かける",
        "pronunciation": "でかける",
        "back": "to go out; to depart",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "手紙",
        "pronunciation": "てがみ",
        "back": "letter",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "できる",
        "pronunciation": "できる",
        "back": "to be able to (to accomplish)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "出口",
        "pronunciation": "でぐち",
        "back": "an exit",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "テスト",
        "pronunciation": "テスト",
        "back": "test",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "では",
        "pronunciation": "では",
        "back": "then, well, so",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "デパート",
        "pronunciation": "デパート",
        "back": "(abbr.) department store",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "でも",
        "pronunciation": "でも",
        "back": "but, however",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "出る",
        "pronunciation": "でる",
        "back": "to appear, to leave",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "テレビ",
        "pronunciation": "テレビ",
        "back": "television, TV",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "天気",
        "pronunciation": "てんき",
        "back": "weather",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "電気",
        "pronunciation": "でんき",
        "back": "electricity, (electric) light",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "電車",
        "pronunciation": "でんしゃ",
        "back": "electric train",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "電話",
        "pronunciation": "でんわ",
        "back": "a telephone",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "戸",
        "pronunciation": "と",
        "back": "door (Japanese style)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～度",
        "pronunciation": "～ど",
        "back": "counter for occurrences; ~ degree; ~ point",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ドア",
        "pronunciation": "ドア",
        "back": "door (Western style)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "トイレ",
        "pronunciation": "トイレ",
        "back": "bathroom; toilet",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "どう",
        "pronunciation": "どう",
        "back": "how, in what way",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "どうして",
        "pronunciation": "どうして",
        "back": "why, for what reason",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "どうぞ",
        "pronunciation": "どうぞ",
        "back": "please, kindly, by all means",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "動物",
        "pronunciation": "どうぶつ",
        "back": "animal",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "どうも",
        "pronunciation": "どうも",
        "back": "Thank you; somehow; no matter how hard one may try",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "十",
        "pronunciation": "(〜を) とお",
        "back": "ten (~)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "遠い",
        "pronunciation": "とおい",
        "back": "far (away), distant",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "十日",
        "pronunciation": "とおか",
        "back": "ten days; tenth day of the month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～時",
        "pronunciation": "～とき",
        "back": "at the time of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "時々",
        "pronunciation": "ときどき",
        "back": "sometimes",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "時計",
        "pronunciation": "とけい",
        "back": "a watch; a clock",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "どこ",
        "pronunciation": "どこ",
        "back": "where, what place",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "所",
        "pronunciation": "ところ",
        "back": "place",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "年",
        "pronunciation": "とし",
        "back": "year, age",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "図書館",
        "pronunciation": "としょかん",
        "back": "library",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "どちら",
        "pronunciation": "どちら",
        "back": "which (one) (way); where (polite)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "どっち",
        "pronunciation": "どっち",
        "back": "which one, which way",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "とても",
        "pronunciation": "とても",
        "back": "very (much), greatly, exceedingly",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "どなた",
        "pronunciation": "どなた",
        "back": "who",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "隣",
        "pronunciation": "となり",
        "back": "next to, next door to",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "どの",
        "pronunciation": "どの",
        "back": "which",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "飛ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "とぶ",
        "back": "to fly, to hop",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "止まる",
        "pronunciation": "とまる",
        "back": "to come to a halt",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "友達",
        "pronunciation": "ともだち",
        "back": "friend",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "土曜日",
        "pronunciation": "どようび",
        "back": "Saturday",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "鳥",
        "pronunciation": "とり",
        "back": "chicken (lit., bird)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "鶏肉",
        "pronunciation": "とりにく",
        "back": "chicken meat",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "取る",
        "pronunciation": "とる",
        "back": "to take (a class); to get (a grade)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "撮る",
        "pronunciation": "とる",
        "back": "to take (a photo), to make (a film)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "どれ",
        "pronunciation": "どれ",
        "back": "which one",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "どんな",
        "pronunciation": "どんな",
        "back": "what, what kind of",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ない",
        "pronunciation": "ない",
        "back": "there isn't, doesn't have",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ナイフ",
        "pronunciation": "ナイフ",
        "back": "knife",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "中",
        "pronunciation": "なか",
        "back": "inside, middle, among",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "長い",
        "pronunciation": "ながい",
        "back": "long, lengthy",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "鳴く",
        "pronunciation": "なく",
        "back": "to make sound (animal)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "無くす",
        "pronunciation": "なくす",
        "back": "to lose something",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "なぜ",
        "pronunciation": "なぜ",
        "back": "why (same as どうして)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "夏",
        "pronunciation": "なつ",
        "back": "summer",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "夏休み",
        "pronunciation": "なつやすみ",
        "back": "summer vacation",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～など",
        "pronunciation": "～など",
        "back": "et cetera",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "七つ",
        "pronunciation": "ななつ",
        "back": "seven things",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "何",
        "pronunciation": "なん; なに",
        "back": "what",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "七日",
        "pronunciation": "なのか",
        "back": "seven days; seventh day (of the month)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "名前",
        "pronunciation": "なまえ",
        "back": "name",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "習う",
        "pronunciation": "ならう",
        "back": "to learn",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "並ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "ならぶ",
        "back": "to line up, to stand in a line (v.i.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "並べる",
        "pronunciation": "ならべる",
        "back": "to put (things) side by side; to line up",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "なる",
        "pronunciation": "なる",
        "back": "to become",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "何～",
        "pronunciation": "なん～",
        "back": "what sort of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "二",
        "pronunciation": "に",
        "back": "two",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "にぎやか",
        "pronunciation": "にぎやか",
        "back": "bustling, busy",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "肉",
        "pronunciation": "にく",
        "back": "meat",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "西",
        "pronunciation": "にし",
        "back": "west",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～日",
        "pronunciation": "～にち",
        "back": "~ day of the month, for ~ days",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "日曜日",
        "pronunciation": "にちようび",
        "back": "Sunday",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "荷物",
        "pronunciation": "にもつ",
        "back": "luggage; baggage",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ニュース",
        "pronunciation": "ニュース",
        "back": "news",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "庭",
        "pronunciation": "にわ",
        "back": "garden",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～人",
        "pronunciation": "～にん",
        "back": "counter for people",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "脱ぐ",
        "pronunciation": "ぬぐ",
        "back": "to take off (clothes)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "温い",
        "pronunciation": "ぬるい",
        "back": "lukewarm",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ネクタイ",
        "pronunciation": "ネクタイ",
        "back": "tie, necktie",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "猫",
        "pronunciation": "ねこ",
        "back": "cat",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "寝る",
        "pronunciation": "ねる",
        "back": "to sleep; to go to sleep; to go to bed",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～年",
        "pronunciation": "～ねん",
        "back": "~ years",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ノート",
        "pronunciation": "ノート",
        "back": "notebook",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "登る",
        "pronunciation": "のぼる",
        "back": "to climb",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "飲み物",
        "pronunciation": "のみもの",
        "back": "drink, beverage",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "飲む",
        "pronunciation": "のむ",
        "back": "to drink",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "乗る",
        "pronunciation": "のる",
        "back": "to get on, to ride in, to board",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "歯",
        "pronunciation": "は",
        "back": "tooth",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "パーティー",
        "pronunciation": "パーティー",
        "back": "a party",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "はい",
        "pronunciation": "はい",
        "back": "yes",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～杯",
        "pronunciation": "～はい",
        "back": "counter for cupfuls",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "灰皿",
        "pronunciation": "はいざら",
        "back": "ashtray",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "入る",
        "pronunciation": "はいる",
        "back": "to enter, to contain, to hold",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "葉書",
        "pronunciation": "はがき",
        "back": "postcard",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "はく",
        "pronunciation": "はく",
        "back": "to put on (items below your waist)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "箱",
        "pronunciation": "はこ",
        "back": "box",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "橋",
        "pronunciation": "はし",
        "back": "bridge",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "箸",
        "pronunciation": "はし",
        "back": "chopsticks",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "始まる",
        "pronunciation": "はじまる",
        "back": "(something) begins",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "初め; 始め",
        "pronunciation": "はじめ",
        "back": "beginning, start",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "初めて",
        "pronunciation": "はじめて",
        "back": "for the first time",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "走る",
        "pronunciation": "はしる",
        "back": "to run",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "バス",
        "pronunciation": "バス",
        "back": "bus; bath; bass",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "バター",
        "pronunciation": "バター",
        "back": "butter",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "二十歳",
        "pronunciation": "はたち",
        "back": "20 years old",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "働く",
        "pronunciation": "はたらく",
        "back": "to work",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "八",
        "pronunciation": "はち",
        "back": "eight",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "二十日",
        "pronunciation": "はつか",
        "back": "twenty days, twentieth (day of the month)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "花",
        "pronunciation": "はな",
        "back": "flower",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "鼻",
        "pronunciation": "はな",
        "back": "nose",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "話",
        "pronunciation": "はなし",
        "back": "talk (chat), story",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "話す",
        "pronunciation": "はなす",
        "back": "to speak",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "母",
        "pronunciation": "はは",
        "back": "(my) mother",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "早い",
        "pronunciation": "はやい",
        "back": "early",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "速い",
        "pronunciation": "はやい",
        "back": "fast, quick",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "春",
        "pronunciation": "はる",
        "back": "spring",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "貼る",
        "pronunciation": "はる",
        "back": "to post; to paste; to attach",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "晴れ",
        "pronunciation": "はれ",
        "back": "clear (sunny) weather",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "晴れる",
        "pronunciation": "はれる",
        "back": "to be sunny",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "半",
        "pronunciation": "はん",
        "back": "half (e.g., にじはん | half-past two)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "晩",
        "pronunciation": "ばん",
        "back": "evening",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～番",
        "pronunciation": "～ばん",
        "back": "~st; ~th best",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "パン",
        "pronunciation": "パン",
        "back": "bread",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ハンカチ",
        "pronunciation": "ハンカチ",
        "back": "handkerchief",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "番号",
        "pronunciation": "ばんごう",
        "back": "number, series of digits",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "晩御飯",
        "pronunciation": "ばんごはん",
        "back": "dinner, evening meal",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "半分",
        "pronunciation": "はんぶん",
        "back": "half",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "東",
        "pronunciation": "ひがし",
        "back": "east",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～匹",
        "pronunciation": "～ひき",
        "back": "counter for small animals",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "引く",
        "pronunciation": "ひく",
        "back": "to pull, to draw; subtract",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "弾く",
        "pronunciation": "ひく",
        "back": "to play (a string instrument or piano)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "低い",
        "pronunciation": "ひくい",
        "back": "short, low",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "飛行機",
        "pronunciation": "ひこうき",
        "back": "airplane",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "左",
        "pronunciation": "ひだり",
        "back": "left hand side",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "人",
        "pronunciation": "ひと",
        "back": "man, person",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "一つ",
        "pronunciation": "ひとつ",
        "back": "one thing",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "一月",
        "pronunciation": "ひとつき",
        "back": "one month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "一人",
        "pronunciation": "ひとり",
        "back": "one person",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "暇",
        "pronunciation": "ひま",
        "back": "free time, leisure",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "百",
        "pronunciation": "ひゃく",
        "back": "hundred",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "病院",
        "pronunciation": "びょういん",
        "back": "hospital",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "病気",
        "pronunciation": "びょうき",
        "back": "illness; sickness",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "平仮名",
        "pronunciation": "ひらがな",
        "back": "hiragana",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "昼",
        "pronunciation": "ひる",
        "back": "noon, daytime",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "昼御飯",
        "pronunciation": "ひるごはん",
        "back": "lunch, midday meal",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "広い",
        "pronunciation": "ひろい",
        "back": "spacious; wide; broad",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "フィルム",
        "pronunciation": "フィルム",
        "back": "film (roll of)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "封筒",
        "pronunciation": "ふうとう",
        "back": "envelope",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "プール",
        "pronunciation": "プール",
        "back": "swimming pool",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "フォーク",
        "pronunciation": "フォーク",
        "back": "fork",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "吹く",
        "pronunciation": "ふく",
        "back": "to blow (wind, etc.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "服",
        "pronunciation": "ふく",
        "back": "clothes",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "二つ",
        "pronunciation": "ふたつ",
        "back": "two things",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "豚肉",
        "pronunciation": "ぶたにく",
        "back": "pork",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "二人",
        "pronunciation": "ふたり",
        "back": "two people",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "二日",
        "pronunciation": "ふつか",
        "back": "two days; second day of the month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "太い",
        "pronunciation": "ふとい",
        "back": "fat, thick",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "冬",
        "pronunciation": "ふゆ",
        "back": "winter",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "降る",
        "pronunciation": "ふる",
        "back": "to precipitate, to fall (e.g., rain, snow, etc.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "古い",
        "pronunciation": "ふるい",
        "back": "old (in reference to objects, not people), aged, ancient",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～分",
        "pronunciation": "～ふん",
        "back": "~ minutes",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "文章",
        "pronunciation": "ぶんしょう",
        "back": "sentence, text",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ページ",
        "pronunciation": "ページ",
        "back": "a page",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "下手",
        "pronunciation": "へた",
        "back": "unskillful, poor",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ベッド",
        "pronunciation": "ベッド",
        "back": "bed",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ペット",
        "pronunciation": "ペット",
        "back": "pet",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "部屋",
        "pronunciation": "へや",
        "back": "a room",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "辺",
        "pronunciation": "へん",
        "back": "area, vicinity",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ペン",
        "pronunciation": "ペン",
        "back": "pen",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "勉強",
        "pronunciation": "べんきょう (する)",
        "back": "study",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "便利",
        "pronunciation": "べんり",
        "back": "convenient, handy",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "帽子",
        "pronunciation": "ぼうし",
        "back": "hat; cap",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ボールペン",
        "pronunciation": "ボールペン",
        "back": "ball-point pen",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "外",
        "pronunciation": "ほか",
        "back": "other, the rest",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ポケット",
        "pronunciation": "ポケット",
        "back": "pocket",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "欲しい",
        "pronunciation": "ほしい",
        "back": "to want, in need of",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ポスト",
        "pronunciation": "ポスト",
        "back": "mailbox; post, position",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "細い",
        "pronunciation": "ほそい",
        "back": "thin, slender, fine",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ボタン",
        "pronunciation": "ボタン",
        "back": "button",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ホテル",
        "pronunciation": "ホテル",
        "back": "hotel",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "本",
        "pronunciation": "ほん",
        "back": "book",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～本",
        "pronunciation": "～ほん",
        "back": "counter for long cylindrical things",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "本棚",
        "pronunciation": "ほんだな",
        "back": "bookshelf",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "本当",
        "pronunciation": "ほんとう",
        "back": "real, true",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～枚",
        "pronunciation": "～まい",
        "back": "counter for flat things",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "毎朝",
        "pronunciation": "まいあさ",
        "back": "every morning",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "毎月",
        "pronunciation": "まいげつ; まいつき",
        "back": "every month, monthly",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "毎週",
        "pronunciation": "まいしゅう",
        "back": "every week",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "毎日",
        "pronunciation": "まいにち",
        "back": "every day",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "毎年",
        "pronunciation": "まいねん; まいとし",
        "back": "every year, yearly, annually",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "毎晩",
        "pronunciation": "まいばん",
        "back": "every night",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "前",
        "pronunciation": "まえ",
        "back": "before, in front",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～前",
        "pronunciation": "～まえ",
        "back": "in front of ~",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "曲る",
        "pronunciation": "まがる",
        "back": "to turn, to bend",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "まずい",
        "pronunciation": "まずい",
        "back": "terrible (in reference to food), unappetizing, unpleasant (taste)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "また",
        "pronunciation": "また",
        "back": "and; furthermore",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "まだ",
        "pronunciation": "まだ",
        "back": "yet, still, besides",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "町",
        "pronunciation": "まち",
        "back": "town; city",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "待つ",
        "pronunciation": "まつ",
        "back": "to wait",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "まっすぐ",
        "pronunciation": "まっすぐ",
        "back": "straight (ahead), direct",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "マッチ",
        "pronunciation": "マッチ",
        "back": "match",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "窓",
        "pronunciation": "まど",
        "back": "window",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "丸い; 円い",
        "pronunciation": "まるい",
        "back": "round, circular",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "万",
        "pronunciation": "まん",
        "back": "ten thousand",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "万年筆",
        "pronunciation": "まんねんひつ",
        "back": "fountain pen",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "磨く",
        "pronunciation": "みがく",
        "back": "to brush (teeth); to polish",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "右",
        "pronunciation": "みぎ",
        "back": "right hand side",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "短い",
        "pronunciation": "みじかい",
        "back": "short (length)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "水",
        "pronunciation": "みず",
        "back": "water",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "店",
        "pronunciation": "みせ",
        "back": "store, shop",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "見せる",
        "pronunciation": "みせる",
        "back": "to show, to display",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "道",
        "pronunciation": "みち",
        "back": "road, street; way, directions",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "三日",
        "pronunciation": "みっか",
        "back": "three days, third day of the month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "三つ",
        "pronunciation": "みっつ",
        "back": "three things",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "緑",
        "pronunciation": "みどり",
        "back": "green",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "皆さん",
        "pronunciation": "みなさん",
        "back": "all of you, everyone",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "南",
        "pronunciation": "みなみ",
        "back": "South",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "耳",
        "pronunciation": "みみ",
        "back": "ear",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "見る",
        "pronunciation": "みる",
        "back": "to see, to look",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "みんな",
        "pronunciation": "みんな",
        "back": "all, everyone, everybody",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "六日",
        "pronunciation": "むいか",
        "back": "six days; sixth day of month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "向こう",
        "pronunciation": "むこう",
        "back": "beyond, over there",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "難しい",
        "pronunciation": "むずかしい",
        "back": "difficult",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "六つ",
        "pronunciation": "むっつ",
        "back": "six things",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "村",
        "pronunciation": "むら",
        "back": "village",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "目",
        "pronunciation": "め",
        "back": "eye(s)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "メートル",
        "pronunciation": "メートル",
        "back": "meter",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "眼鏡",
        "pronunciation": "めがね",
        "back": "eye glasses",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "もう",
        "pronunciation": "もう",
        "back": "already; again; more",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "木曜日",
        "pronunciation": "もくようび",
        "back": "Thursday",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "もしもし",
        "pronunciation": "もしもし",
        "back": "Hello? (used on the phone)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "持つ",
        "pronunciation": "もつ",
        "back": "to hold, to carry; to possess",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "もっと",
        "pronunciation": "もっと",
        "back": "more",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "物",
        "pronunciation": "もの",
        "back": "thing (concrete object)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "門",
        "pronunciation": "もん",
        "back": "gate",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "問題",
        "pronunciation": "もんだい",
        "back": "a problem",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "～屋",
        "pronunciation": "～や",
        "back": "~ shop",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "八百屋",
        "pronunciation": "やおや",
        "back": "greengrocer",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "野菜",
        "pronunciation": "やさい",
        "back": "vegetable",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "易しい",
        "pronunciation": "やさしい",
        "back": "easy, plain, simple",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "安い",
        "pronunciation": "やすい",
        "back": "inexpensive; cheap (things)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "休み",
        "pronunciation": "やすみ",
        "back": "holiday; day off; absence",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "休む",
        "pronunciation": "やすむ",
        "back": "to rest, to have a break, to get time off",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "八つ",
        "pronunciation": "やっつ",
        "back": "eight things",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "山",
        "pronunciation": "やま",
        "back": "mountain",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "やる",
        "pronunciation": "やる",
        "back": "to do; to give (to pets, parents, siblings, etc.)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "夕方",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうがた",
        "back": "late afternoon (typically just before dinner time), evening",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "夕飯",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうはん",
        "back": "dinner, supper, evening meal",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "郵便局",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうびんきょく",
        "back": "post office",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "昨夜",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうべ",
        "back": "last night",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "有名",
        "pronunciation": "ゆうめい",
        "back": "famous",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "雪",
        "pronunciation": "ゆき",
        "back": "snow",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ゆっくりと",
        "pronunciation": "ゆっくりと",
        "back": "slowly, at ease",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "八日",
        "pronunciation": "ようか",
        "back": "eight days; eighth day of the month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "洋服",
        "pronunciation": "ようふく",
        "back": "Western-style clothes",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "よく",
        "pronunciation": "よく",
        "back": "frequently, often (much); well, skillfully",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "横",
        "pronunciation": "よこ",
        "back": "beside; side; width",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "四日",
        "pronunciation": "よっか",
        "back": "four days; fourth day of the month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "四つ",
        "pronunciation": "よっつ",
        "back": "four things",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "呼ぶ",
        "pronunciation": "よぶ",
        "back": "to call (one's name); to invite",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "読む",
        "pronunciation": "よむ",
        "back": "to read",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "夜",
        "pronunciation": "よる",
        "back": "evening, night",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "弱い",
        "pronunciation": "よわい",
        "back": "weak",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "来月",
        "pronunciation": "らいげつ",
        "back": "next month",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "来週",
        "pronunciation": "らいしゅう",
        "back": "next week",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "来年",
        "pronunciation": "らいねん",
        "back": "next year",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ラジオ",
        "pronunciation": "ラジオ",
        "back": "radio",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ラジオカセ",
        "pronunciation": "ラジオカセ",
        "back": "radio cassette player",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "りっぱ",
        "pronunciation": "りっぱ",
        "back": "splendid, fine",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "留学生",
        "pronunciation": "りゅうがくせい",
        "back": "international student",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "両親",
        "pronunciation": "りょうしん",
        "back": "parents (lit., both parents)",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "料理",
        "pronunciation": "りょうり",
        "back": "cooking; cuisine",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "旅行",
        "pronunciation": "りょこう",
        "back": "travel, trip",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "零",
        "pronunciation": "れい",
        "back": "zero, nought",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "冷蔵庫",
        "pronunciation": "れいぞうこ",
        "back": "refrigerator",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "レコード",
        "pronunciation": "レコード",
        "back": "record",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "レストラン",
        "pronunciation": "レストラン",
        "back": "restaurant",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "練習",
        "pronunciation": "れんしゅう (する)",
        "back": "(to) practice",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "廊下",
        "pronunciation": "ろうか",
        "back": "corridor",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "六",
        "pronunciation": "ろく",
        "back": "six",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "ワイシャツ",
        "pronunciation": "ワイシャツ",
        "back": "shirt (lit: white shirt), business shirt",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "若い",
        "pronunciation": "わかい",
        "back": "young",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "分かる",
        "pronunciation": "わかる",
        "back": "to understand",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "忘れる",
        "pronunciation": "わすれる",
        "back": "to forget",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "私",
        "pronunciation": "わたし",
        "back": "I, myself",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "私",
        "pronunciation": "わたくし",
        "back": "I (formal), myself, private affairs",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "渡す",
        "pronunciation": "わたす",
        "back": "to hand (something) over (v.t.); to get across",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "渡る",
        "pronunciation": "わたる",
        "back": "to cross over, to go across",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    },
    {
        "front": "悪い",
        "pronunciation": "わるい",
        "back": "bad, sinful; inferior",
        "JLPT Level": "N5",
        "collection_id": "7"
    }
]